<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<!--===========================================================
<
< TEXT STRINGS FOR LOST TO THE ZONE TASKS
<	CoC 1.5r6 - Lost to the Zone
<
<	Made by: SarisKhan
<	Last revised: 05 October 2017
<
<===========================================================-->

<string_table>

	<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Kalancha (Clear Sky Medic) Lost to the Zone Tasks -->
	
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_1_name">
		<text>Unnatural Selection</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_1_text">
		<text>Collect %s samples for Professor Kalancha.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_1_about">
		<text>Mutants of the Zone have displayed numerous peculiar adaptations to its anomalous conditions. Please, collect some tissue samples for my research. They might help us persevere in this environment as well.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Mutants of the Zone have displayed numerous peculiar adaptations to its anomalous conditions. Please, collect some tissue samples for my research. They might help us persevere in this environment as well. Collect %s samples.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>The samples are in good condition. Very well, I will get to research immediately. Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_2_name">
		<text>Scientific Progress</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_2_text">
		<text>Find one %s artefact for Professor Kalancha.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_2_about">
		<text>Artefacts may provide invaluable data for our research. However, with the many threats we face our men cannot really afford to collect them for me all that often. Could you help me?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Artefacts may provide invaluable data for our research. However, with the many threats we face our men cannot really afford to collect them for me all that often. Could you help me? Find one %s artefact.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Even after all these years they never cease to amaze me. What a wonderful specimen. Thank you for your assistance.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_3_name">
		<text>Scarce Supplies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_3_text">
		<text>Professor Kalancha requires some additional %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_3_about">
		<text>You see, Spore does his best to provide supplies for us. But even after all these years we are still in a difficult situation. There is no shortage of injuries to treat but our medical supplies are limited. Please, help me supplement our stock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>You see, Spore does his best to provide supplies for us. But even after all these years we are still in a difficult situation. There is no shortage of injuries to treat but our medical supplies are limited. Please, help me supplement our stock. Procure some %s, please.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>We are all deeply indebted for your help.</text>
	</string>

<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Sakharov (Ecog Trader) Collect New Artefact Task -->

	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_name">
		<text>Scientific Progress</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_text">
		<text>Sakharov needs a %s artefact for research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_about">
		<text>As you may know, new artefacts have recently appeared in the Zone. I'd like you to collect some research material for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>As you may know, new artefacts have recently appeared in the Zone. I'd like you to collect some research material for me. I would like you to find a %s and bring it to me, please.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you, sir. This will help immensely in my research.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Hermann (Ecog Trader) Collect New Artefact Task -->

	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_name">
		<text>Scientific Progress</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_text">
		<text>Hermann needs a %s artefact for research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_about">
		<text>Well, we could use new research material for once. I suppose you could help us with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Well, we could use new research material for once. I suppose you could help us with that. I would like you to find a %s and bring it to me. Your assistance will be rewarded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Finally. Thank you for your cooperation, here's your payment.</text>
	</string>

<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_3_name">
		<text>Makarov in a Haystack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_3_text">
		<text>Fanatic asked to retrieve lost family heirloom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_3_about">
		<text>So, listen. Some bastards decided to mock a rookie and, well, they hid his Makarov somewhere in the car park. When I found out I quickly got rid of them, but not before giving them a good beating. Still, they didn't tell me exactly where did they hide the pistol. And the boy's sitting over there in a miserable mood. You see, he told me that the Makarov was given to him by his late father, a policeman. It's not right to let him sulk like that. Can you help me find the pistol?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>So, listen. Some bastards decided to mock a rookie and, well, they hid his Makarov somewhere in the car park. When I found out I quickly got rid of them, but not before giving them a good beating. Still, they didn't tell me exactly where did they hide the pistol. And the boy's sitting over there in a miserable mood. You see, he told me that the Makarov was given to him by his late father, a policeman. It's not right to let him sulk like that. Can you help me find the pistol? Try to find the Makarov somewhere in the car park. One of the bandits might've taken it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done, thanks. Good people are few and far between in the Zone, and I appreciate your help. Take this money as a reward.</text>
	</string>

<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Blackjack (Mercenary Barman) Tasks -->
	
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_1_name">
		<text>Monster Hunter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_1_text">
		<text>There is demand for a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_1_about">
		<text>Yes, I've always got some work for you. A wealthy client's interested in a rare mutant part. Bring me to it and I'll make it worth the effort.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Yes, I've always got some work for you. A wealthy client's interested in a rare mutant part. Bring me to it and I'll make it worth the effort. Bring me %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done, here's your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_2_name">
		<text>Professional Hitman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_2_text">
		<text>Blackjack wants to collect some %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_2_about">
		<text>What do you feel when you shoot a stalker? Recoil, huh? Well, show me what you've got.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>What do you feel when you shoot a stalker? Recoil, huh? Well, show me what you've got. Do you want to hunt the most dangerous game? Bring me some %s, and I'll pay you well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Good job. Here's your money.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_3_name">
		<text>Night Terror</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_3_text">
		<text>Blackjack wants to eliminate a dangerous mutant which haunts the Red Forest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_3_about">
		<text>Listen. There've been rumours that a particularly nasty specimen of chimera haunts the Red Forest. Not even whole teams of stalkers are safe. And they say the chimera's pitch black. That just might be the fucker which remodelled my face. So, I want it really, really dead, all right? Gear up and tear it a new asshole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_barman_task_3_finish">
		<text>Excellent job, stalker. Maybe my scars won't itch that much anymore. Well, here's your reward, you deserve it.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Mender (Mercenary Medic) Scarce Supplies Task -->
	
	<string id="cit_killer_medic_task_1_name">
		<text>Scarce Supplies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_medic_task_1_text">
		<text>Mender wants some additional %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_medic_task_1_about">
		<text>There's always something to do in our safe haven. Blokes come back from work with all kinds of gashes, holes and burns to patch up. At this rate I might run out of supplies a bit earlier than the next restock happens, and I don't really wanna add my mates to the long list of people I killed. Help me out, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_medic_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>There's always something to do in our safe haven. Blokes come back from work with all kinds of gashes, holes and burns to patch up. At this rate I might run out of supplies a bit earlier than the next restock happens, and I don't really wanna add my mates to the long list of people I killed. Help me out, okay? Procure some %s. I'll pay you premium for those.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_medic_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Hey, swell job. Time to treat those whining wankers. Here, that's your reward.</text>
	</string>

<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Voronin (Duty Honcho) Decimate the Enemy Task -->
	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_1_name">
		<text>New Zone Order</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_1_text">
		<text>General Voronin wants to decimate the enemy ranks. Collect %s.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_1_about">
		<text>Listen, stalker. We strive to destroy the Zone, although there are enemies who wish to destroy us. Criminals, anarchists and fanatics driven by avarice, ignorance or delusion. While the Zone remains our primary threat, and even though we cannot afford to spark a large-scale conflict, let our enemies know that we shall not tolerate their impudence. Eliminate the fools who dare oppose us.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Listen, stalker. We strive to destroy the Zone, although there are enemies who wish to destroy us. Criminals, anarchists and fanatics driven by avarice, ignorance or delusion. While the Zone remains our primary threat, and even though we cannot afford to spark a large-scale conflict, let our enemies know that we shall not tolerate their impudence. Eliminate the fools who dare oppose us. Bring me several %s as proof of your devotion to the cause.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent job. We are like a mighty bulldozer on our way to ravage the Zone. With that, our enemies know they can only step aside or perish.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Voronin (Duty Honcho) Hunt the Mutants Task -->
	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_2_name">
		<text>Big Game Hunter</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_2_text">
		<text>Collect %s trophies for General Voronin.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_2_about">
		<text>Mutants are a difficult enemy. They cannot be reasoned with and they cannot be deterred. They hunger, and they hunt. The time has come for someone like you to hunt them down. Prove your worth and contribute toward the Zone's destruction.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Mutants are a difficult enemy. They cannot be reasoned with and they cannot be deterred. They hunger, and they hunt. The time has come for someone like you to hunt them down. Prove your worth and contribute toward the Zone's destruction. Bring me %s.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Magnificent trophies. Let me reward your bravery.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Voronin (Duty Honcho) Night Terror Task -->
	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_3_name">
		<text>Night Terror</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_3_text">
		<text>Voronin wants to eliminate a dangerous mutant which haunts the Truck Cemetery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_3_about">
		<text>Our patrols reported that a particularly dangerous mutant haunts the Truck Cemetery. The monster has already taken lives of several good Dutyers. That has to stop immediately. Go, search for the beast and destroy it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_task_3_finish">
		<text>Another step toward fulfilling our goal. You will be rewarded.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Kuznetsov (Military Honcho) Tight Security Task -->
	<string id="agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_task_1_name">
		<text>Tight Security</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_task_1_text">
		<text>Kuznetsov wants to collect some %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_task_1_about">
		<text>Listen, soldier. The higher-ups want proof that we firmly control the area. That's rather difficult to claim with all the stalkers roaming about. Fortunately, the higher-ups won't check on that personally. As such, I want you to collect some patches that I will show them as proof we've secured the perimeter. Understood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Listen, soldier. The higher-ups want proof that we firmly control the area. That's rather difficult to claim with all the stalkers roaming about. Fortunately, the higher-ups won't check on that personally. As such, I want you to collect some patches that I will show them as proof we've secured the perimeter. Understood? Bring me some %s and I'll reward your reliability.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_smart_terrain_1_6_near_2_military_colonel_kovalski_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done, soldier. Here's your bonus.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Rogovets (Military Medic) Scarce Supplies Task -->
	<string id="agr_army_medic_task_1_name">
		<text>Scarce Supplies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_army_medic_task_1_text">
		<text>Rogovets wants some additional %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_army_medic_task_1_about">
		<text>Good day, soldier. Or not so good. This place's extremely dangerous, as you likely know full well. Anyway, we've got plenty of wounded to treat every day and a shortage of supplies to treat them with. Can you help me procure some additional medicaments? I'd be very grateful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_army_medic_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Good day, soldier. Or not so good. This place's extremely dangerous, as you likely know full well. Anyway, we've got plenty of wounded to treat every day and a shortage of supplies to treat them with. Can you help me procure some additional medicaments? I'd be very grateful. Obtain some %s and I will share a part of my paycheck with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_army_medic_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you, soldier.</text>
	</string>

<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Skinflint (Freedom Trader) Night Terror Task -->
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_2_name">
		<text>Night Terror</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_2_text">
		<text>Skinflint wants to eliminate a dangerous mutant which haunts the Bloodsucker Village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_2_about">
		<text>You know 'bout the Bloodsucker Village, right? Well, our guys can handle the usual tentacle monsters just fine. But there's been this mean black motherfucker that only comes out to hunt at night. He's already killed a few good mates and I don't want the list to get any longer. Can you put a few bullets in its head for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_2_finish">
		<text>Hah! No more gross tentacle rape for a while. Good job, man.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Skinflint (Freedom Trader) Scarce Supplies Task -->
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_3_name">
		<text>Scarce Supplies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_3_text">
		<text>Skinflint wants some %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_3_about">
		<text>Hey man. Some of our guys can get a bit too adventurous from time to time. We haven't got enough supplies to treat all of 'em.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Hey man. Some of our guys can get a bit too adventurous from time to time. We haven't got enough supplies to treat all of 'em. Can you bring some %s?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_10_freedom_trader_stalker_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>You're awesome, man.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->
<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Eidolon (Elite Monolith Soldier) Purge the Infidels Task -->
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_1_name">
		<text>Purge the Infidels</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_1_text">
		<text>Eidolon wants to collect some %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_1_about">
		<text>We are besieged. Infidels wish to exploit the almighty Monolith. Driven by avarice. Ignorance. Base desires. On behalf of the Monolith. We act, the guardians. Purge the infidels. Collect their badges. As a trophy. A sign of our unquestionable, superiority. Go, brother. Destroy them all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>We are besieged. Infidels wish to exploit the almighty Monolith. Driven by avarice. Ignorance. Base desires. On behalf of the Monolith. We act, the guardians. Purge the infidels. Collect their badges. As a trophy. A sign of our unquestionable, superiority. Go, brother. Destroy them all. Acquire %s on your mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Such devotion. To our glorious cause. Devotion shall be rewarded.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Eidolon (Elite Monolith Soldier) Hunt the Mutants Task -->
	
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_2_name">
		<text>The Greatest Warrior</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_2_text">
		<text>Collect %s trophies for Eidolon.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_2_about">
		<text>Dangerous. Lethal beasts. A gift of the Zone, for us to behold. For us to take. Guardians, providers, as well as a milestone. A way to test our strength. Resolve, and combat prowess. Go, brother. Hunt a mighty hunter, man versus beast.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Dangerous. Lethal beasts. A gift of the Zone, for us to behold. For us to take. Guardians, providers, as well as a milestone. A way to test our strength. Resolve, and combat prowess. Go, brother. Hunt a mighty hunter, man versus beast. Collect %s to prove your worth.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Magnificent trophy. The Monolith is proud. So am I. A reward, for you.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Eidolon (Elite Monolith Soldier) Harvest the Fruit Task -->

	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_3_name">
		<text>Harvest the Fruit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_3_text">
		<text>Eidolon wants to collect a %s artefact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_3_about">
		<text>We protect the Monolith. The Monolith protects us. We serve, and the Zone delivers. Splendid fruit, resplendent with its unequalled brilliance. Powerful, to empower us. Go now, harvest the fruit, brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>We protect the Monolith. The Monolith protects us. We serve, and the Zone delivers. Splendid fruit, resplendent with its unequalled brilliance. Powerful, to empower us. Go now, harvest the fruit, brother. Harvest a %s, to bolster our strength.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_eidolon_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent. Marvellous. A sight to behold. You have got my gratitude, loyal brother.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\ -->

</string_table>