<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="about_baraholka_hunter_trader_0">
		<text>Why exactly is this place called the “flea market”?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_baraholka_hunter_trader_1">
		<text>Never been to such a place in the Great Land? Let's just say this place is a market, albeit an unusual market. There are no big shot hucksters around here like Sidorovich, only guys that sell what they owe and what they find on the ground! By the way, you can get some nice goods around here at night, and the whole place has also got a nice background to it. A while ago, there were a bunch of guys in the ruins of the building nearby until they were driven off by Dutyers who didn't particularly like the fact that they were trading artifacts. Those bastards didn't care where they got it from or how; only the prices mattered to them! They decided to bring back the past recently, the Duty boys holed up in their bar anyway, and the bandits don't know about this place. The building's inconspicuous and quite cozy... I don't even know where that steel door leads. I joined them later, when my combat skills started to soften up...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="about_dog_marsh_part_two_0">
		<text>I spoke to Noah.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dog_marsh_part_two_1">
		<text>Oh, I forgot about the request. So what does he have there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dog_marsh_part_two_2">
		<text>They say her name's Lassie. She's got two puppies, and they haven't shown any kind of aggressive behavior.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dog_marsh_part_two_3">
		<text>Puppies? Never thought you'd ever see that in the Zone. Well, thanks. Now I know that there are more friendly pseudodogs breeding in the Zone. Here are a few provisions for your future journeys... and, if you need it, you can have some information about a route between the army warehouses and the Red Forest. It's remained with us like an echo from the past.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="about_esc_m_trader_call_tips">
		<text>“Opening hours: 06:00–20:00”</text>
	</string>



	<string id="about_freedom_lider_miklyha_0">
		<text>Are you the stalker who reached the center of the Zone and stayed there for half a year?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_freedom_lider_miklyha_1">
		<text>Well, not half a year, just over a month. But yeah, name's Mikluha. Nice to meet you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_freedom_lider_miklyha_2">
		<text>How was it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_freedom_lider_miklyha_3">
		<text>Sorry, but I'd rather not start reminiscing. What matters most is that I got out safe and sound.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_freedom_lider_miklyha_4">
		<text>Got it. Thanks anyway.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="about_gar_talk_to_choper_0">
		<text>Tell me about this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_gar_talk_to_choper_1">
		<text>What can I say? This place isn't really the best. Radiation chews you up through the ass, and it's full of freaks like Dutyers and bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_gar_talk_to_choper_2">
		<text>And how are the sights?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_gar_talk_to_choper_3">
		<text>I guess the flea market here's the main landmark... There's the train hangar north of here. Don't go there, it's chock full of bandits. Further north along the road is the entrance to the Bar, guarded by sentries from Duty. Close by near the road to the Cordon is a substation of some sort, but nobody goes there. It's just a good-for-nothing area full of anomalies. And by the way, we've got three whopping spots full of anomalies in the area, and one of them is, unfortunately, in the substation itself... lots of Electros and shit. The stalkers have chosen these areas and aren't letting anyone pass, although that doesn't matter to the bandits; they haven't come here to hunt artifacts, but rather steal them from those who possess them... which is why they have such a strategic advantage, being located right by the entrance to the Bar. The wildlife here ain't too bad, as long as you stay on the surface and out of the substation. There's a tunnel the railway in the train hangar leads into, and damned if I know what's there... for all I know, not even the bandits have gone there... egh, and I've heard that a certain type of local fauna has gathered there.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_0">
		<text>Since you're an expert hunter, I'd like to know some more about mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_1">
		<text>There are a few cute rodents in the Zone, called “tushkanos”. You've seen them for sure. They don't really seem dangerous, but in packs, they can easily kill even an experienced stalker. There was a case where a special detachment of Dutyers went to sweep a bloodsucker lair. Those idiots made camp somewhere in the middle of the Agroprom complex... One of the guys took off somewhere while another screwed around on his PDA. No one was keeping the night watch. Morning came, and no one was there; something was wrong. The first people to enter that room were in for a big surprise... The throats of the squad members had been all chewed up. Typical tushkano traces. God knows why the rodents just up and left their meal. Anyway, the rest of the soldiers decided to head to the lair and finish the job, writing off the deaths of their comrades afterwards. That's how those men perished. Some stalker ended up retrieving their PDAs, having a new story to tell in the Bar for shits and giggles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_2">
		<text>Every rookie encounters a few dogs at the Cordon, as well as in the Great Land. They don't really differ that much from their “prototypes”, so to speak... except they're blind, but that doesn't really keep them down, since their other senses have evolved... especially their ability to smell. They can take out newbies like fish in a barrel, and sometimes more experienced stalkers, too, mostly thanks to their maneuverability and sudden strikes. Hey, here's a story for you: somebody made it a habit to snatch some sausage from the Bar. Everyone raised some fuss, tore up the security, and some men from Duty even ended up keeping watch and check who was stealing. Eventually, they saw a dog run in through a hole in the fence and, naturally, shot it down. In the morning, a solemn-looking stalker comes into the Bar and asks about the dog... Barman realizes what's happening and tells him to ask the guys from Duty. Turns out the fresh-faced lad was moving to the Zone with that dead dog, who was his pet. They went though a lot... The guy was also an orphan, and then this happens to him. Ever since that moment, any wise guy who crosses the border into the Zone with a pet either keeps moving or makes dinner out of his “little friend” for other stalkers... just to keep tensions low. By the way, all that sausage was actually stolen by a local alcoholic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_3">
		<text>There are dogs, and there are pseudodogs. Why “pseudo”, you ask? Well, they originally evolved from wild wolves. On their own, they are easily dispatched by point blank buckshot rounds, much like ordinary wild dogs. However, a pack of pseudodogs is nothing to scoff at. Moreover, they conjure clones of themselves that swarm you... and when that happens, you need to find and kill the real one for the phantoms to stop appearing, otherwise you end up wasting precious ammo and risk getting yourself badly hurt. Those creatures are very reasonable, though, and there are even legends about, claiming they can be tamed. The Swamp Doctor's pseudodog is an example. You can go find him if you don't believe me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_4">
		<text>Let me tell you about snorks. The most common theory is that they're former military personnel who guarded the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant before the second explosion, when it completely fried their brains and turned them into abominations. Something like a zombie, only... even more bestial and primitive. Another theory is that they were exposed to some kind of gas prior to their change, which explains why all of them wear gas masks. When the first emission struck, it was powerful enough to vaporize anyone in the vicinity of the power plant in the blink of an eye, even collapsing underground structures, causing the substance to leak out of a secret complex or something. They crawl on all fours, claw, kick, and even pounce fairly long distances to close in on their prey. Just one is dangerous, but a group of them? Might as well off yourself right then and there. If you ever come across snorks, sidestep their pounce, then blast their ass full of lead. Heck, if you're confident, but also have a death wish, you can kill them in midair. Good luck with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_5">
		<text>Zombies. You know those American flicks where zombies just grunt, moan, and attack with their hands? Well, it ain't like that in Zone... sort of. Most zombies here are former stalkers, their brains completely mashed, torn, and battered by the Brain Scorcher. A lot of them still retain their speech and are also capable of operating firearms. It's hard to understand what they're saying most of the time... Many of them are also slaves to a controller that exploits them for various purposes, although rarely, the controller uses his “servants” as food. Sakharov might be able to give you a better understanding. There's also a more barbaric, generic type of zombie, more like the ones you see in movies. They're slow, and not at all capable of using guns, so it should be simple to kill them... just don't let yourself get cornered. They also feign death quite well... shoot them anywhere other than the head, and they'll fall over and wait for your closure. It's best to confirm the kill by shooting them in the head from a distance while they're down, as they emit lots of radiation up close. According to a few documents discovered by the Marked One during his prime years, as well as a few other stalkers, the uniforms some of the more ordinary zombies wear was experimental, suggesting the zombies might've been something more than just working men. It's likely they originate from laboratories and complexes, and there's bound to be more of them located underground, so be wary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_6">
		<text>Bloodsuckers, perhaps? Let's see. Rumor has it they're mutated human beings. Whether or not they mutated from the radiation after the explosions or were scientifically modified by other humans, I don't know. What I do know, however, is that they're one of the most dangerous predators inhabiting the Zone. Not only do they boast incredible speed, but they also camouflage themselves, making them extremely dangerous and aggressive beasts. They use stealth and circle around you, tiring your legs out, waiting for the perfect moment to strike; and when they do, it's curtains for you. See, their name speaks for itself. They drain so much blood that by the time you unhinge those slimy feelers off your neck, you might as well be a piece of paper floating in the wind. I've heard stories of a stalker having committed suicide while being circled indefinitely by a bloodsucker. It's almost like a game to them, really. When they're not sucking your blood through a straw, their razor sharp claws come into play. Just like snorks, you can avoid their attacks, but you gotta expect it: be alert, use a shotgun, aim for the head, then fire. Rookies end up with empty mags and often fatal wounds. You'd better find a high spot or stick close to an object, keeping both of your eyes open, because the bastard will appear right before you. Keep your trigger finger on the ready and fire right as the sucker closes in. That's the best tactic if they find you alone... running away from them is problematic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_7">
		<text>Burers. They are near-legendary creatures, the existence of which many don't even want to know... Personally, I shit myself with fear just thinking about them. The best advice I can give regarding burers is to not head into dungeons or any kinds of empty complexes, laboratories in particular, because they love dwelling in such places. Recently, though, they have been sighted in pretty much every place in the Zone, and this is primarily thanks to to the actions of the Marked One, who turned off the Brain Scorcher. Chimeras too, for example, used to live closer to the center of the Zone, but then suddenly migrated and increased their population. Apparently, someone who runs all of this in the center of the Zone has got some influence over these creatures and is using them as a kind of Cerberus on the last approaches toward their “stronghold”. If you get into trouble and end up unable to escape, I'd advise you to protect your head, because they've got relatively powerful telekinesis powers. They can fire a focused impulse and knock you off your feet, and also take away your weapons and exhaust you, somehow influencing the gravity around you. They resemble fat, hideous dwarfs, who wear huge shoes with their own characteristic sounds, as well as black cloaks, strangely enough sewn almost their size. I too think that they are the result of experiments in secret laboratories. There are also different subspecies of burers, for example fire and electric, just like poltergeists. Some argue that the poltergeist is an evolutionary stage of the burer... however, if an electric poltergeist acts on you only with telekinesis, then a corresponding burer can easily throw a ball of lightning at you or even a whole Electra anomaly, the size of a substation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_8">
		<text>Controllers are no joke: those monsters emit a steady psy-background and can manipulate the consciousness of any person. It's absolutely fatal to approach them without the right type of protection, and you're generally better off staying away from any places they might be dwelling in. They'll most likely just burn your brain out, not even zombifying you, in order to make some juicy grub out of you right then and there. Legend's going around saying that they can even talk, but I don't really believe it... Their high level of intellect is beyond doubt, though. Sometimes they can stage clever ambushes. They often wander alone, greedy for food, or thinking about whatever goes on in that screwed-up head of theirs... A stalker once dropped by and told me and the boys that there was a weird creature that settled down around Rostok. He went to have a look, but was stopped by a sudden, severe headache that almost made him drop his gun. So, he backed off, thinking it was just radiation... The rest of us went with him to scoop the place out, came in; and I also felt a headache! Later, we went back prepared, having taken some special pills that basically got rid of any emotions in our body. I looked around and saw a man-shaped figure sitting in the darkness. I opened fire, but it disappeared, and then, the bastard came out behind my back, and I shot him. Then I heard a faint, yet familiar voice... and couldn't believe it. I had shot down my friend Vasyuk. Eventually we managed to get rid of that mutant freak, but I quit hunting ever since and ended up opening a bar here. I was fortunate not to get killed. Redhead was a smart guy, so he took off to the north after what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_9">
		<text>And the cats... Have you seen those things? Oh, god. Only this place can turn pets into feral beasts. Their whole thyroid is swollen from all the radiation, along with tumors located inside their cheeks. I don't really know why those cats have become like this. They've grown in size with sharper claws, and they run like crazy. People usually have to get domestic cats down from trees... Here, you're the one who gets chased around. To make matters worse, they've developed a pack mentality similar to dogs and wolves. They're wild and they can be found anywhere in the Zone, so keep an eye on your surroundings at all times. They come running, and if you aren't careful, they will cling onto your ass and have a nice, tasty bite.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_10">
		<text>Not many people here believe in the paranormal, and everyone has their own faith. Some people believe in their own strength, some believe in their leaders, and some believe in alien intervention... but certainly not in God. However, there is still a monster by the name of “poltergeist”, because how else would you describe a translucent flying abomination that throws objects at you? Still, there's pretty much nothing in common between the mutant and the type of entity in folklore. You can kill it in quite ordinary ways. It doesn't react to salt—we had a poor bastard that tried it—and looks like a flying electric anomaly, or, less commonly, a fire essence. The electric one loves showering you with all sorts of random garbage, just like a burer, but the fire one is somehow able to create a jet of fire right in front of your face, similar in effect to a geyser and extremely hot. Shoot directly into the essence - you won't miss, but it is very difficult to kill because of its speed and maneuverability. In a few cases, stalkers have spotted some kind of black or smoky poltergeist. Nothing certain is known about its properties, but it's quite a rare specimen, and probably so because meeting with it means death in the vast majority of cases. It's even more difficult to kill because of its smoke that's harder to trace. Thus, aiming and shooting at its core is more difficult.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_11">
		<text>There are also creatures whose tales are told in front of campfires. They are called fractures. Humanoid creatures with hypertrophic arms and necks, they possess an abnormal hand that can break a person's chest, while the other is more often than not normal, without any anomalous property. There are a lot of stories about the fact that Fractures often like to come into contact with stalkers and ask for all kinds of crap, anywhere from cans to imported toothpaste. If you aren't lucky and don't have what it asks of you, then prepare for a fight or a certain death... especially death, because fractures often come into contact during a favorable situation for them; for example, if you are alone and he's already holding you from behind with his bucketed hand. If you do have what it asks of you, don't hand it over rushedly; rather, move away from it quietly and on all fours. That way, you won't get harmed. Anyway, those are all stories... who really knows. Some even leave provisions in places where fractures have been spotted, in vain hopes to drive them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_12">
		<text>Here's another one: the pseudogiant. Usually, its height never exceeds that of a human's... however, its powerful paws can cause very strong shock waves, which is how it earned its name. Until recently, again, nothing about it was known, and it is most likely another of those abominations from the laboratories, thanks to the underground assholes who love to rummage around every single complex and not close any doors behind them. To the north, there was some kind of military guy who never shut the door at some facility... at the Iron Forest in Zaton, I believe. Since then, these giants have been observed even in the vicinity of the Jupiter plant. By observing some of its features, it is possible to determine that “it” was once a man... like the small, hanging arms in front of the main ones, its skin, and a few other peculiar characteristics. It's got some sharp teeth, but don't worry about that, because it's more likely to just knock you down and crush you. And don't take its awkward appearance into account, because it never falls down and never goes astray. The best thing to do before venturing near an area where a pseudogiant has been spotted is to grab a couple of rifle grenades and a machine gun, as the skin and bones of the mutant have shown excellent resistance to small arms, and the creature itself is very resilient.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_13">
		<text>The chimera can rightfully be considered at the top of the food chain in the Zone. How come? It is a very clever creature: a nocturnal predator that can pounce at you with a single jump from a distance of several tens of meters. Four-legged mutant, has two heads, for which it has received its nickname. It is also very durable and has sharp claws, capable of tearing through even the skin of a pseudogiant. It lets out a characteristic roar while jumping, frighteningly similar to a person's. They've have mainly been encountered in the northern parts of the Zone, in open places near facilities or complexes. As told by local hunter Trapper, they have their own sphere of influence, where they rest and hunt during late at night. There is also a subspecies, namely the black chimera. It cannot be seen at all in the dark, which makes it much more dangerous than its relatives, as the usual ones have almost human skin color. It is also said to be stronger and more enduring... Escaping from a chimera is practically impossible. It's better to find a narrow room that will hamper its maneuverability, or try to jump aside while it leaps at you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_14">
		<text>Wild boars and flesh. The latter are an example of a terribly mutated pig, as proven by scientists. Those creatures are rather sluggish and weak, and only a complete moron could get under its “bladed” paws, which will penetrate virtually any armor. As for boars, differ little from their relatives outside the Zone, apart from the fact that they are larger and more dangerous... Oh, and their hooves are much stronger, and can cut through fabric and human flesh effortlessly. It's enough just to jump aside and move somewhere in a couple of meters when these beasts rush at you, to avoid their fangs. Oftentimes, the meat of both wild boars and flesh is consumed, but not without being treated beforehand, to avoid radiation poisoning.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_monsters_trader_hangar_15">
		<text>Karliks... Thanks for helping me gather information about them. Here's what I've jotted down: they mainly reside in underground complexes, most of which have previously been used for experiments on people. Apparently, Karliks are the result of such experiments. They possess supernatural strength, good speed and attack most often in groups. At the moment, only one subspecies has been discovered; smoked ones. Dirty, mutated by anomalies, they emit dangerous radiation, it is better not to go near them without a Wrenched or a Bubble in your pocket.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="agr_main_monolith_mlr_task_5_attack_done_message">
		<text>Mentor:\nFollow Inquisitor's orders, he still seeks your assistance. You will return to me later.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="agr_main_monolith_mlr_task_5_doc">
		<text>Documentation on recent orders</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_main_monolith_mlr_task_5_doc_desc">
		<text>These documents focus exclusively on order #66, which states that prototype item 62, along with all its respective documentation, was delivered to the NIICHAZ.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="agr_1_6_medic_army_mlr_hello_0">
		<text>Huh? Oh, it's you...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_1_6_medic_army_mlr_heal_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_1_6_medic_army_mlr_heal_1">
		<text>Alright, let's take a look... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_1_6_medic_army_mlr_heal_2">
		<text>Don't be ridiculous, you're fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_1_6_medic_army_mlr_heal_3">
		<text>How bad is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_1_6_medic_army_mlr_heal_4">
		<text>That's all. You can go.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_1">
		<text>Oh, I work as the technician here at the checkpoint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_2">
		<text>What do they call you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_3">
		<text>No need for formality and ranks... not on the parade ground, at least. In case of any attack, my name would be too long to pronounce. Name's Sergey, though I prefer Seryoga.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_4">
		<text>Nice to meet you, Seryoga.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_5">
		<text>Likewise. If you need anything fixed up, just let me know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_6">
		<text>What's the current situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_7">
		<text>Nothing interesting. There's a stalker village a bit to the north... Nothing but hostiles all the way up to Agroprom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_8">
		<text>So we're stuck here and in danger of being attacked at any moment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_9">
		<text>Nah, not too long ago, our commanding officers got us a BTR, although it's already broken down. Other than that, they've reinforced our patrols, and our helicopter's always ready to go. By the way, when you leave the checkpoint northside, stay on the road. There's a minefield on both sides.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_st_10">
		<text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>Seryoga, a military technician, has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>I do, actually. We recently left all our tools at the research complex in Yantar, which is why I can't even repair the BTR here. I need tools, basic ones. Mind helping out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I do, actually. We recently left all our tools at the research complex in Yantar, which is why I can't even repair the BTR here. I need tools, basic ones. Mind helping out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you so much! I will give you a discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_2_text">
		<text>Seryoga, a military technician, has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_2_about">
		<text>Sadly, the tools that you gave me aren't enough, as they only work for the most basic of upgrades. I need more advanced tools, they shouldn't be too rare to find. Could you find them for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Sadly, the tools that you gave me aren't enough, as they only work for the most basic of upgrades. I need more advanced tools, they shouldn't be too rare to find. Could you find them for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Much appreciated. A big “thank you” from everybody here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_3_text">
		<text>Seryoga, a military technician, has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_3_about">
		<text>I'm tired of rummaging around for BTR parts, it's time to get our guys equipped with some proper gear. I could use a different kind of tools... specifically, calibration tools. Can you provide me with those?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I'm tired of rummaging around for BTR parts, it's time to get our guys equipped with some proper gear. I could use a different kind of tools... specifically, calibration tools. Can you provide me with those?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_south_mechan_mlr_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Amazing. Never thought I'd see such sophisticated technology again... especially around these parts. And you won't stop me from giving you a fine discount.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="army_yan_mec_about_tool_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_yan_mec_about_tool_1">
		<text>I'm with the military, callsign “Peregrine”. We've got troops stationed here to help out with maintaining the equipment. I'm also a part-time technician, so if something breaks, it's up to me to take care of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_yan_mec_about_tool_2">
		<text>What's the current situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_yan_mec_about_tool_3">
		<text>To be honest with you, it's shit. I don't have the tools I need, all thanks to the outstanding supply of the higher-ups. The equipment the scientists have got here hasn't really been making it easy for us, and it's gonna need some higher quality modifications... Managed to get the old receiver here repaired, though it's still spouting a bunch of gibberish. Our guys kicked the bucket at the army warehouses a couple of years ago and it's still transmitting their voices.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_yan_mec_about_tool_4">
		<text>Well, this is the Zone, you never know what'll happen. Best wishes.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty_0">
		<text>They say you've got some interesting goods in exchange for Duty patches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty_1">
		<text>Of course! I can offer two hundred and ten 5.56 rounds for twenty patches, fifty 7.62 rounds for fifteen patches, twenty M209 underbarrel grenades for fifty patches, a scientific Freedom suit for fifty patches, a Freedom exoskeleton for sixty-five patches, and a unique SVD for a hundred patches.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_0">
		<text>I have a few patches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_1">
		<text>Oh, great! Take your pick: two hundred and ten 5.56 rounds for twenty patches, fifty 7.62 rounds for fifteen patches, twenty M209 underbarrel grenades for fifty patches, a scientific Freedom suit for fifty patches, a Freedom exoskeleton for sixty-five patches, or a specially crafted SVD for a hundred patches!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_2">
		<text>Two hundred and ten rounds of 5.56.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_3">
		<text>Fifty 7.62 rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_4">
		<text>Twenty M209 grenades should be good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_5">
		<text>Gimme that scientific suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_6">
		<text>I'll take the exo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_7">
		<text>Let me have that unique-looking SVD.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ashot_price_for_pathes_duty1_8">
		<text>I won't take anything. I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="aslan_st_0">
		<text>What's the current situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_1">
		<text>Well, the Syndicate only has one central base in the Zone, and it's right here. The path to Yantar is cut off because of the psy-installation, and crowds of zombies sometimes come out of there, along with mutants. Our guys occupy Limansk to the north, but other than that, that place has gone to shit. It's a maze full of Monolith. At the army warehouses in the east, it's all Freedom territory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_2">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_3">
		<text>As for any dangers, you'll see those for yourself. Keep in mind, though: when carrying out orders, you've got a job to do, and any emotions are just gonna distract you. Just put those aside. There's no room for emotion, no room for morality, only intellect and calculation. And regarding other paths, the safest route is through Limansk. There's plenty of closed space where you'll be safe from sniper fire, and you can hide from firefights as well as anomalies in shelter located around the city. The area's generally quite unpredictable, however. You can never know what exactly's around the corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_4">
		<text>You say that this base is central. Does that mean there are any other outposts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_5">
		<text>There are three locations I know of that are under our control. The first one is in Zaton, at the edge of the northern marshes. The second one is being held by a detachment of ours in the southwest part of the Pripyat outskirts, and the third squadron is stationed in the Red Forest, at the bridge to Limansk, where there's also a supply agent. Other than that, you can find our squads in various parts of the Zone when they're carrying out contracts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_6">
		<text>So anything north of Limansk is Monolith territory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_7">
		<text>Pretty much. There's an old hospital not far from Limansk. No point in going there... The path to the Chernobyl NPP, as well as the one leading to Yantar are both cut off by psy-emissions. After you reach Limansk, stay on the southern road and make sure you've got some supplies with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aslan_st_8">
		<text>Understood, thanks for the info.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_start_dlg_0">
		<text>Ah, a new face in my diner. Welcome, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_start_dlg_1">
		<text>You work as a cook here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_start_dlg_2">
		<text>Yeah, guess my time at that sharashka paid off. Have some vodka to your heart's content. If you wanna have a drink, a snack, and a laugh, you found the right place. This certainly ain't no 100 Rads, but on the other hand, we ain't got wimpy knuckleheads around here, either. Our boys are square and our spoons in one piece, tee-hee.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_start_dlg_3">
		<text>I'll make sure to drop by.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_about_lottery_0">
		<text>Is there anything to do around here? I'm fucking bored.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_about_lottery_1">
		<text>Out of luck, aren't you, sucker? I've got a lottery of sorts for ya. Just for shits and giggles, you can fetch me some patches from other groupings and win yourself some decent gizmos... or end up with jack shit, he-he.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_about_lottery_2">
		<text>I'll have tried. Let's see what kind of scam you've got, big shot.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_ab_find_number_0">
		<text>Anything else fun to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_ab_find_number_1">
		<text>Do I look like a damn clown to you?... Actually, I have an idea. We can play some Russian roulette: I've got an old revolver here, and we can fire off the entire cylinder. Obviously, I'm gonna shoot into the air and not into myself. You win, you earn five patches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_ab_find_number_2">
		<text>Let's start.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_0">
		<text>Take out your gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_1">
		<text>He-he, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_2">
		<text>[pull the trigger]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_3">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_4">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_5">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_6">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_7">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_8">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_9">
		<text>[pull the trigger]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_10">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_11">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_12">
		<text>[miss]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_13">
		<text>[pull the trigger]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_14">
		<text>You've got some balls! Five grand for you, big boy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_dar_mlr_find_number_15">
		<text>Aw, fuck! You win, here's your stuff.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bandit_barman_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Strange tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>Zhuchila has complained about the recklessness of local hoodlums. You have been asked to go to the railway tunnel opposite the depot and find the SVD.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>Yeah, got one thing. Some asshole went into the nearby tunnel, apparently wanted to show something to his friends, and you know that tunnel; terrible place. He came back with a brand new SVD! Surely stole it from someone—fuck if I know who—but it's clear that the fucker ran into some creatures there who ended up knocking his rifle from his hands, and that was end of that. You're gonna go after that beauty, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Yeah, got one thing. Some asshole went into the nearby tunnel, apparently wanted to show something to his friends, and you know that tunnel; terrible place. He came back with a brand new SVD! Surely stole it from someone—fuck if I know who—but it's clear that the fucker ran into some creatures there who ended up knocking his rifle from his hands, and that was end of that. You're gonna go after that beauty, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_barman_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Fucking awesome. Here, take this and have yourself a nap or something... and I'll think about who I can pass this loot off to.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bandit_gar_smart_terrain_5_2_medic_mlr_heal_0">
		<text>Think I've caught a bullet or two.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_gar_smart_terrain_5_2_medic_mlr_heal_1">
		<text>Aw, caught a bullet? Need your wound kissed? Man, get your ass over here and ready the dough, two grand.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_heal_5">
			<text>I think I feel better already... I'm gonna get going.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="bandit_gar_smart_terrain_5_2_medic_mlr_heal_2">
		<text>You're healthy, alright. Man, if you're here just to waste my time, I might as well take your nuts, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_gar_smart_terrain_5_2_medic_mlr_heal_3">
		<text>Screw you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_heal_4">
		<text>Okay, you'll live. Get going, and don't forget about the brotherhood.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bandit_main_base_medic_mlr_heal_0">
		<text>Need a check-up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_main_base_medic_mlr_heal_1">
		<text>Ah, of course, can't even keep yourself in one piece. Let's see... Oh, and cough up a thousand, will you?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="bandit_main_base_medic_mlr_heal_5">
			<text>I'd rather freaking go to Kiev from here than entrust myself to you for that much money.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="bandit_main_base_medic_mlr_heal_2">
		<text>Hands and feet are okay... Dick is in place... Yeah, you're alright.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_main_base_medic_mlr_heal_3">
		<text>How bad is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_main_base_medic_mlr_heal_4">
		<text>Fuck, man, I don't understand any of this shit. Whatever, you should be better now.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_0">
		<text>Share your story, brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_1">
		<text>You trying to get me prosecuted or something? Whatever, get comfortable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_2">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_3">
		<text>There were times when my face was constantly on a roll of honor... I worked as a mechanical engineer at a plant and got recognized in my company as the best specialist in that profession. They awarded me prizes and certificates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_4">
		<text>I'm guessing you wanted to get some tail?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_5">
		<text>Don't interrupt me... and do pay attention to my name.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_6">
		<text>They call you Limpid because you've got something limp down under?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_7">
		<text>Real funny guy. Anyway, I enjoyed hanging out with my guys after a long shift. Had a few too many drinks... The boss caught us, and I got fired like some stupid loser.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_8">
		<text>Life's a bitch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_9">
		<text>The bitch that all of us have to put up with. Got a job as an ordinary locksmith and found a new friend by the name of Vitka. Barely got paid jack shit, but thankfully I earned enough to get myself a few rounds once in a while. At one time we got drunk and fucked around... don't even remember why. Anyway, I stabbed him with a screwdriver. Good thing that he didn't die right then and there. Spent a few years in maximum security while my bitch wife sold everything and ran off. When I got released, I spent all my money on drinks and ended up in the slums... Got here when the Zone came about. Here, everyone's equal. We're all outcasts. I met up with the guys at the Garbage. They found me useful as a technician and let me stay there. Best time in my life... tons of guns and vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_10">
		<text>This isn't the Garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_11">
		<text>Again with your damn interrupting. The big-ass Emission happened, and we hid like little girls. When that nightmare was over with, we had a meeting on where the fuck to go: the Garbage turned out to be a bad shelter from those kinds of emissions. We had to leave it for good and move through different roads in small groups to this place: the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_mechanic_st_12">
		<text>That's quite a story.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>The technician at the Garbage has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>Yeah, man, of course there's work for you here. Frankly, it's embarrassing for me to ask you for help, but fuck it, no one here's getting me the stuff I need. Basically, I need some tools for rough work. If you find any, deliver 'em here, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Yeah, man, of course there's work for you here. Frankly, it's embarrassing for me to ask you for help, but fuck it, no one here's getting me the stuff I need. Basically, I need some tools for rough work. If you find any, deliver 'em here, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Fuck, man, you've really helped the lads. Brothers don't forget their own, so I'll give you a discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_2_text">
		<text>The technician at the Garbage has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_2_about">
		<text>It doesn't feel complete... my equipment. These tools aren't enough. The others have looked around, but couldn't find a thing. What do you say? Wanna help out the brotherhood once more?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>It doesn't feel complete... my equipment. These tools aren't enough. The others have looked around, but couldn't find a thing. What do you say? Wanna help out the brotherhood once more?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_tech_gar_hangr_mlr_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Respect from the heart, man! Drop by anytime and I'll help you out with these tools, you'll always be welcome here. Sorry I ain't got any beer for you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bandit_trader_st_0">
		<text>Why is your nickname so lousy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_1">
		<text>Look who's talking! Goddamn greenhorns, trying to act all tough... You don't handle them, they can't even hold their own dicks straight when taking a piss. If you do, they act like lousy morons, to put it in your words.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_2">
		<text>Hey, easy. Didn't mean anything by it. Just didn't know what to say.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_3">
		<text>Alright, whatever... Apology accepted. Things ain't easy when you get old and your nerves have gone to shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_4">
		<text>Understood. How did you get your name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_5">
		<text>I'll tell you, if only to put an end to your yapping. My story began under the Soviet Union, before the first time I ended up in prison. I wanted a good life... Did some trade hustle, and been caught for that one day. So after I did my time, I started making new connections and selling stolen stuff. Did that for three years before I, once again, ended up in jail. Got out, but the USSR was gone... You know what the most frustrating thing was?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_6">
		<text>No. Never saw the Soviet Union at a reasonable age.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_7">
		<text>First time I ended up in prison, it was “business”... or “profiteering”, in old Soviet speech. Nowadays, anyone who's successful can end up behind bars. That place is where you feel your ass burn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_8">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_9">
		<text>When I got out of my second stint, everything crashed down. No income at all, and there were loads of people around who were doing the same thing as me. When the Zone came into existence, I figured I'd go see it for myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_10">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_11">
		<text>By the way, they call me Olivius because I tend to try out the cargo people take to me firsthand. I'm keen about quality and condition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_st_12">
		<text>Thanks for the history lesson. Sorry once again.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_task_4_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_task_4_text">
		<text>Petrenko wants you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_task_4_about">
		<text>The men could use some help on a mutant hunt. Are you in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_task_4_fetch_about">
		<text>The men could use some help on a mutant hunt, will you join them? I'd like you to bring back %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_general_petrenko_stalker_task_4_fetch_finish">
		<text>You've earned a big “thank you” and a reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hello_0">
		<text>What is it?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_dialog_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_dialog_1">
		<text>You hand over two thousand, I'll fix you up.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="bar_dolg_medic_dialog_5">
			<text>I don't think so.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_dialog_2">
		<text>You're fit as a fiddle. Now go, I'm busy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_dialog_3">
		<text>How bad is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_dialog_4">
		<text>You're fine, the door's that way. Also, don't forget to take your medicine.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Find the %s artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>Barman has asked you to find a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>I'm interested in artifacts. I give you the coordinates to a certain artifact, you bring it to me... and you also get a reward, of course. Sound good?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I need an artifact, %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done, stalker. Here is your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Assassinate stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>A stalker needs to be taken out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>I have a few takeout jobs from various stalkers and a couple of high-ranking names in Duty. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_2_finish">
		<text>Here's your money. Just don't get carried away with killing.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Destroy the mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>A few stalkers have set out to eliminate a group of mutants. Barman has tasked you with assisting them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_3_about">
		<text>Some stalkers could use some help with taking out a few mutants. I'll give you the coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_barman_stalker_trader_task_3_finish">
		<text>Good work. Here's the money.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bar_visitors_sad_veteran_task_1_name">
		<text>Find out about the fate of the Duty squad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_sad_veteran_task_1_text">
		<text>A squad of Dutyers was last seen in the truck cemetery, near a chemical anomaly. You have been asked to investigate their fate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_sad_veteran_task_1_about">
		<text>Work? I don't think you can help me... Actually, wait. My comrades and I went to the truck cemetery for a recon assignment. You know the place? A boundless area with the empty shells of Soviet vehicles. We were told that there was a squad of Freedomers somewhere in the vicinity. We never managed to find those cocksuckers... but we did find something else. Something frightening, that—that made my friends... fall to their knees and grab their heads. I have no idea why the same didn't happen to me, or why I ran away. It's a shame. Look, I certainly don't believe that my guys are still alive, as they've been gone for a couple of days... but can you at least confirm their deaths? I'll send you the coordinates via PDA; it's near some kind of chemical anomaly. Can you help me, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_visitors_sad_veteran_task_1_finish">
		<text>So they're dead? Freaking... dog tags. I'm sorry... Here's my backup gun, along with some optics for it. Thank you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="baraholka_trader_talking_0">
		<text>What kind of place is this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_talking_1">
		<text>This, my man, is the flea market. Us here sell bit by bit. Truthfully, the stuff here is pretty garbage, but we have to make do. So, you trading?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_talking_2">
		<text>Are you the only trader here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_talking_3">
		<text>What? No! Other guys trade here, we just have one rule: any big deals don't happen before sunset. The guy over at the table is also a trader, and that's not counting the barman who I hope you've noticed. At night, the real life begins... the goods are completely different.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Bring the container to Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>A trader at the flea market in the Garbage has offered you some courier work in the form of getting a container unlocked. The services of a technician will be required.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>You look like a decent guy. I got some dirty work need doing... Can you bring this case to Sakharov?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_1_finish">
		<text>Well done, man.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the %s artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>An employer at the flea market in the Garbage has asked you to find a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>There's always work to do. I need an artifact. Will you go get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>There's always work to do. I need an artifact, called %s. Will you get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done, you deserve this.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="baraholka_trader_night_task_1_name">
		<text>Find the %s artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_night_task_1_text">
		<text>The trader at the flea market wants me to find a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_night_task_1_about">
		<text>You want to earn some loot looking for artifacts of the less common variety? I can offer you some good equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_night_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Feel like earning some loot while looking for rare artifacts? For a %s, I can offer you some more stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_night_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Ah, great work, stalker. Here, for you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_sapsan_talk_0">
		<text>Are you familiar with this kind of container?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_sapsan_talk_1">
		<text>Where did you get that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_sapsan_talk_2">
		<text>A flea marketer asked me to deliver it. Shall we share the stuff fifty-fifty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_sapsan_talk_3">
		<text>You sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_sapsan_talk_4">
		<text>Yeah. Let's get it opened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_sapsan_talk_5">
		<text>Actually, never mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_task_sapsan_talk_6">
		<text>Well, look here. Take anything you like.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="baraholka_trader_two_talk_0">
		<text>What is this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baraholka_trader_two_talk_1">
		<text>Man, you're in the flea market. Stalkers around here trade whatever they can get their hands on; to my right behind the bar is our bartender and part-time hunter, although retired. Left on the couch is my colleague.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="barter_povar_army_0">
		<text>I've brought some vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_1">
		<text>Oh, finally, something to drink. Is there anything particular you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_2">
		<text>Six mags of 9x18.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_3">
		<text>Three 5.45 mags.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_4">
		<text>Six 5.45 mags.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_5">
		<text>Some buckshot shells.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_6">
		<text>Two mags of 7.62.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_7">
		<text>Five boxes for the PKP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barter_povar_army_8">
		<text>The Berill suit.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="barter_povar_army_10">
			<text>I've given the signal to my comrades. You can go pick it up.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barter_povar_army_11">
			<text>I've given the signal to my comrades. You can go pick it up.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barter_povar_army_12">
			<text>I've given the signal to my comrades. You can go pick it up.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barter_povar_army_13">
			<text>I've given the signal to my comrades. You can go pick it up.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barter_povar_army_14">
			<text>I've given the signal to my comrades. You can go pick it up.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barter_povar_army_15">
			<text>I've given the signal to my comrades. You can go pick it up.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barter_povar_army_16">
			<text>I've given the signal to my comrades. You can go pick it up.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="barter_povar_army_9">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="blackbox_mlr">
		<text>Flight recorder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blackbox_mlr_descr">
		<text>Or “black box”, as it is commonly named in media. Flight data recorders are used to record internal aircraft systems and crew conversations, usually storing data that could be useful in the event of determining the cause of a crash. In the Zone, such devices are used on all aircraft, though a proper “black box” is not always fitted. Both the military and different types of dealers may show an interest in it, and they have also proven to be sought-after wares among communities of stalkers.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="border_freedom_keeper_max_task_1_name">
		<text>Hold off the first wave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="border_freedom_keeper_max_task_1_name_1">
		<text>Hold off the second wave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="border_freedom_keeper_max_task_1_name_2">
		<text>Hold off the third wave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="border_freedom_keeper_max_task_1_name_3">
		<text>Return to Max</text>
	</string>
	<string id="border_freedom_keeper_max_task_1_text">
		<text>Max has asked me to defend the Barrier against hordes of zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="border_freedom_keeper_max_task_1_about">
		<text>Okay, listen. Our scouts have noticed a large build-up of zombies at the Barrier. Corpses are regularly migrating because of the absence of radiation, and that's how additional zombie forces come out. We'll take any help if you're willing to offer it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="border_freedom_keeper_max_task_1_finish">
		<text>Thanks for the assistance, man. Take what I have left.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="brain_on_staff_1_0">
		<text>Professor, you must have something that interests you more than anything else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brain_on_staff_1_1">
		<text>Yes, I do have something. I require fresh brain tissue from a controller in order to continue conducting research in psy-emissions. In exchange, I will offer you ten first-aid kits, either scientific or army-made, a Veles detector, or three packs of anabiotics... provided you return, of course.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="brain_on_staff_0">
		<text>I'm back, and with the brain tissue as well. Here, Professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brain_on_staff_1">
		<text>Splendid! Now, I can offer you ten scientific or army first-aid kits, a Veles-class detector, or three packs of anabiotics. The choice is yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brain_on_staff_2">
		<text>I'll take ten scientific medkits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brain_on_staff_3">
		<text>Ten army medkits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brain_on_staff_4">
		<text>Could use the Veles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brain_on_staff_5">
		<text>Anabiotics would be preferred.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brain_on_staff_6">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="bridge_down_red_forest_tips">
		<text>Lower bridge ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bridge_stop_red_forest_tips">
		<text>Stop bridge ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bridge_up_red_forest_tips">
		<text>Raise bridge ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>



	<string id="buy_information_from_trader_0">
		<text>Got any fresh information?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_1">
			<text>I've got information about the Swamp Doctor for seven thousand.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_6">
			<text>I'm listening.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_11">
			<text>The old man is in the Great Swamps, constantly waiting for his friend Strelok. Some stalker visited him recently, and the Doctor told him his story and something else of importance: the story of Strelok's group itself! You can find him and hear it for yourself.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_2">
			<text>Got information about some stalker looking for Strelok's group for ten grand.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_7">
			<text>I'm all ears.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_12">
			<text>This very stalker who visited the Doctor is now out looking for traces of Strelok's group. He's already been to the laboratories in Dark Valley and Yantar, and it's obvious he ain't stopping there. Judging by proven sources, he wants to break into the center of the Zone and finish what the group of stalkers never managed to carry through.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_3">
			<text>I have information that sheds light on the second shutdown of the Brain Scorcher, but only for fifteen grand.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_8">
			<text>Gimme.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_13">
			<text>This same stalker shut down the Brain Scorcher! I wonder when they're gonna try tearing up the control center instead of turning off the switch every time? There are rumors that he's currently heading to Pripyat and that he has some sort of assignment from the Doctor. I don't know if the old man wants to find his friend, or if there's something else behind it.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_4">
			<text>I can post information about the adventures of a mysterious stalker who explored the Generators for twenty-four thousand.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_9">
			<text>Pass it.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="buy_information_from_trader_14">
			<text>Have you ever heard about the Generators? Until recently, they were only considered a myth... but after Strelok's second campaign toward the center of the Zone, there's no doubt they're real. There have been constant disputes about what they really are, but old satellite images suggests some kind of weird infrastructure, in whose honor the entire area was named. Apparently, that's the place the Monolith carry out their orders and all important procedures regarding the territory of the Zone. So the stalker's already gone there, and I think he's serious. His intervention might have a major impact on the Zone. The leaders of a few factions have already expressed their discontent regarding this information.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="buy_information_from_trader_5">
		<text>Not at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="buy_information_from_trader_10">
		<text>Not interested.</text>
	</string>



	<!--

	<string id="barman_change_music_intro_0">
		<text>Do you have any other music?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_change_music_intro_1">
		<text>I've only got Okean Elzy on my laptop. For three thousand, I'll let you enjoy it to your heart's content.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="barman_change_music_turn_0">
		<text>I'd like the music changed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_change_music_turn_1">
		<text>What would you like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_change_music_turn_2">
		<text>The usual.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_change_music_turn_3">
		<text>Okean Elzy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_change_music_turn_4">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>

	-->



	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Eliminate the target</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>The mercenaries have designated a target for you to get rid of.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>We've always got some work. I give you coordinates, you kill a target.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_1_finish">
		<text>Well done. Here's your money.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_2_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_2_text">
		<text>Aslan has asked you to collect %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_2_about">
		<text>Feel like hunting a few people? I'll tell you how many patches you have to strip, and you bring them to me and earn a reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Feel like hunting a few people down? Bring me %s and you'll be handsomely rewarded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_merc_barman_mlr_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done. Here's your money.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="container_with_an_artefacts_baraholka">
		<text>Container</text>
	</string>
	<string id="container_with_an_artefacts_baraholka_descr">
		<text>A locked container, appearing to store a number of objects.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Clean up the mutant lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>Axeman has asked you to destroy the lair of a few mutants that have been stirring up some trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>I need a mutant den taken care of. This place isn't too popular among stalkers, so peoples' wishes about getting here don't happen because of the damn mutants, who are out and about in the forest, the road, even on the approaches. I've got the coordinates and a reward if you can carry out a cleanup. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_1_finish">
		<text>Thanks, maybe more people will end up coming here. Here, as a reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the %s artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_2_text">
		<text>Axeman has asked you to find and return a specific artifact on behalf of a customer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>There are a few buyers here who would be interested in a certain artifact, but since the anomalies here are poor, I prefer to entrust artifact hunting to stalkers. I'd like a %s, and you'll be rewarded, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done, just what I need. Here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_3_name">
		<text>Destroy the bandit's encampment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_3_text">
		<text>It is necessary to assault the bandit's encampment and destroy them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_3_about">
		<text>There's a former military outpost in the vicinity that was formerly occupied by the military... and now the bandits have settled there. Can you deal with them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_trade_mlr_task_3_finish">
		<text>Awesome, man. Here's the reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="disgusting_trees_tips">
		<text>Cut bark ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ds_killer_medic_mlr_heal_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_killer_medic_mlr_heal_1">
		<text>Right, let's take a look... and you had better shell out three thousand.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="ds_killer_medic_mlr_heal_5">
			<text>I don't have any money.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="ds_killer_medic_mlr_heal_2">
		<text>Everything's fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_killer_medic_mlr_heal_3">
		<text>How bad is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_killer_medic_mlr_heal_4">
		<text>Right, everything should be in order now... I hope.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_1_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Are you our guide? I will be marking the location on your PDA. You need to protect us on the way there and, once our task is accomplished, lead us back. You will receive the reward upon your return to the camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_1_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Is it important? We need to hurry, it'll be dangerous to stay here for too long.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_1_complete">
		<text>Thank you, stalker, you've done a good job. Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_1_actor_reply">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_2_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Aren't you an expert on the surrounding area? Hm, then lead the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_2_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Do you want something? If not, then let's not get distracted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_2_complete">
		<text>Thank you, fellow. Have one of our weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_companion_task_mlr_2_actor_reply">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_0">
		<text>How are you holding up, big guy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_1">
		<text>Hey. Getting better by the day. The main gash's been stitched, but it hurts like a motherfucker. I guess I moved around too much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_2">
		<text>And what were you doing there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_3">
		<text>Well, I was looking for an adventure. There was a rumor that, like, after a blowout, the tunnel went down only partially and something weird was found there. Maybe some beasts inhabited it, as they say that bodies have been found in the roundabouts... oddly, without any weapons. It's only afterward that I figured what was going on, even scooted without my bag. Good thing I retrieved it in the end. These creatures appeared, like, from thin air! Fucked up shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_4">
		<text>Better not stick your nose out... especially since you've got a handy skill that lets you just sit around and make cash. It's not like doctoring Soviet grans for wee wage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_5">
		<text>You're right, I'm talking bull. Alright, see you around, friend. Still gotta sort out some ampoules here. Good hunting!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_1">
		<text>Let's have a look, partner...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_2">
		<text>Not sure what you need, everything's fine. Drink something for psy-protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_3">
		<text>How bad is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_4">
		<text>Uh-huh... I see, keep still for a moment... Right, let's get you patched up and on the way to a recovery!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_name_1">
		<text>First aid: examine or ignore the signal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_name_2">
		<text>First aid: find the medic kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_name_3">
		<text>First aid: return the medical kit to the stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_name_4">
		<text>First aid: escort the stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_name_5">
		<text>First aid: speak to the stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_text_descr">
		<text>A distress signal from a stalker has come your way, stating that he requires assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_message">
		<text>Kashpirovsky:\nAnyone out there? Help... I'm bleedin' out at the entrance to the railway tunnel, to the east.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_medbag">
		<text>Medical kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_medbag_desc">
		<text>An ordinary medical kit with bandages and drugs for countering the dangers of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_medbag_hidden_search_tips">
		<text>Inspect masonry ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_2_0">
		<text>Hey, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_2_1">
		<text>No time for chit-chat, my wounds could get infected... Damn snork bruised me and almost chewed off my hand! Quick, my medic bag's in that hole... without it, I'm dead.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_0">
		<text>Here's your bag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_1">
		<text>I'm gonna down some pills first, and then bandage these wounds... Ow, shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_2">
		<text>Everything alright?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_3">
		<text>Yeah, yeah, I'm okay. Here, take a couple of first aid kits just in case. Let's head to the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_4">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_4_0">
		<text>So how do you feel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_4_1">
		<text>Ugh, feels like the whole world is spinning... wonder how I even got here. Gonna lie down and have myself some ammonia, then I'll have to patch myself up. Hey, take as much money as you need from the backpack and come back in a few days if you need any help. Oh, by the way, never introduced myself... They call me Kashpirovsky. I'll be staying around here to treat local stalkers. I'd better get going, my legs aren't gonna keep up for much longer.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_1_name">
		<text>Destroy the mutant lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_1_text">
		<text>A mutant lair needs to be destroyed in order to protect the rookies in the village and any other stalkers passing through the Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_1_about">
		<text>We've got a problem. The mutants have found a new spot to settle down at, and every day in the Cordon has been getting more and more dangerous with those things around... We just can't let them grow in numbers. You're gonna have to head over there and take out anything you find. Everyone here will be in your debt if you get it done. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_1_finish">
		<text>Great work. Thanks to you, the area will be safer for the rookies. Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_2_name">
		<text>Find a Pellicle artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_2_text">
		<text>Fanatic has asked you to find a Pellicle artifact for a rookie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>So, here's the deal. A rookie of ours went to Agroprom recently, all prepared for a merry adventure with a pistol in his right hand and a detector in his left. He scavenged some anomalous area for goodies and ended up finding an artifact. On his way back to the village some army patrol stopped him and took his artifact along with the rest of his stuff. Now he's just sitting there, absolutely devastated by what happened. It was his first artifact, and they call it a Pellicle. I would go look for it myself, but I can't leave the rookies alone. They need some protection, and they've still got a lot to learn. So, will you help him out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_fanat_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Ah, you've found a Pellicle? Excellent, I think the stalker will be happy. I sure don't need him whining and sobbing all day... Gets annoying putting up with all of that. Anyway, thanks for the help.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>Zhurov has asked you to bring %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>The top brass has launched an unofficial program, you wanna take part? As proof, I require patches from criminals in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>The top brass has launched an unofficial program, you wanna take part? You can gather %s, don't strain yourself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Hah, you're certainly no slouch. Nice work, here's your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the AK-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>Zhurov has mentioned that one of his subordinates has lost his registered assault rifle somewhere in the territory of the southern checkpoint in the Cordon. It needs to be found.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>Glad you asked. Quite a lousy accident happened not long ago; namely, one of the soldiers lost his rifle. He says it should be around somewhere in the vicinity of this checkpoint, but no one knows where exactly. If this all turns out to be a joke, I'll be dealing with everyone responsible personally. Try tracking it down. You probably don't have anything to do right now, but if you so much as dare stand around while looking for it, your neck is gonna be feeling sorry afterward. And only here I do not need to yell, there was a number on that rifle and his soldier fortunately wrote down, well, otherwise it's just that - a criminal is looming around.</text> <!-- fix -->
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Oh, yes, a lousy incident happened here to us, namely one of the soldiers lost his rifle. According to him, it should be somewhere in the territory of this Southern checkpoint, but where exactly - no one knows. If this is someone's joke, then I'll personally deal with him. Listen, can you try and track this shit? You're still just idle, but just try to stick around during the test, I'll choke. And only here I do not need to yell, there was a number on that rifle and his soldier fortunately wrote down, well, otherwise it's just that - a criminal is looming around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done. Here's some pocket money.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Pseudodogs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>Zhurov has asked you to handle a pack of pseudodogs that have been terrorizing local patrols.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_3_about">
		<text>Yes, got some new work for you. Clean out this square of pseudodogs; it's opposite the village, I'll mark it on your PDA. Cranky criminals and other illegals haven't driven them out, and I can't send anyone else, so I need someone to solve the problem with them alone... or they'll be gnawing our patrols at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_3_16_military_trader_task_3_finish">
		<text>Well done, soldier.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_0">
		<text>You specialize in repairs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_1">
		<text>You seem alright, not like a smartass. Yeah, I do repairs here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_2">
		<text>What do you mean by “alright”?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_3">
		<text>I got into a big mess, you know what I'm saying? I ended up in the Zone because of fuck-ups in my youth, and also thanks to this damn beer. My “friends” asked me to be their lookout while they were cleaning out a store, stealing a couple of cigarette boxes and a crate of beer when suddenly, the cops arrived. The guys got in a panic and started thinking of where to hide, and they threw away everything they stole... but I ran slower than everyone else, and long story short: I got caught. I didn't rat those shitheads out, so the only possible outcome was getting the crime pinned on myself, and God knows how I was going to get treated in prison after something like that. I got locked up for four years and left that place a grown man on parole. I thought to myself that I wouldn't get involved in this kind of shit anymore; that I'd find a job and rent some place, get my life in order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_4">
		<text>What else?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_7">
			<text>Well, things haven't moved forward. Got no job, no cash, and the guys I served time with nicknamed me “bro”. The head honcho proposed that I run away to here. He noticed me because I was working my ass off at my work station like Papa Carlo, and I basically had no other choice. I would've joined the stalkers, but I didn't know anyone here; I didn't have enough money for even a hunting rifle, and if the cops would've caught me again, I'd have a fat chance of getting another parole. You know, I don't like all this "prison romanticism". These concepts of theirs are alien to me, and moreover, they're out of place here in the Zone. This isn't the same Zone as the one on the mainland... They could've been even more cruel. I dream of saving up some money and putting this godforsaken shithole in the past.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_8">
			<text>Things happen. What's your name?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_9">
			<text>I go by Baltic. Some thief made fun of my story... and I've had problems with this nickname, but I've managed to keep my dignity. And what kind of beer was in the box on that fateful evening... I don't remember.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_5">
		<text>Of course I sympathize.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_first_meet_6">
		<text>Oh, screw you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_1_text">
		<text>Baltic asked me to get him %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_1_about">
		<text>Bring me any kind of tools, provided that they aren't too shitty. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Bring me any kind of tools, provided that they aren't too shitty. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>You're in luck! I'll jot down that I owe you a slight discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_2_text">
		<text>Baltic asked me to get him %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_2_about">
		<text>Can you help with less rubbishy tools? The whole crib is dying for some.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Can you help with less rubbishy tools? The whole crib is dying for some.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>You really warm my heart, lad. Remember that your discount is being doubled.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_3_text">
		<text>Baltic asked me to get him %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_3_about">
		<text>I'm personally asking you to bring me some thieves' tools, unless, of course, you can't be arsed. Alright?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I'm personally asking you to bring me some thieves' tools, unless, of course, you can't be arsed. Alright?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_mechanic_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you from the bottom of my heart. This will make our guns worthy of real soldiers.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_first_meet_0">
		<text>Are you the local boss?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_first_meet_1">
		<text>Living like a boss, dying like a boss. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_first_meet_2">
		<text>Got any work need carrying out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_first_meet_3">
		<text>That's the right question to ask. I got some work. I haggle some stuff, and you get rich. They call me Afghan, don't ask why. Any other questions?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Creatures at the farm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>Afgan worries that a pack of bloodsuckers, who were recently seen in a nearby farm, are migrating towards the factory; we need to save the camp from possible danger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>Here in the nearby farm our guys saw some bloodsuckers, maybe there are several of them, I don't know. I'm afraid that these scum will make their way to the territory of the factory and worse, dig a lair under it, and then you can kiss everyone goodbye. Such a contingency is appalling, so get them over as soon as possible. Well, can do it or find me someone else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_1_finish">
		<text>Here, take this artifact - my men pinched it from some dumb ass greenhorn.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Mutant slaughter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>It's necessary to clean this place of mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>The beasts torment us, prevent them from ambushing and spreading 'suckers. I give the coordinates, you eliminate, Agreed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_2_finish">
		<text>Well done, you really show concern for the boys. Here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Killing stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>It's necessary to take down this target.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_3_about">
		<text>Many bastards annoy us and totally behave insolently. In general, I give you the coordinates, and you eliminate the target. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_smart_terrain_10_bandit_trader_task_3_finish">
		<text>Good, 'cause I can't sit idle, there's always suckers to deal with. There you go.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Find five dog tails</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>Get Sidorovich five dog tails</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>So, it's like this. I need five dog tails, or to be more precise, one good man - a zoologist. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Now's gonna be really stinky in here. Just be glad I'm not fining you for this stench, grrm.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_4_name">
		<text>Find three cat tails</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_4_text">
		<text>Get Sidorovich three cat tails</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_4_fetch_about">
		<text>Bring me three cat's tails, and I'll give you some money and maybe a good weapon. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_4_fetch_finish">
		<text>Great, come here. Here's your gun and money. That's all.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_5_name">
		<text>Destroy the mutant lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_5_text">
		<text>Sidorovich acts as an intermediary among various stalkers and military men interested in shooting mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_5_about">
		<text>In came a request, asking to clear the area from mutants. You're game right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_5_finish">
		<text>Good, take some loot.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_6_name">
		<text>Excursion to hell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_6_text">
		<text>Sidorovich suggested to follow the rookies until they get experienced.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_6_about">
		<text>Work, eh? Well there is one thing here. You're not a snotty greenhorn, as far as I can judge by your profile in the PDA, grrh. Ugh. In short, some stupid ones piled up to me, asked me to show what, and how it is here in the Zone. Well, I sent them to Fanatic, and this devil cunningly said that they say that basic recruit training among newcomers no longer holds; well, I know that unnecessary deaths are not needed here, it does not restore its reputation, like nerve cells. So I asked them to wait at the village, until I find a suitable candidate. Well, are you leading these jerks around the neighborhood? It is necessary that they do not leave you with empty pockets and with joyful mines on their faces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_6_finish">
		<text>Keep these presents to you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_7_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_7_text">
		<text>Sidorovich offers unpretentious tasks asking to find parts of mutant bodies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_7_about">
		<text>There's always plenty of work to do. Various private organizations or individuals are often interested in body parts of the local fauna, the focus of their activities often fluctuates... Ah-ehm, sometimes I get carried away. In short, I give you a tip, you haul it in. Ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_7_fetch_about">
		<text>There's always plenty of work to do. Various private organizations or individuals are often interested in body parts of the local fauna, the focus of their activities often fluctuates... Ah-ehm, sometimes I get carried away. In short, I give you a tip, you haul it in. Ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_7_fetch_finish">
		<text>Yeah, give me this shit. Here's your loot.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_0">
		<text>I'd like to purchase some extra equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_1">
		<text>What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_2">
			<text>Medical supplies.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_3">
			<text>Provisions.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_4">
			<text>Ammunition.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_5">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_6">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_7">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="euro_level_of_buy_equpments_27">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_1">
		<text>Basic training: deal with the boars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_3">
		<text>Basic training: speak to Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_4">
		<text>Basic training: get to the anomalous zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_5">
		<text>Basic training: speak to Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_9">
		<text>Basic training: retrieve the Jellyfish artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_6">
		<text>Basic training: return to the village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_7">
		<text>Basic training: speak to Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_8">
		<text>Basic training: speak to Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="task_fanat_kmb_1_descr">
		<text>Fanatic, one of the more experienced stalkers in the village, has decided to teach you a thing or two.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start_0">
		<text>Oh, a new face? Would you like to go through some basic training?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start_1">
		<text>Sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start_2">
		<text>No, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start_3">
		<text>Excellent. The biggest threat around here are the mutants. There's a herd of boars by the ravine, and you and I are going there to clear the place out. Try and keep them off me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start1_0">
		<text>Phew. What now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start1_1">
		<text>Well done. See if your knife's strong enough to get a few parts off of them. When you're done, let's head over to the nearest anomalous zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start2_0">
		<text>What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start2_1">
		<text>So, this pit is full of gravitational anomalies. See the artifact over there? It's called a Jellyfish, and Jellyfishes, along with every other artifact, have both positive and negative qualities... We're quite fortunate to have found one. Here, a decent detector you can use to find artifacts. Here are a few pills, in case you manage to catch any radiation. Now, take a few bolts and throw them in front of you to check if the path's safe. Let's go. I'll cover you from here on.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start3_0">
		<text>Hey, I got the artifact!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start3_1">
		<text>Well, well... I can see you'll be an experienced stalker one day. Let's head back to the village, we'll continue your training there.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start4_0">
		<text>That sure was something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_1_start4_1">
		<text>Tired? Heh, don't put anything away yet. The training has just begun.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="fanat_kmb_2_1">
		<text>Basic training: find the stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_2_2">
		<text>Basic training: speak to Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="task_fanat_kmb_2_descr">
		<text>Your next task is to learn how to seek out stashes. A specific stash laid out by Fanatic is located somewhere in the rookie village.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_2_start_0">
		<text>I'm ready, what now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_2_start_1">
		<text>Tell me, what self-respecting stalker has never marauded the secrets of another? The Zone is for everyone here. Those who manage eat, and sometimes, finding a stash is not just an achievement, but a necessity. I've hidden a backpack somewhere in the village. Try and find it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_2_start1_0">
		<text>Found it. Thanks for the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_2_start1_1">
		<text>Huh... I see that with your level of perception, the Zone won't be taking you so easily. Your final lesson is about to start, take some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_1">
		<text>Basic training: clear out the vehicle station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_2">
		<text>Basic training: speak to Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_3">
		<text>Basic training: return to the village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_4">
		<text>Basic training: speak to Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="task_fanat_kmb_3_descr">
		<text>The final task given to you by Fanatic is one of resilience. Together, you will have to eliminate the bandits residing in the vehicle station.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_start_0">
		<text>And what is our final task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_start_1">
		<text>You'll see. As you know, the most insidious enemy of man, strangely enough, remains a man. For a long time, we've kept the vehicle station clear of all the bandits, but they keep coming back. They've been a steady threat, usually numbering from around five to seven. Let's go take care of them.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_start1_0">
		<text>Hah, the two of us against these. We're heroes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_start1_1">
		<text>What you just called heroism here is commonplace for more experienced stalkers. Anyway, let's head back to the village.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_start2_0">
		<text>It's nice that we've got a mentor like you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanat_kmb_3_start2_1">
		<text>Thank you, though I'd say the true leader around here is Wolf. He went on the way to the center of the Zone recently. If you want, we can try and find him later... right now, I need to rest up. Oh, and here's some intel on a route between here and the Garbage, in case you don't already have any. Good job, you are your own stalker now.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_army_0">
		<text>I've found a flight recorder from a helicopter wreckage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_army_1">
		<text>Good find! Well done, soldier.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_csky_0">
		<text>I found a flight recorder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_csky_1">
		<text>Ah, an excellent find! Perhaps we'll finally find the cause of these air raids in the marshes.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_freedom_0">
		<text>I found a flight recorder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_freedom_1">
		<text>Oh, serious? Bring it here. Let's see what these bozos are planning.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_haron_0">
		<text>Brother, I'm on board. I dug up the flight recorder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_haron_1">
		<text>Give it here, let's see what the military is planning this time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_killer_0">
		<text>Here. I found a flight recorder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_killer_1">
		<text>A military one? Great. That's actually a nice gizmo you've got there, I'll take it off your hands for some paper.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_owl_0">
		<text>Are you interested in data from a flight recorder?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_blackbox_mlr_reward_owl_1">
		<text>Wha—of course! Give it here.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="first_meet_to_barman_mil_7_7_0">
		<text>Is this a dining room, or a bar, or something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_meet_to_barman_mil_7_7_1">
		<text>Well, only Duty's got a dining room in the Zone, and nobody's seen it. Welcome, man. You can call me Ganja. I've been in charge of the local grub after they put Chef in the minefield, he-he.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="first_meet_words_mon_teacher">
		<text>Mentor:\nI welcome you, warriors of the new Monolith!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="second_meet_words_mon_teacher">
		<text>Mentor:\nYou are our only hope for the future. Soon, I shall test you individually and observe whether you are worthy amongst our ranks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_meet_words_mon_teacher">
		<text>Mentor:\nYou are all dismissed... except for the fighter to the far left. Come here, I have a task for you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="gar_smart_terrain_5_4_main_dolg_soldier_task_1_name">
		<text>Clear out the parking lot from bandits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_smart_terrain_5_4_main_dolg_soldier_task_1_text">
		<text>The bandits were completely fucked up and settled near Duty's post.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_smart_terrain_5_4_main_dolg_soldier_task_1_about">
		<text>Well, if you can, then you can clean the parking lot from the bandits. These freaks are completely fucked up, once they allow themselves to have such neighbors. Yes, and we would take care of them, but I do not have the extra people. Are you going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_smart_terrain_5_4_main_dolg_soldier_task_1_finish">
		<text>Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="give_main_monolith_mlr_task_5_message">
		<text>Mentor:\nWhen you have time, come visit me. Some trivial business has come up.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="guard1_meet_mlr_0">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_0">
		<text>Can you organize a trip? There's somewhere I need to fly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_1">
		<text>Yeah, I can take you to the Cordon, and Yantar... Wait, who are you, even? I don't offer transport for ordinary soldiers like you. Shoo.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_list_0">
		<text>Where do you fly to, again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_list_1">
		<text>To our checkpoint in the Cordon for five thousand rubles and the base in Yantar for seven thousand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_vert_0">
		<text>I require a pilot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_vert_1">
		<text>Alright, our next flight leaves shortly. Where to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_vert_2">
		<text>To the checkpoint in the Cordon. %c[255,238,153,26][5000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_vert_3">
		<text>To the base in Yantar. %c[255,238,153,26][7000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_agr_mlr_military_vert_4">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_0">
		<text>I need a helicopter. Is this possible to organize?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_1">
		<text>It is, but we won't be using up fuel just for you. You'll have to prove that you're worth the lift.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_list_0">
		<text>To which places do you offer transport?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_list_1">
		<text>To our base in Agroprom for five thousand rubles, and the mobile lab at lake Yantar for ten thousand. We can take you to the gas station in the Darkscape, too, for three thousand, although we have no forces stationed there.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_vert_0">
		<text>I could use a lift.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_vert_1">
		<text>Where to, soldier?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_vert_2">
		<text>To the military base in Agroprom. %c[255,238,153,26][5000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_vert_3">
		<text>To the gas station in the Darkscape. %c[255,238,153,26][3000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_vert_4">
		<text>To the mobile lab in Yantar. %c[255,238,153,26][10000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guid_esc_mlr_military_vert_5">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Destroy mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>Clean up mutant lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>I need your help eliminating a few mutants. Here are the coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_1_finish">
		<text>Good work, here's the money.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Bring %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>Butcher needs %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>Want to help us hunt a few dangerous creatures?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Want to help us hunt various dangerous creatures? You can bring %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent work, hunter.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Kill the pyromaniac burer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>During the night, burers appear out of hot places near anomalous zones. No more should come out again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_3_about">
		<text>This job is dangerous, and must be done before morning. Not far from here, in the deposit of abandoned equipment, some strange burers crawl out and terrorize local stalkers. Many are already afraid to hunt for artifacts at night and work as a whole is difficult, so you will go with a couple of other worried stalkers. Will you help them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_3_finish">
		<text>Well done, here's your share.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_4_name">
		<text>Destroy the civilian zombies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_4_text">
		<text>A pack of zombies came from Yantar to the Garbage, and now they stick to one of the garbage piles; you have to neutralize them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_4_about">
		<text>There is a good job for a hunter. You're a hunter, right? There you go! So, basically, you need to clean one of the garbage heaps from the zombies, I'll send you the coordinates on the PDA. Are you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_4_finish">
		<text>Very nice job indeed, here's what you deserve.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_5_name">
		<text>Escort the Dutyers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_5_text">
		<text>You need to cover some Duty soldiers while they are carrying out measurements of anomalies, on the instructions of scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_5_about">
		<text>It is necessary to lead the Dutiers around the landfill, they have to fulfill some orders by some scientists. They have few people, so someone should cover their backs, are you going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_gar_trader_task_5_finish">
		<text>Thanks man. Here is your reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="hunter_trader_meet_0">
		<text>Are you another bandit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_trader_meet_1">
		<text>Heh, no. I'm not a bandit, and I won't shoot unless you give me a good reason to. I'm a hunter by trade, but I wouldn't put it past anyone in the Zone to mistake me for a bandit. As you can see, I manage a small, cozy, and generally safe bar with the guys here... well, safe for the most part. By the way, name's Butcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_trader_meet_2">
		<text>So you're an artifact hunter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_trader_meet_3">
		<text>Eh, not quite. We don't collect artifacts, we don't adhere to any common views on the Zone, and we certainly don't try to unravel its secrets. Our job is to hunt mutants, and not because they represent, in our opinion, a threat—as Duty seems to wholeheartedly believe—but because of the thrill of the hunt. Many of us were former hunters, both amateurs and professionals outside of the Zone, though many perished, since they weren't prepared for the level of... unpredictability the Zone showed them. Oh, and the trenchcoat; you might understand that such outfits are quite ideal for hunting, and the mobility they offer is certainly useful. We also try to stay out of any armed conflicts between other groups of stalkers, and the coats definitely help us stand out in that regard. On top of that, they generally serve us well as an unofficial uniform of sorts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_trader_meet_4">
		<text>I see. Well, you work at a bar. Do you have anything for sale?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_trader_meet_5">
		<text>I do, though my stock is nothing special. Some stalkers bring mutant parts to me and I sell them. I also have a few other goods, like provisions, medicine, and equipment. And if you're up for hunting mutants for coin, I've got a few jobs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_trader_meet_6">
		<text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_0">
		<text>I'd like to buy intel on a few routes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_1">
		<text>Certainly. Here's what I've got.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_2">
			<text>From the army warehouses to the Radar. %c[255,238,153,26][25000 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_9">
			<text>So, do you have the money for it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_11">
			<text>Yes, here you are.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_3">
			<text>From the Radar to the bunker below it. %c[255,238,153,26][37500 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_12">
			<text>Got the dough?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_13">
			<text>Of course. Here.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_4">
			<text>From the Radar to Pripyat. %c[255,238,153,26][50000 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_14">
			<text>Have you got the cash?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_15">
			<text>Here you go.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_5">
			<text>From central Pripyat to the outskirts. %c[255,238,153,26][100000 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_16">
			<text>I'll need the paper, first.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_17">
			<text>Yeah, here it is.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_6">
			<text>From Pripyat to the Chernobyl NPP. %c[255,238,153,26][150000 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_18">
			<text>Have you got any money with you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_19">
			<text>Yeah, here you go.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_7">
			<text>Between the southern and northern parts of the Chernobyl NPP. %c[255,238,153,26][175000 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_20">
			<text>That's a lotta money. Hope you've got it.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_21">
			<text>You bet. Here.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_10">
		<text>I don't have the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inf_trader_buy_transitions_8">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="inf_trader_sell_stashes_0">
		<text>I'd like to purchase some info on stashes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inf_trader_sell_stashes_1">
		<text>Very well. I'm gonna ask you to give up five thousand. Whatever's in the stash is unknown to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inf_trader_sell_stashes_2">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inf_trader_sell_stashes_3">
		<text>No, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inf_trader_sell_stashes_4">
		<text>Pleasure doing business with you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="information_about_stash_7_4_bandit_trader_0">
		<text>Looking for information on stashes. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_7_4_bandit_trader_1">
		<text>Damn, how'd you know? I got info before others could even find out. Whatever, seven grand and it's all yours.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="information_about_stash_7_4_bandit_trader1_0">
		<text>I'll take it. %c[255,238,153,26][7000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_7_4_bandit_trader1_1">
		<text>Knock yourself out.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="information_about_stash_barah_night_0">
		<text>Hey, do you have information on stashes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_barah_night_1">
		<text>Sure do. I'll part with one for six thousand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="information_about_stash_barah_night1_0">
		<text>Here. %c[255,238,153,26][6000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_barah_night1_1">
		<text>Pleasure doin' business. There ya go.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="information_about_stash_barman_mil_7_7_0">
		<text>Heard you got information on stashes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_barman_mil_7_7_1">
		<text>Oh, of course! We've had all sorts of people come here. I get that you wouldn't want to wander around the Zone forever, so I'll go ahead and tell you where to go for six and a half.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="information_about_stash_barmen_0">
		<text>Any stash information for sale?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_barmen_1">
		<text>Funny you ask. Sometimes, when stalkers around here grab a bottle, they drunkenly slip info on their stashes. Don't know what they keep in there, but what I do know is the value: seven thousand, and it's all yours.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="information_about_stash_barmen1_0">
		<text>Here. %c[255,238,153,26][7000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_barmen1_1">
		<text>Much appreciated.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="information_about_stash_owl_zat_0">
		<text>You got any info on stashes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_owl_zat_1">
		<text>I've got everything and more; if you've got the cash, that is. Got plenty of spare info from various sources. Eight thousand for this one, no less.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="information_about_stash_owl_zat1_0">
		<text>Here. %c[255,238,153,26][8000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="information_about_stash_owl_zat1_1">
		<text>Right. Here are your coordinates.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="item_pda_map_mlr_name">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_map_mlr_descr">
		<text>A personal digital assistant containing possible information on routes between different areas.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="jg_task_name">
		<text>Guide the stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jg_task_text">
		<text>A stalker has tasked you with escorting him safely to a specific location.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medic_heal_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medic_heal_1">
		<text>Any whim for your money. Four thousand rubles.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medic_heal_5">
			<text>I don't have that money.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medic_heal_2">
		<text>You seem to be in order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medic_heal_3">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medic_heal_4">
		<text>That's all, stay out of trouble!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_name">
		<text>Find the %s artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_text">
		<text>Professor Hermann has asked you to find a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_about">
		<text>We could use some sample artifacts, would you like to help us? You will be paid for the task.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>We could use some sample artifacts, would you like to find a %s for us? We will pay you if you manage to return one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you very much.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_2_name">
		<text>Collect bark from mutated trees</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_2_text">
		<text>Hermann has asked me to help with research on the local flora by going to the Red Forest for samples of bark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_2_about">
		<text>We've always got jobs to do. Our MBU deals with the research of flora... for example, some time ago, we asked a stalker to deliver us a few types of plants to study their properties. Now we have taken an interest in the anomalous grove in the Red Forest, which is located in the middle of a Symbiont anomalous zone. We will need samples of bark from from the most twisted and mutated trees that can be found there. Will you help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_task_2_finish">
		<text>Oh, splendid! Give them here. You may have an artifact from us.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_3_text">
		<text>Yar asked you to bring him %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_3_about">
		<text>I've been asking myself a question here, and I'd like to remember the old days and try to upgrade an SVD. Do you think you could provide me with the right tools?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I've been asking myself a question here, and I'd like to remember the old days and try to upgrade an SVD. Do you think you could provide me with the right tools?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you, you've also helped all the other guys. I'll probably increase your discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_4_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_4_text">
		<text>Yar asked you to bring him %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_4_about">
		<text>That previous toolkit was unfortunately not enough for me. To create a masterpiece, I need a third set of tools. Will you help out your uncle Yar again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_4_fetch_about">
		<text>That previous toolkit was unfortunately not enough for me. To create a masterpiece, I need a third set of tools. Will you help out your uncle Yar again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_4_fetch_finish">
		<text>You truly deserve to be my special client: the only stalker with such a large discount. Thank you!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_1_text">
		<text>The tech gangster has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_1_about">
		<text>Yeah, stalkers snatched everything and set up defenses at Yanov, those fuckers. We ain't got shit! Need some tools, man. Get me some, yeah?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Yeah, stalkers snatched everything and set up defenses at Yanov, those fuckers. We ain't got shit! Need some tools, man. Get me some, yeah?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Ah, beautiful! Someone's getting a discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_2_text">
		<text>The tech gangster has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_2_about">
		<text>Listen, I don't wanna bother you too much and all, but could you just bring one more kit here? Need a better kit to improve our shit, you know? It's hard for us here without the right upgrades, heh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Listen, I don't wanna bother you too much and all, but could you just bring one more kit here? Need a better kit to improve our shit, you know? It's hard for us here without the right upgrades, heh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thanks, man. You're a real guy, you know that?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_3_text">
		<text>The tech gangster has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_3_about">
		<text>Hey, buddy, the two other sets of tools you brought us is really helpin', but I need the best o' the best. You know... the shit that'll make 'em go, “oooh, yeeeah...”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Hey, buddy, the two other sets of tools you brought us is really helpin', but I need the best o' the best. You know... the shit that'll make 'em go, “oooh, yeeeah...”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_cont_mech_bandit_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well, fuck me sideways! What a rarity... a real rarity. I'll give you another discount, you deserve it. Thanks, bro.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>Gatekeeper has asked you to get a hold of %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>Our soldiers need some equipment, can you get it for us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Yeah. Our soldiers need %s. Can you get one for us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Good job. Fair reward for fair work.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the %s artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_2_text">
		<text>A mercenary needs a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_2_about">
		<text>Our soldiers could use a few artifacts, it'll be tough getting through Limansk without them. Could you help us find one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Our soldiers could use a few artifacts, it'll be tough getting through Limansk without them. Could you help us find a %s?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_bridge_trader_mlr_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Many thanks. Here, have this.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="killer_task_to_lim_on_the_bridge_1">
		<text>Clear out the chimera lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_task_to_lim_on_the_bridge_2">
		<text>Return to the bridge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_task_to_lim_on_the_bridge_descr">
		<text>The mercenaries have put you up against a formidable challenge in order to cross the bridge.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="loki_st_0">
		<text>Are you in charge here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_1">
		<text>That I am. Name's Loki, right hand of Miklukha at this station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_2">
		<text>An interesting name. It's like the Scandinavian deity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_3">
		<text>That's what it is. It's what they called me in the early days, right around when the Brain Scorcher showed up. Those were crazy times.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_4">
		<text>Could you tell me more about the events after the Scorcher?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_5">
		<text>Sure. When the Scorcher was shut down, my squad launched a campaign towards the north. We went on for some time, going through different places... As the Chernobyl power plant loomed on the horizon, we decided to look for a place to set up camp and found this station while it was empty. The Zone turned to hell, and Duty appeared. The places were strange, there weren't many people, and times were wild with emissions. After calling a truce, we agreed to keep all weapons holstered and knives sheathed in this station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_6">
		<text>And where is Duty now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_7">
		<text>They're not here. Anyone who we didn't manage to shoot down ran off. Not long ago, a stalker by the name of Sasha appeared and helped us out considerably. The man did a lot of good things. The last piece of the puzzle he gave us was the PDA of the man who founded Duty, and according to it, he and his group were former military. Seems like he just cut off comms with the headquarters, which made local stalkers go nuts and left enemy forces confused. We kept a careful balance in this station. And thanks to the help of that stalker, we've been getting all kinds of support... from free stalkers, defectors, sympathizers, you name it. We've basically forced Duty out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_8">
		<text>And where did the stalker go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_9">
		<text>I don't know. Last I heard, he was heading towards Jupiter with some kind of fireteam. He was a good man, hopefully he's alive and kicking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_10">
		<text>What makes the local environment dangerous?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_11">
		<text>It's full of mutants. On top of that, you've got the Monolith. Those bastards have taken over the old depot and lined the perimeter with scouts and machine guns. Other than that, some areas are crawling with zombies, such as the old village of Kopachy west of us, along with the ventilation complex and the Volkhov AA complex. Keep your eyes peeled, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loki_st_12">
		<text>Thanks. I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_0">
		<text>I've got some patches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_1">
		<text>Hand 'em over.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_2">
			<text>Clear Sky, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_3">
			<text>Mercs, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_4">
			<text>Loners, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_5">
			<text>Scientists, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_6">
			<text>Freedom, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_7">
			<text>Duty, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_8">
			<text>Monolith, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_9">
			<text>Military, ten pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_11">
			<text>Clear Sky, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_12">
			<text>Mercs, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_13">
			<text>Loners, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_14">
			<text>Scientists, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_15">
			<text>Freedom, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_16">
			<text>Duty, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_17">
			<text>Monolith, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_18">
			<text>Military, fifty pieces.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_10">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_19">
		<text>Here, have an artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_20">
		<text>Here you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_21">
		<text>Take this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_22">
		<text>Have an artifact!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_23">
		<text>Lucky son of a gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_24">
		<text>Here's some good shit for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_25">
		<text>Not too shabby. An artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_26">
		<text>Lucky boy! Something for the rads.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_27">
		<text>A good artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_28">
		<text>A whole two artifacts! You mother...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_29">
		<text>You're gonna rob me blind like this, ha-ha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_30">
		<text>You're lucky.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_31">
		<text>Aaand you get a kit for crawling around anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_34">
		<text>And I happen to have just the artifact for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_35">
		<text>You're a fortunate son for sure!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_36">
		<text>Damn!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_37">
		<text>Nope. Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_38">
		<text>Not today, hotshot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_39">
		<text>Not a thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_40">
		<text>O-o-o, some great equipment... and it's yours!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_bandit_barman_dar_mlr_41">
		<text>Here's your good stuff.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_0">
		<text>I have a few patches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_1">
		<text>Rad, dude. What've you got?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_2">
			<text>Clear Sky, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_3">
			<text>Freedom, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_4">
			<text>Loners, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_5">
			<text>Scientists, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_6">
			<text>Bandits, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_7">
			<text>Duty, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_8">
			<text>Monolith, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_9">
			<text>Military, ten patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_11">
			<text>Clear Sky, fifty patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_12">
			<text>Freedom, fifty patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_13">
			<text>Loners, fifty patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_14">
			<text>Scientists. Even got fifty.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_15">
			<text>Bandits, fifty patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_16">
			<text>Duty, fifty patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_17">
			<text>Monolith, fifty patches.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_18">
			<text>Military, fifty patches.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_10">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_19">
		<text>Here, take your artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_20">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_21">
		<text>Here, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_22">
		<text>Here's your artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_23">
		<text>Someone got lucky today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_24">
		<text>You get a nice present.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_25">
		<text>Here's a solid artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_26">
		<text>You're a lucky man! Here's something for the radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_27">
		<text>A beautiful artifact. Here you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_28">
		<text>Two artifacts! You're lucky.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_29">
		<text>And here's the jackpot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_30">
		<text>You're a fortunate man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_31">
		<text>An excellent kit for an artifact hunter!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_34">
		<text>A rare and wonderful artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_35">
		<text>Damn, you're lucky!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_36">
		<text>Jackpot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_37">
		<text>Alas, you didn't get anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_38">
		<text>You're quite unlucky.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_39">
		<text>Better luck next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_40">
		<text>Excellent equipment for an excellent marksman.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lottery_barman_mil_7_7_mlr_41">
		<text>Ideal for long-range attacks.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_0">
		<text>I'd like to purchase some extra equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_1">
		<text>What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_2">
			<text>Medical supplies.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_3">
			<text>Provisions.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_4">
			<text>Ammunition.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_5">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_6">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_7">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="low_level_of_buy_equpments_29">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_heal_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_heal_1">
		<text>A thousand rubles, then we'll see what I can do.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_heal_2">
		<text>You're healthy. I doubt that's news for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_doctor_heal_3">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_name_1">
		<text>Rebirth: head into the bunker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_name_2">
		<text>Rebirth: find the control room</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_name_3">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to Griffin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_name_4">
		<text>Rebirth: defend the control room</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_name_5">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to Griffin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_descr">
		<text>The brotherhood wants to seize the Brain Scorcher again.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_name_1">
		<text>Rebirth: meet with the rest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_name_2">
		<text>Rebirth: listen to Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_name_3">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_name_4">
		<text>Rebirth: complete the first test</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_name_5">
		<text>Rebirth: return to Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_descr">
		<text>The very day you have been waiting for has arrived. Pass through the thorns and the Monolith will give you what you have desired.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1_0">
		<text>My brother. Why have you come here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1_1">
		<text>To fulfill my innermost desire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1_2">
		<text>That very desire is what keeps us remaining as a brotherhood. The Monolith has changed. Roughly speaking, the brotherhood is now supported only by a number of enthusiasts. Many former fighters of ours deserted us after the shutdown of the Brain Scorcher. Some have remained simply because they would die outside the brotherhood, but this doesn't mean they will leave sooner or later. And some, like the two of us, have stayed here because we want to build our own personal paradise, and because the technologies of the C-Consciousness allow us to stay here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1_3">
		<text>You mentioned some tests?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1_4">
		<text>All in due time, my brother. Remember that your old life is coming to an end. Over time, the brotherhood has decreased in numbers but increased in fervor. What you will be experiencing here will, to any objectively normal person, seem a true horror... To begin with, I want to observe your willpower. I want you to put an end to the pseudogiant roaming around in this city, without the use of your current equipment. However you manage to accomplish the objective—with your bare hands, with the help of your fellow brothers, or with the help of any weaponry you might find—is of no matter to me. You will reveal to yourself what you are capable of for the sake of achieving your goal and what means you will end up resorting to. Now, be on your way!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1_5">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_2_0">
		<text>The creature is no more. I wonder why we destroy them when they may prove useful against the infidels?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_2_1">
		<text>The power of the C-Consciousness is not enough to keep even a handful of people in check... At this time, mutants have no place amongst our forces. Nonetheless, admirable work. Your possessions are in the blue box behind you. When you're ready for the next challenge, come.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_name_1">
		<text>Rebirth: follow Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_name_2">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_name_3">
		<text>Rebirth: kill the prisoners</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_name_4">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_descr">
		<text>I don't know what will happen this time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_1_0">
		<text>What is my next test?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_1_1">
		<text>Come with me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_2_0">
		<text>You see these men? Mark their fate. Prove your loyalty to our cause... without the shadow of a doubt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_2_1">
		<text>Very well.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_3_0">
		<text>Well done. These men were of Freedom, presumably scouts... We will establish why they were here. Come to me later and we shall decide what to do next.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_3_1">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_name_2">
		<text>Rebirth: go to the Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_name_3">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to the leader of Wings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_descr">
		<text>Mentor has informed you of a squad in need of assistance in the Radar.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1_0">
		<text>What do you require of me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1_1">
		<text>The cossacks have spotted activity of our patrols at the Radar and the edges of Pripyat. I want you to decide on how we should deal with the matter. This will test your mental abilities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1_3">
		<text>We need to commence an attack on their nearest foothold: the Barrier. Their scouting will be hampered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1_4">
		<text>We should set out to find the rest of the reconnaissance group; they may not have moved in pairs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1_5">
		<text>In that case, you should head out at once. We shall we how you will handle this, as you have suggested yourself. We have no other soldiers to send with you, but you may have a few grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1_6">
		<text>You're damn right. But here's the crap that's going on according to their PDA messages. One of our recruits with whom you've done duty earlier must have snatched some five Monolith suits and given them out to saboteurs. We'll deal with the rest of those scouts by ourselves, and you should bust that spy. I've called the recruits over, they must be here, and they also know I have to have a frank talk with each, so you inquire non-intrusively what would I want with them.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_tip">
		<text>Mentor:\nI have some additional work for you to be done, leftmost fighter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_tip_2">
		<text>Mentor:\nDone? Too bad I didn't see his face at that moment, ha-ha! Now, head to the Radar; our reconnaissance team has moved in there. The “Wings” group is waiting for you. See the commander, he will set things into motion with your help.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_name_1">
		<text>Rebirth: clear out the Barrier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_name_2">
		<text>Rebirth: return to the Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_name_3">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to the leader of Wings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_descr">
		<text>Me and my big mouth... They gave me grenades, though.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_tip">
		<text>Cease your attack and return to the Radar, our fighters need help. Speak to Griffin, he runs the Wings detachment.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_name_1">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to the first brother</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_name_2">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to the second brother</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_name_3">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to the third brother</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_name_4">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to the fourth brother</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_name_5">
		<text>Rebirth: share insights with Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_descr">
		<text>Hmm... I wonder why he does not suspect me?</text>
	</string>



	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_0">
		<text>You must be our new companion. Ready to take a walk and behold the former greatness of these places?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_1">
		<text>Are you part of Wings? What are we doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_2">
		<text>That we are; or more precisely, what is left of them. I'm Griffin, and the other guys go by Sparrow and Pegasus. The guy with SVD is Wind. So, listen: we once had a lot of men in this place, and it was something for all the unbelievers to fear... until a stalker sabotaged the local brainwashing facility, so to speak. What started there had to be witnessed: Duty, Freedom, the loners and the military. Our best units took a punch in the gut, and as a result, everyone is dead. But no one has been able to actually control this place. I don't know what happened here, but the area's completely inhabited by all kinds of creatures, including zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_3">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_4">
		<text>We need to head into the bunker under the Brain Scorcher and assess the situation. One of the most important questions we've been asking needs to be answered today: “is it possible to restart the installation?” Are you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_5">
		<text>I'm ready. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_6">
		<text>I'm not ready yet.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_in_bun_tip">
		<text>Griffin:\nWe need to get into the very end of the complex. Careful, who knows what's around here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_in_heart_of_station_tip">
		<text>Griffin:\nHere's the control room... it must've seen better days. Men, let's discuss our next steps.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_2_0">
		<text>What now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_2_1">
		<text>Keep this place protected while I try to figure out what's going on here. We're probably going to have a few visitors.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_0">
		<text>Any results?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_1">
		<text>Currently, nothing. Apparently, someone's disassembled the control panel, but that's just half of it: the cooling system is bust, and I'll have to inspect it further in due time. I doubt that my strength here alone will be enough... but that's nothing you need to worry about at the moment. Listen, have you been assigned to any detachment yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_2">
		<text>Not really. Mentor has ordered us to respond to any incoming messages, and that's all we've got.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_3">
		<text>It seems to me that there is some potential in you. I want to express my gratitude from our whole group and give you our uniform, you deserve it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_4">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_5">
		<text>I'll report back to base. See our supplier in Pripyat; he'll give you our uniform. I believe you'll be in for a pleasant surprise. By the way, fighter... I hope to see you in our ranks in the future.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_4_0">
		<text>I heard that I was supposed to recieve something from Wings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_4_1">
		<text>Here's your Abakan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_4_2">
		<text>Earned their respect? Well done, you'll be heading a long way. Here, have the company's squad uniform.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_n_1">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to Mentor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_n_2">
		<text>Rebirth: assault the laundromat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_n_3">
		<text>Rebirth: speak to Inquisitor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_descr">
		<text>The laundromat needs to be cleared of stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1_0">
		<text>What task have you got, Mentor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1_1">
		<text>You will have to seize a stalker base in the outskirts. Our brothers believe that they will be an interference in our plans and a threat to the brotherhood as a whole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1_2">
		<text>Am I going there on my own?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1_3">
		<text>No, you are not. You will meet with another group of ours serving as assault troops. I give newcomers an opportunity to spend some time with two different groups so that it will be easier for them to determine their own place in the brotherhood. A shame that the third group has been taken out, though... Now, finish your task.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2_0">
		<text>We did well. Mentor has told me that I am at your disposal from now on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2_1">
		<text>You really did help us! At last, Mentor has begun to recruit some stronger men. Keep your equipment in good condition and have some rest. Once you're ready, you may head to our base at the CNPP. We'll continue making preparations here, and I'll contact you once we're done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2_2">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_name_1">
		<text>Head to the sarcophagus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_name_2">
		<text>Find all possible information about the Crystal group</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_name_3">
		<text>Return to Inquisitor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_descr">
		<text>Inquisitor has asked you to learn more about the once-legendary team of defenders of the Monolith and find some information about them.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1_0">
		<text>Mentor mentioned a third detachment that was wiped out. Who did he have in mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1_1">
		<text>The Crystal group. At one point, it was our most powerful force, tasked to protect the C-Consciousness and the sarcophagus along with all the surrounding areas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1_2">
		<text>But what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1_3">
		<text>As you know, some freak or a group of some freaks broke our protective barrier, the Brain Scorcher, and here came the Sunshiners, all sorts of "adventurers," even those bastards. I don't have a lot of information, as we were doing some kind of weird stuff with Preacher at the time... But I digress: the entire group is put under the net, the boys held out until the last, and if they were able to prevent the threat or not, I think you can see it yourself. By the way, you can rummage through the Sarcophagus, see if you can find some information or maybe a weapon of those times. Just don't forget to grab something for removing radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1_4">
		<text>Perhaps I'll go. I'm interested in the fate of the group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1_5">
		<text>Too dangerous for me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_2_0">
		<text>Here, take it. Most of the information is either lost, or I do not know how to read it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_2_1">
		<text>I'll tell Mentor, he'll do it later. That's really a pity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_about_leader_0">
		<text>Why did you decide to stay in the brotherhood? As I understand it, you were first zombified.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_about_leader_1">
		<text>I woke up somewhere near Pripyat, with people I did not know and nothing else, as they did not remember. We were united only by uniform, and still we did not betray each other. My old life was left behind, my brother... it just so happened and nothing can be done to fix it. And I also found myself with my rifle, with twenty-two incisions on it. I don't think I'd be accepted anywhere else.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1_mess_attack">
		<text>Inquisitor:\nWe're commencing the attack. Come on.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_1_name">
		<text>Destroy the bandit's base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_1_text">
		<text>I need to dislodge the bandits from their principal place of stationing in the marshes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_1_about">
		<text>This work must be done before the morning, since all those bastards are in the camp at this time. I've gathered a group of tough guys that can get even with the thugs at their home base in the fishing hamlet, Will you go with them? There's only one thing: don't ditch the guys, if someone dies, I won't forgive you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_1_finish">
		<text>Thank you, this is from me. You are worthy to wear this uniform.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_2_name">
		<text>Eliminate the objective</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_2_text">
		<text>It is necessary to destroy this objective.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_2_about">
		<text>I have tasks to clean up the marshes from all rubbish. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_2_finish">
		<text>Thank you, here's your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_3_name">
		<text>Kill the black chimera</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_3_text">
		<text>It is necessary to save the hidden base of the Clear Sky from imminent danger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_3_about">
		<text>In short, the situation is dire. Near the tower in the southwest of the swamps settled some creature that attacks mostly at night. You have to go there now, and kill it; if you want to, of course...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mar_smart_terrain_base_stalker_leader_marsh_task_3_finish">
		<text>Thank you from the bottom of my heart, brother.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_start_0">
		<text>Salutations, fellow brother. My duty is to provide technical support for our brethren in the area.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_1_text">
		<text>The technician at the depot has asked you to bring %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_1_about">
		<text>Our base was set up here recently, but the lack of tools for our brothers has been acute. Will you find a set of basic tools for the benefit of the brotherhood? It would be invaluable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Our base was set up here recently, but the lack of tools for our brothers has been acute. Will you find a set of basic tools for the benefit of the brotherhood? It would be invaluable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent. This will help us gain a foothold and grow in strength... I believe you deserve a discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_2_text">
		<text>The technician at the depot has asked you to bring %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_2_about">
		<text>Fighting has shown that our weapons are marginally inferior to those of the infidels, among which exist capable technicians. I require tools for fine work to save our brothers from such inferiorities. Will you help, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Fighting has shown that our weapons are marginally inferior to those of the infidels, among which exist capable technicians. I require tools for fine work to save our brothers from such inferiorities. Will you help, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Good work. The equipment supplied to our brothers will prove to be dominant over all others in the area... You will be getting an additional reduction in fees.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_3_text">
		<text>The technician at the depot has asked you to bring %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_3_about">
		<text>We will be able to surpass them all, brother! To accomplish that, I require tools for calibrating our weapons. Please, locate a set and bring it to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>We will be able to surpass them all, brother! To accomplish that, I require tools for calibrating our weapons. Please, locate a set and bring it to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_jup_depo_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>It is settled. With these recent discoveries, we shall conquer the surrounding areas. From here on out, my services for you will be provided to the best of my capability.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_start_0">
		<text>Greetings, brother. I carry out Its will by preserving the equipment of our brotherhood.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_1_text">
		<text>The technician in the Yubileiny service center has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_1_about">
		<text>I need your help, brother. I require tools for our equipment so that our brethren may spread the word of the Monolith more effectively.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I need your help, brother. I require tools for our equipment so that our brethren may spread the word of the Monolith more effectively.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent work, brother. Everything we gain from future improvements will go to our charity, and your contribution will grant you a small discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_2_text">
		<text>The technician in the Yubileiny service center has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_2_about">
		<text>The set of tools you located previously does not suffice. Finer tools are required for more extensive work so that our brethren may continue spreading Its will. Will you serve our cause once again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>The set of tools you located previously does not suffice. Finer tools are required for more extensive work so that our brethren may continue spreading Its will. Will you serve our cause once again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent work, brother. Everything we gain from future improvements will go to our charity, and your contribution will grant you an additional discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_3_text">
		<text>The technician in the Yubileiny service center asked me to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_3_about">
		<text>The last set of tools that you brought here was... adequate, but why stop at what has been achieved when we can attain something even better? What we need are the best tools in the Zone. I ask of you to serve Its will one last time, my brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>The last set of tools that you brought here was... adequate, but why stop at what has been achieved when we can attain something even better? What we need are the best tools in the Zone. I ask of you to serve Its will one last time, my brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechanic_monolith_kbo_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Outstanding work, brother. Rest assured, I will mention your contribution to our brothers... and I promise to provide any assistance within my ability.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_dasc_traveler_mlr_0">
		<text>Hey, are you waiting for someone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_dasc_traveler_mlr_1">
		<text>Oh, hey! Wouldn't happen to need the services of a humble guide, would you? I can take you to the rookie village in the Cordon, the... “hidden” base in the Great Swamps, and the flea market in the Garbage.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_dasc_traveler_mlr_list_0">
		<text>Remind me, where do your routes lead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_dasc_traveler_mlr_list_1">
		<text>One thousand rubles will lead you to the rookie village in the Cordon. For twenty-five hundred, I can get you to the hidden base in the Great Swamp or the flea market in the Garbage.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_ds_killer_guide_main_base_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ds_killer_guide_main_base_1">
		<text>I'm a guide, they call me Leopard. As you can see, this place is surrounded by all sorts of danger, but we've got an underground sewer network that not many know of, with the fortunate exception of yours truly. We can get you out of the city to one of two bases: the waste processing station in Zaton, or our outpost by the bridge in the Red Forest.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_ds_killer_guide_main_base_list_0">
		<text>Remind me, where do your routes lead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ds_killer_guide_main_base_list_1">
		<text>You don't have too many options: there's the waste processing station in southern Zaton and our outpost by the bridge in the Red Forest. Eight thousand and twenty-five thousand, respectively.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_bar_0">
		<text>Are you a guide?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_bar_1">
		<text>Yep, Navigator's the name. Can take you to a few places for a modest fee. Rookies are my customers most of the time, but I can lead any experienced stalker as well. No shame in that. I'll break it down: you pay, I get you wherever you want to go, and I return here. I can take you to one of six locations: Yantar, the Great Swamps, the army warehouses, the Garbage, the Cordon, and Jupiter.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_bar_list_0">
		<text>Sorry, where can you escort me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_bar_list_1">
		<text>To the the Garbage for seven hundred, the army warehouses for one thousand, the Rookie Village in the Cordon for three thousand, Yantar for thirty-five hundred, Yanov station in Jupiter for six thousand, and the Great Swamps, also for six thousand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_dv_bandit_0">
		<text>Who have we got here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_dv_bandit_1">
		<text>You blind or something? I'm the local guide here. If you need my help, I can drop you at quite a few places, such as our outpost in the Truck Cemetery or our warehouse in Jupiter. It'll cost ya, though...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_list_0">
		<text>Remind me which paths you take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_list_1">
		<text>The Garbage; twenty-five hundred, the truck cemetery; twenty-five hundred, the Cordon; four thousand, and Jupiter, eight thousand. All our territory, ha-ha!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_jup_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_jup_1">
		<text>Nice to meet you, bro. Name's Garry, and I'm a guide. Usually roam around the center of the Zone. I can take you to the Bar, Pripyat and its outskirts, the Red Forest, Zaton, and the Jupiter Underground.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_jup_list_0">
		<text>Forgot. Where can you lead me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_jup_list_1">
		<text>I can offer trips to the Bar for six thousand rubles, Pripyat for three thousand and its outskirts for four thousand, the Red Forest for twenty-five hundred, the Skadovsk in Zaton for two thousand, and the Jupiter Underground for fifteen hundred.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_jupdepo_mon_0">
		<text>To which places may I travel to, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_jupdepo_mon_1">
		<text>There are several. We have routes that lead to the Red Forest, the outskirts, and central Pripyat itself. I cannot take you to any of these locations myself, but you may go with your brothers. I don't believe you'll find that a problem.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_jupdepo_mon_list_0">
		<text>Where can the guides take me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_jupdepo_mon_list_1">
		<text>To the Red Forest for six thousand rubles, the outskirts for two thousand, and Pripyat for one thousand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_0">
		<text>Is there anywhere I may travel, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_1">
		<text>Certainly. I may ask our brothers to lead you in exchange for a donation to the brotherhood. You may be taken to the outskirts of Pripyat east of here, to Jupiter to the west, and to the Red Forest located to the southwest.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_list_0">
		<text>To which places may I travel to, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_list_1">
		<text>There are ways to the outskirts east of here and Jupiter to the west. Both will cost you one thousand rubles.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_marsh_csky_0">
		<text>Hey, why are you standing there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_marsh_csky_1">
		<text>Well, there's no time for me to sit around; gotta be in constant sight, considering I'm the local guide. If you've got the money, there are a few places in the Swamps I can guide you to: the observation post, the water pump station, or the machine yard. I can also take a route to the rookie village in the Cordon. If you've gone completely bonkers, Agroprom is another option, and if you're in a good mood, there's also the Bar!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_marsh_csky_list_0">
		<text>Can you name your routes again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_marsh_csky_list_1">
		<text>These are the routes I take: the observation outpost for three hundred rubles, the pump station and the old church both for five hundred, the machine yard for eight hundred, the rookie village in the Cordon for fifteen hundred, Agroprom for two thousand, and the Bar for four thousand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_pri_stalker_list_0">
		<text>Where do you travel to again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_pri_stalker_list_1">
		<text>To the Nuclear Power Plant for twelve thousand rubles, Pripyat for three thousand, Yanov station in Jupiter for four thousand, the Radar for eight thousand, the Jupiter Underground for just one thousand, and Zaton, via Garry, for four thousand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_prikbo_mon_0">
		<text>To which places may I travel to, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_prikbo_mon_1">
		<text>For your money, the brothers may be your guides. You may be escorted to Jupiter and central Pripyat; come to us at any time for our services.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_prikbo_mon_list_0">
		<text>Where can the guides take me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_prikbo_mon_list_1">
		<text>To Jupiter for two thousand rubles. They may also guide you to Pripyat for a mere sum of one thousand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_red_forest_mon_0">
		<text>To which places may I travel to, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_red_forest_mon_1">
		<text>I can not escort you personally, but our brothers may show you where to go, for a fee. We've got positions set up in the Red Forest, Jupiter and Pripyat. We would be glad to assist you at any time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_red_forest_mon_list_0">
		<text>Where can the guides take me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_red_forest_mon_list_1">
		<text>To the outskirts of Pripyat for five thousand rubles, Jupiter for six thousand, and central Pripyat for five thousand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_guid_zat_0">
		<text>You look like an interesting character.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_zat_1">
		<text>Pathfinder Pilot at your service. There aren't many places I can take you, but it'll definitely be much faster and safer than traveling alone. I offer services to Pripyat and its outskirts via fellow guide Garry, though I can take you to Jupiter myself.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_guid_zat_list_0">
		<text>Give me your travel list again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guid_zat_list_1">
		<text>I can talk to Garry about guiding you to Pripyat for four thousand, as well as the outskirts for five thousand. I can lead you to Yanov station in Jupiter by myself for two thousand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_povar_army_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_povar_army_1">
		<text>The local cook, I guess. I can't even make something simple like an omelet, but somehow, that's the assigned role I received in the army. I'm not a real soldier, so they put me here in Yantar. Anyway, they call me Spirit. Usually I take to drinking because it's so depressing around here. If that ain't enough, this is the main base of the scientists, meaning my officers come here for inspections from time to time, and they don't really like me drinking... Last time they were here, they poured my vodka out right before my eyes. Bastards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_povar_army_2">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_povar_army_3">
		<text>Well, I know that getting ammo around here is rough, especially when Sakharov doesn't even sell any. I can hook you up with some stuff, but only Soviet-era shit, unfortunately. I've also got a few outfits; everything I've managed to steal is mine. What do you say about trading with me for a few bottles of Cossacks? For five bottles, I can offer you six mags of 9x18, or three mags of 5.45. For ten bottles, I can share six mags of 5.45, two mags of 7.62, or five packs of 12x70 buckshot rounds. For fifteen bottles and seven thousand rubles, I can get you five box mags for the PKP, and for twenty bottles, I'll fetch you an entire Berill suit from the bins. Don't think I'm a scoundrel... it's not that bad, the lion's share goes to the guys. They've left me their equipment in a stash. I'll leave any goods between the hangars outside the bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_povar_army_4">
		<text>I'll consider it. Thank you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="meet_zaton_killer_guide_station_0">
		<text>Greetings, what do you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_zaton_killer_guide_station_1">
		<text>I could ask you a reasonable question in return: what's your damn business? But that's not what you wanna hear, is it? I work as a trader and a guide, and I know routes to our head base in the Dead City, along with our main outpost in Zaton.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="meet_zaton_killer_guide_station_list_0">
		<text>Could you remind me where your routes lead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_zaton_killer_guide_station_list_1">
		<text>Two routes, pal. Dead City for eight grand, and the Red Forest for two and a half.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>Griffin has asked you to collect %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>There are just too many of those goddamn fanatics. Could you wipe them out? I've got a little something that could help you out in future hunts. It's yours if you bring me twenty-five of their patches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>There are just too many of those goddamn fanatics. Could you wipe them out? I've got a little something that could help you out in future hunts. It's yours if you bring me twenty-five of their patches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thanks, stalker. Here's that little toy I promised you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_2_name">
		<text>Find a Soul artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_2_text">
		<text>Griffin has asked you to locate and return a Soul artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>There's no doctor here, and we've got to survive somehow. Ordinary medical equipment just isn't enough for us, and not many of the men know how to use it properly. It's hard enough taking care of everyone around here. So, I want to ask for your help. I've heard about an artifact called the Soul, said to have an ability to heal the wounds of people. Could you find one and bring it here for us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>You actually found one? I can't believe it... Thank you, stalker! This will help the others. And don't go without your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_3_name">
		<text>Clean out the grocery store</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_3_text">
		<text>The mercenaries want the dogs at the nearest grocery store taken care of.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_3_about">
		<text>We've got another problem. There are dogs who have settled down at the grocery store, and that's no good for us. They've been barking at us nonstop, and that draws unwanted attention. I'd appreciate it if you could clear them out from that place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_tesak_mlr_task_3_finish">
		<text>Thank you, great work. Here's some money for your trouble.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="merc_pri_a16_trader_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_trader_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>Toolkit needed %s for the mercs squad, stuck in Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_trader_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>Yes, I have a list of the primary things that I need. In particular, ammunition, repair kits and medicines. Can you help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_trader_mlr_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I have a list of the top things I need. In particular, ammunition, repair kits and medicines. Now I need %s. Can you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_pri_a16_trader_mlr_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Climb on the roof of the water tower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_name_wait">
		<text>Wait an hour for it to start</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_name_end">
		<text>Go back to Ganja</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>Ganja asked you to climb to the roof of the water tower in order to download some entertainment data for Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>Oh, dude, glad you asked... Listen, as you know, we've got an internet network around these parts, but its range is freaking terrible. Usually, we have someone climb the water tower in the bloodsucker's village and download all the good stuff for the guys, 'cause the speed there is pretty great. This one time, you could be the one going up there. I've already opened the right program on this laptop, you just have to download the stuff for us. Will you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_finish">
		<text>Thanks, brother! If you enjoyed it, you can come back later. Getting to the top of that tower is basically a hobby of ours, heh.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_notebook">
		<text>Freedom laptop</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_barman_mlr_task_1_notebook_descr">
		<text>A laptop shared among members of Freedom, used for recreational purposes. There are several copies of social network pages, music, various video games, movies ranging from art films to more recent blockbusters, photos of carriers of this information; and of course, videos, pictures, and drawings of pornographic nature.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_meet_0">
		<text>Hey, what's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_meet_1">
		<text>Nothing much, just lazing around. I'm Leshiy, local guide and scout.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_meet_2">
		<text>And how's the local intelligence? I presume you've visited many places?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_meet_3">
		<text>Indeed. I've even been in an anomaly. Entered a spatial bubble with my squad back when I was a mercenary. It's a long story. Anyway, if you need to travel somewhere, you can talk to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_meet_4">
		<text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_list_0">
		<text>So where can you lead me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_list_1">
		<text>On my list is Yanov for six grand, the Cordon village for forty-five hundred, and Yantar for five grand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_0">
		<text>Lead me somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_1">
		<text>Sure, man. Where to?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_2">
			<text>To Yanov. %c[255,238,153,26][6000 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_5">
			<text>Need the money first, pal.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_8">
			<text>Here, all yours.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_3">
			<text>To the Cordon. %c[255,238,153,26][4500 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_6">
			<text>Got the money?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_9">
			<text>Here, keep it.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_4">
			<text>To Yantar. %c[255,238,153,26][5000 RU]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_7">
			<text>Did you bring the money?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_10">
			<text>Of course. Here.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_11">
		<text>Forgot it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_guid_go_12">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mil_freedom_medic_heal_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_medic_heal_1">
		<text>Huh? Right, come on over. My price is two thousand, hope you've got that much.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="mil_freedom_medic_heal_5">
			<text>Nope, ain't got nothing.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="mil_freedom_medic_heal_2">
		<text>Dude, you're healthier than my buddy Vitka. And he's a drug addict!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_medic_heal_3">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_medic_heal_4">
		<text>This might sting a bit. Right, you stay healthy now.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_6_name">
		<text>Defeat the Dutyers in the village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_6_text">
		<text>Mikluha knows how to discourage once and for all the Dutiers from going to the village near the path to Rostok, and in this I might be useful to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_6_about">
		<text>Oh fighter, hello! There's a delicate matter for us to handle. Do you know that the Dutiers have simply monotonously been trying to consolidate themselves in one of the villages on the way to Rostok for years? No? Basically, I know how to discourage their desire to come there once and for all and for this we must show them our tactics, so to speak. Some fresh forces just arrived there, I really do not know why they are there, but if we defeat them with half their number, imagine how much pressure it will produce? Well, are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_6_finish">
		<text>Wonderful! Well done fighter, take this rifle. And don't even have to straighten it, the barrel is good, certainly not for open military spaces, but in some places it sure must come in handy, he he.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_7_name">
		<text>Find four detectors, Veles-class</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_7_text">
		<text>Miklukha complained that the level of technical support of the group leaves much to be desired, you need to find four Veles detectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_7_about">
		<text>Oh, you're just in time; my men rarely drop by to work, but alas, I can't blame them for that. If you do not know, in the old years during Lukash, Cook and other cockeyed personalities, the level of material support of our group was negligible and from the "descendants" we got almost nothing. Now, I want to resume the tradition of gathering artifacts so to speak on people's needs, but we possess only a couple of detectors, Veles-class, and one of them was broken. I need four of these detectors, I'll pay five grands for each. Well, are you in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_7_fetch_about">
		<text>Oh, you're just in time; my men rarely drop by to work, but alas, I can't blame them for that. If you do not know, in the old years during Lukash, Cook and other cockeyed personalities, the level of material support of our group was negligible and from the "descendants" we got almost nothing. Now, I want to resume the tradition of gathering artifacts so to speak on people's needs, but we possess only a couple of detectors, Veles-class, and one of them was broken. I need four of these detectors, I'll pay five grands for each. Well, are you in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_smart_terrain_7_7_freedom_leader_stalker_task_7_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you, take your money.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mlr_inventory_box_no_use">
		<text>Unremarkable chimney top</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mlr_strelok_item_01">
		<text>Worn notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mlr_strelok_item_01_desc">
		<text>A notebook, likely owned by Strelok himself. It describes in detail how to get into an underground complex by the name of X18.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mlr_transiver_item">
		<text>Transceiver</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mlr_transiver_item_desc">
		<text>An old model of an army transmitter, serves to communicate and transmit information.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mon_blue_box_mlr_no_use">
		<text>This box is locked.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="monolith_outfit_wings_name">
		<text>Wings of the Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_outfit_wings_description">
		<text>A variant of the standard Monolith suit, providing a lighter load and additional comfort unlike its predecessor. Tailored to the new realities of the brotherhood, it offers enhanced protection from radiation and psi-emissions.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg_0">
		<text>How are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg_1">
		<text>A bit uneasy, man, but that's normal when you're in new places. I heard Mentor's calling on us for some reason?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg_2">
		<text>So I've heard. What do you think about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg_3">
		<text>I'm afraid of failing my very first test. Is it a joke to get into the Zone? I think he's worrying about me bringing the wrong artifact, or not getting any artifact at all... Gods. Gonna need some time to myself, buddy.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg_0">
		<text>Hey. Have you heard that Mentor's calling us one by one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg_1">
		<text>Yeah, I've heard, but what's the use? It means he's gonna need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg_2">
		<text>How do you feel about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg_3">
		<text>Not in the mood to crack into a rant. I'm preparing for my third test.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg_0">
		<text>Everyone else here seems rather reclusive, brother. Would you be interested in conversing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg_1">
		<text>Why not? And how are you faring?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg_2">
		<text>Everything is fine. I'm under the wing of the people who will be fulfilling my dream in the end.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg_3">
		<text>And what is your dream?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg_4">
		<text>If I'm going to be chatting about my dream in every one of my encounters, it becomes a purpose and not a dream. What are you here for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg_5">
		<text>I'm here mostly for the sake of money. What else can an honest stalker dream of? Anyway, you are certainly a good man, but I'd like to rest from conversations. I've heard so many things today...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg_0">
		<text>Hello. How are you feeling under the Monolith?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg_1">
		<text>You know, I was an experienced walker and I've had such a children's dream in the Monolith. I've accomplished half of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg_2">
		<text>And what are you waiting for from the brotherhood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg_3">
		<text>I just want to give myself to the Monolith without any second thoughts, you understand? Nobody is waiting for me in the Great Land. Now, I need to sort out the crap from the second test. Bye, brother.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_0">
		<text>I may have found a spy. I can bring him and show you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_1">
		<text>Go ahead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_2">
		<text>I believe this is the first brother I've spoken to. Seems like a crazy type.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_3">
		<text>This might be the second brother I've had any conversation with. He's quite reclusive, might be hiding something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_4">
		<text>Seems to be the third brother I've met. Too sociable. He came here for the sake of money and couldn't come up with any better excuse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_5">
		<text>Definitely the fourth brother I've had words with. He's strange, too correct. Wanted to appease.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_6">
		<text>Man, you're a terrible investigator. Did you think I was gonna let you go just for that? Our guys have followed you and already taken care of the 'traitor'. You haven't lived up to my hopes, nor have you earned any reward whatsoever. Head to the Radar and meet up with Wings, they could use some assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg_7">
		<text>Safe to say you did a great job. I've sent a bunch of my guys with you, because I can't leave such a serious matter on your shoulders alone. Don't worry, they've already taken care of the messenger. Griffin sent a message, some shit's gone down at the Radar. Head there and meet up with Wings, they're gonna need your help. And take this shotgun, you've earned it. It'll come in handy.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="noah_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Man, what the hell were you shooting for? You almost killed me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="noah_start_dialog_1">
		<text>And what are you here for? No bullshitting. Don't waste my time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="noah_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Okay, easy. Just passing by. Need any help? Can you answer a few questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="noah_start_dialog_3">
		<text>I'll answer, but don't screw around.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="noah_start_dialog1_0">
		<text>I have a couple of questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="noah_start_dialog1_1">
		<text>Yeah? Spill it.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_2">
			<text>Where did you get this dog?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_7">
			<text>That's Lassie. A sweet little bitch... If not for her, I'd have been devoured in my sleep long ago. Cursed mutants... I hate them! Soon as you close your eyes, they start reaching for you with their nasty claws, fangs and feelers...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_8">
			<text>I see.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_9">
			<text>And those puppies; where do they come from if she's next to you all the time? Heh.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_3">
			<text>Why do you live on this garbage can?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_10">
			<text>It's the Ark! Remember that... you will, if you want to live! When a Wave starts, stay close. Here you'll have a chance to survive. No mutant will ever break in here.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_11">
			<text>What “Wave”? What are you talking about?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_12">
			<text>The creatures are watching me day and night. You do not understand... those snorks from the southern plateau have followed me right up to the Ark! I'm an experienced hunter and I know that they would not have chased the victim for so damn long. Something isn't clear... they must have a collective mind of sorts. My thoughts have been confirmed by the recent attacks on the barge by those horrors.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_13">
			<text>I guess anything can happen in the Zone, but if your estimates are correct, we're in some deep trouble.</text>
		</string>

		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_4">
			<text>Why do you not trust people?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="noah_start_dialog1_14">
			<text>Because I've been through too much.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="noah_start_dialog1_5">
		<text>I think I'll go.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="path_unknown">
		<text>This path is unknown</text>
	</string>
	<string id="path_unlocked">
		<text>New path unlocked:</text>
	</string>



	<string id="pay_or_go_away_gar_oupost_talk_0">
		<text>So, stalker. To go further, you need to pay five thousand, otherwise we'll drop you. Our kindness will last exactly one hour. Will you pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pay_or_go_away_gar_oupost_talk_1">
		<text>Here, corrupt officer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pay_or_go_away_gar_oupost_talk_2">
		<text>Not yet.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="pole_factory_doc_1">
		<text>Security chief's records</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_1_desc">
		<text>Absolutely useless records, which contain the names and pictures of all employees, who were repeatedly observed at the beginning and end of the work day. However, the dates indicate that this complex was used after the first blowout.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pole_factory_doc_2">
		<text>Production Information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_2_desc">
		<text>There's no interesting info in this one too, nothing extraordinary happened here, apparently the employees of this plant were mainly engaged in energy issues.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pole_factory_doc_3">
		<text>Accounting book</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_3_desc">
		<text>A book containing basic information on key individuals and the material structure of the new enterprise. The lion's share of funds is earmarked, received from the state. No unusual content is located within, as it doesn't deal the matter of armaments.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pole_factory_doc_4">
		<text>PDA of a dead stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_4_desc">
		<text>The battery's dead, but a note was attached under the cover, apparently duplicating the last message, just for this case: "Stalker, if you are reading this - better leave from here for good. If you came here hoping to profit, then know that there is nothing, although by the time of the discovery of this PDA, I think you understood everything yourself, I do not know if we will survive this night, I feel extremely disgusted. As if something reads my thoughts and scoffs at us. We can, terribly get tired from fatigue, we make a small stop here; I'll hide the PDA just in case, so that the mutants do not tear it up."</text>
	</string>



	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_1_name">
		<text>Destroy the enemy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_1_text">
		<text>A key position in the Zone must be liberated.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_1_about">
		<text>You know what I love the most? Surprise attacks. Unleash your rage against our opponents and you will be rewarded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_1_finish">
		<text>Excellent. Have your due.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_2_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_2_text">
		<text>Mentor has asked you to bring %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_2_about">
		<text>It's time to make those bastards pay. Tear off their patches and bring them to me, and I'll give you a bonus.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>It's time to make thos bastards pay. Bring me %s and I'll give you a bonus.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Outstanding, brother. This is for you, from the Monolith.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_3_name">
		<text>Fend off the zombie assault</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_3_text">
		<text>Zombies are entering the area from the Radar again. You need to clear them away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_3_about">
		<text>Zombies are coming in from Radar. We need to face them at the south side of the city rid the area of them; any soldiers you bring with you will surely be of assistance. Will you be going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_teacher_mlr_task_3_finish">
		<text>Well done. Have a reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="remember_dyx_barter_0">
		<text>Remind me, what do you have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="remember_dyx_barter_1">
		<text>This is what I've got: for five bottles, I can get you six mags of 9x18, or three mags of 5.45. For ten bottles, I can get you either six 5.45 mags, two mags of 7.62, or five packs of 12x70 buckshot. For fifteen bottles and a decent sum of seven thousand rubles, I can get you five box mags for the PKP, and for twenty bottles... I'll get you an entire Berill.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="request_go_to_nimble_0">
		<text>Excuse me, Garik. I need to pass through.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="request_to_no_go_nimble_bar_0">
		<text>Is there something in that room?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="request_to_no_go_nimble_bar_1">
		<text>Not something, someone. That guy in there is a veteran, and he can get anyone any kind of equipment, even unique stuff. He isn't accepting any visitors, though; gotta make sure you're trusted for that. Gonna need a name around here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="request_to_no_go_nimble_bar_1_0">
		<text>So, can I meet this man now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="request_to_no_go_nimble_bar_1_1">
		<text>Hm... Alright. I'll let Garik know. The name of the guy is Nimble. Head straight and then right along the corridor.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="request_to_no_go_nimble_bar_2_0">
		<text>Is there something in that room?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="request_to_no_go_nimble_bar_2_1">
		<text>Not something, someone. That guy in there is a veteran, and he can get anyone any kind of equipment; even unique stuff. If you want to see him, go ahead. I trust you. You can tell Garik you need to pass. Just head straight and then right down the corridor - his name is Nimble.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="request_to_no_trade_dialog_0">
		<text>Can I buy extra equipment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="request_to_no_trade_dialog_1">
		<text>That's certainly possible, but nobody right now will want to sell you anything extra. You'll have to gain some trust and experience, and after that you can buy equipment wholesale.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="request_to_no_trade_dialog_monolith_0">
		<text>May I purchase additional equipment from you, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="request_to_no_trade_dialog_monolith_1">
		<text>You may, although not at this point in time. First, I must see to it that you continue to carry the will of the Monolith towards the infidel masses. We may talk about this transaction when you gain more experience.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_name">
		<text>Find the rookie's weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_text">
		<text>A stalker nicknamed Fatty asked to retrieve for him his own weapon, which he dropped during a careless investigation of the abnormal substation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_0">
		<text>What is it you wanted to offer me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1">
		<text>The whole factory that's in the vicinity. You know, this place here certainly isn't the nicest, but nobody here's complaining, as, frankly, the artifacts here aren't that common, and it is dangerous here for the outskirts of the Zone. But recently, rumors about the local factory started spreading, about some kind of weapon being created by the government in this place following the first Chernobyl disaster. You know the stories about the Marked One and Strelok, both almost completely having looted all of the underground complexes? There's hope for beginners here; to get something valuable and expensive without having to travel to the center of the Zone. So they've pushed forward, and I'm one of them. Bandits have followed, because there are many stalkers out here, and there's a lot of loot to grab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_2">
		<text>So you want me come along and look for intelligence?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_3">
		<text>Yep. But you gotta help me with something, first. There's no way to survive around here without weaponry. I used to have a good shotgun... Grabbed it before I came here, but I went to the local substation not far from here, and there was a strange anomaly there... I got careless and got zapped! Fortunately, I wasn't hurt, but I freaked out and threw the weapon, then ran away here. Laugh all you want, but when you escape death narrowly... So, will you bring it to me? That's... if you want to help me with something else afterwards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_4">
		<text>Alright, I'll go get your shotgun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_5">
		<text>Not now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_0">
		<text>Here's your gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_1">
		<text>Thanks. Take this Flash as a token of gratitude; I managed to find it in that anomaly. Prepare yourself carefully... when night comes, we'll head over to the factory.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_from_factory_0">
		<text>I've already been at the factory, actually.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_from_factory_1">
		<text>Oh, don't mess around. Do you have any evidence?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_from_factory_2">
		<text>Yeah. Here's something I found there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_from_factory_3">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_from_factory_4">
		<text>And here I was hoping for something better... Thank you for clearing up the situation, it seemed dangerous there. I have nothing to repay you with... except for my shotgun. I don't need it anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_dlg_1_from_factory_5">
		<text>Don't bother me.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name">
		<text>Explore the complex</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_1">
		<text>Return</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_2">
		<text>Kill the controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_3">
		<text>Speak to Fatty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_3_0">
		<text>Return to the village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_text">
		<text>Tonight, Fatty is going with you to investigate the mysteries of the factory complex. Finishing the search before morning would be important.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_0">
		<text>Well, I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_1">
		<text>Great, I just can't wait to discover all the secrets of this place. But be alert, I hope we will manage without incidents.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_2_0">
		<text>Hmm...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_2_1">
		<text>It's always like this, you know? I almost died again and you saved me... Again. But there was nothing there... Well, here's your moral, man: rely only on objective, diversified information, draw the damn parallels and don't look at the world through rose-tinted glasses. Ugh, fuck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_2_2">
		<text>What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_2_3">
		<text>Will you give me the documents? I'll keep them as a souvenir, after the attacks. I have nothing to repay you, but I can become your good friend if you want to wander with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_2_4">
		<text>Yes, here, they are useless to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_dlg_2_5">
		<text>Are you kidding me or something? I risked my life because of you, three damn times. It's better if I sell them to Barman.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_questions_0">
		<text>Got any thoughts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_questions_1">
		<text>Let's check out that PDA, there might be something useful on it. I don't think they've touched it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_questions_2">
		<text>I think we should check out the three-story administrative building in the middle of the complex, along with the workshops.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_questions_3">
		<text>Right? Let's scout it, maybe the stalkers left behind some traces while they were still kicking. I just don't wanna stay around here for too long... got a bad feeling about this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_questions_4">
		<text>None at the moment.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_name">
		<text>Find the heckler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_name_1">
		<text>Kill Alpha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_text">
		<text>Someone has been annoying Fatty, who now wants this person gotten rid of.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_0">
		<text>What else do you need help with?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_1">
		<text>A while ago, some dummy from the village came by and made fun of my looks. Could you pay him a little visit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_2">
		<text>How am I going to take him out? If I'm spotted, I'm done for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_3">
		<text>They won't know, trust me. I heard he's looking for some help with raiding the area. Just find him and tell him you're a stalker interested in some work, then lead him to a few bandits or mutants. They'll turn him into Swiss cheese. You in? I can't offer you anything personally, but anything on his corpse will be yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_4">
		<text>Let's do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_5">
		<text>Don't you find that a bit excessive? No, thanks.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_1_0">
		<text>Hey, nice camp you've got here. I was planning a trip and needed someone to cover my back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_1_1">
		<text>Hm, do I know you? Whatever, sure, stalker. Let's go. Getting kinda bored just sitting around here anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_dlg_1_2">
		<text>Okay, let's move.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_name">
		<text>PDA of a Crystal member</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_descr">
		<text>Tens of files filled with strange and incoherent information, among which can be understood that the members of this squad were from the world's best military services. They had likely supervised the experiments carried out at the nuclear power plant before and after the first emission, later becoming zombified.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_1_name">
		<text>PDA of a Crystal member</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_1_descr">
		<text>This device is worn out beyond repair.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_2_name">
		<text>PDA of a Crystal member</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_2_descr">
		<text>“The great Monolith said He was in danger; the brothers were spread out and put on alert. No one is expressing any thoughts about the situation happening outside, so today, we will have to kill or die. For the sake of the Monolith, I will do it.”</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_3_name">
		<text>PDA of a Crystal member</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_3_descr">
		<text>Nothing remarkable is stored in the memory of the device, except for one single note, dated June 2012:\n“The last few days, the Monolith has stopped appearing in my dreams. Instead, I have begun to see episodes from the life of someone else, perhaps even mine. Is It testing my will? Is my faith in It not strong enough? Then I am ready to demonstrate to It how steadfast I am, because today, the day has come, the day when dozens, hundreds of fools try to get close to Its effulgence. Today, they shall learn the power of the guardians of the Monolith.”</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_4_name">
		<text>PDA of a Crystal member</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_4_descr">
		<text>This appears to have belonged a member of the brotherhood, who was already engaged in several activities other than patrolling. Within is a description of a “revelatory room” in which the brains were fixed by “infidels”. The description of “mysterious visions” most likely resembles an image broadcast through a monitor. In addition to the previously unknown zombifying waves of the Brain Scorcher, the owners of this place did not hesitate to use methods of direct indoctrination in their future soldiers, through their “TV”. A method old as the world, but more effective here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_5_name">
		<text>PDA of a Crystal member</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_crystal_pda_mlr_5_descr">
		<text>“We've loaded the bodies into the truck and gave out the devices with instructions as the storm was raging. At last, we've handed the vehicle over to the brotherhood; the Monolith will tell them where It wants them. I saw the face of a man with a scar... I believe I have encountered him before at some point.”</text>
	</string>



	<string id="simulation_task_19_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_19_text">
		<text>A Freedomer asked me to collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_19_about">
		<text>Man, can you gather some Duty scum patches for me? It'll help me rest easier at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_19_fetch_about">
		<text>Man, can you gather some Duty scum patches for me? It'll help me rest easier at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_19_fetch_finish">
		<text>Maximum respect, bro! Hold on to this artifact.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simulation_task_20_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_20_text">
		<text>A Duty member asked me to collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_20_about">
		<text>I've got some work, alright. Why don't you go beat up a couple of anarchists? Those freaks are breathing a little too freely these days. And, as evidence, would you bring me their patches?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_20_fetch_about">
		<text>I've got some work, alright. Why don't you go beat up a couple of anarchists? Those freaks are breathing a little too freely these days. And, as evidence, would you bring me their patches?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_20_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thanks, man. Here, take this artifact while no one's looking.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simulation_task_21_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_21_text">
		<text>A stalker asked me to collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_21_about">
		<text>Hi brother, won't you get some patches? I'll give you this artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_21_fetch_about">
		<text>Hello brother, will you rip away %s? They got me already. And I'll give you this artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_21_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you, brother, friend and helper. Here's your artifact.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simulation_task_22_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_22_text">
		<text>A bandit asked you to collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_22_about">
		<text>Hey, boy. I have some work for you. There's too many punks out there interfering with our business. Whack some of them and return their patches to me, will you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_22_fetch_about">
		<text>Hey, boy. I have some work for you. There's too many punks out there interfering with our business. Whack some of them and return their patches to me, will you? I need %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_22_fetch_finish">
		<text>Good job, man. My respect and artifact to you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simulation_task_23_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_23_text">
		<text>A stalker has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_23_about">
		<text>Man, I was thinking of going on an excursion with the guys, but there's something specific we need that we can't find. You wanna help us out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_23_fetch_about">
		<text>Man, I was thinking of going on an excursion with the guys, but we need %s and I can't find any. You wanna help us out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_23_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thanks for the help! Here, have a reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simulation_task_24_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_24_text">
		<text>A stalker has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_24_about">
		<text>Some of my equipment's broken down, and I'm heading on a raid tonight. Can you help me find something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_24_fetch_about">
		<text>Some of my equipment's broken down, and I'm heading on a raid tonight. Can you help me out and find me %s?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="simulation_task_24_fetch_finish">
		<text>Oh, thank you so much, man. Here, have some money.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_achievement_cheater_name">
		<text>Cheater</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_achievement_cheater_hint">
		<text>Worse than you already are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_achievement_cheater_descr">
		<text>Vasyan had already deliberately foreseen what you were going to do. Do not do this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_achievement_cheater_unlock">
		<text>Achievement unlocked: Cheater</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_agr_SRI_name">
		<text>Agroprom Research Institute</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ATP_name">
		<text>Vehicle station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar100rent_name">
		<text>100 Rads bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_base_freedom_name">
		<text>Army warehouses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_big_bus_station_name">
		<text>Bus station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_border_name">
		<text>Barrier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bs_village_name">
		<text>Bloodsucker village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dar_complex_name">
		<text>Industrial complex</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dar_farm_name">
		<text>Farm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dasc_fuel_station_name">
		<text>Gas station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dasc_treesucker_state_name">
		<text>Sawmill</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ds_administration_name">
		<text>Administration</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ds_HoC_name">
		<text>House of Culture</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ds_market_name">
		<text>Market</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_elevator_name">
		<text>Mill</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_factory_10_name">
		<text>Factory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gar_angar_name">
		<text>Train hangar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gar_baraholka_name">
		<text>Flea market</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gar_outpost_name">
		<text>Checkpoint by Rostok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gar_spot_electric_station_name">
		<text>Old substation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gar_train_tonnel_spot_mlr_name">
		<text>Railway tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hotel_poless_name">
		<text>Hotel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lim_bridge_name">
		<text>Bridge to Limansk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lim_bubbles_name">
		<text>Space anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lim_house_lesnik_name">
		<text>Forester's building</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lim_nonbuild_name">
		<text>Construction site</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lim_zastava_name">
		<text>Front outpost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mar_fishing_village_name">
		<text>Fishing village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mar_hide_base_spot_name">
		<text>Clear Sky base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mar_mechanic_yard_name">
		<text>Machine yard</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mar_old_church_name">
		<text>Old church</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mar_post_vishka_name">
		<text>Observation post</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mar_water_pump_station_name">
		<text>Water pump station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mon_base_name">
		<text>Palace of Culture</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_neut_base_name">
		<text>Farm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_north_blockpost_name">
		<text>Military outpost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_novice_village_name">
		<text>Rookie village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rad_bunker_name">
		<text>Bunker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_radar_first_zastava_name">
		<text>First outpost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_red_central_mine_name">
		<text>Mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_red_crap_name">
		<text>Devilish encampment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_red_dark_yar_name">
		<text>Dark bank</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_red_dead_area_spot_name">
		<text>Meadow of corpses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_red_witch_round_name">
		<text>Witch circle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_south_blokpost_name">
		<text>Southern checkpoint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tc_bandit_base_name">
		<text>Camp in the outskirts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tc_kpp_name">
		<text>Radar checkpoint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tc_vert_name">
		<text>Helicopter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tunnel_electr_name">
		<text>Tunnel with Electro anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_val_bandit_base_name">
		<text>Bandit base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_yanbunker_name">
		<text>Research facility</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_yancomplex_name">
		<text>Industrial complex</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_ammo_5.45x39_fmj_opt">
		<text>5.45, FMJ, eight packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_5.45x39_ap_opt">
		<text>5.45, armor-piercing, five packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_5.56x45_ss190_opt">
		<text>5.56, eight magazines.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_5.56x45_ap_opt">
		<text>5.56, armor-piercing, five magazines.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_7.62x25_p_opt">
		<text>7.62x25, P, six packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_7.62x25_ps_opt">
		<text>7.62x25, PST, five packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_7.62x39_fmj_opt">
		<text>7.62x39, FMJ, eight packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_7.62x39_ap_opt">
		<text>7.62x39, armor-piercing, five packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_7.62x54_7h1_opt">
		<text>7.62x45, ten packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_9x18_fmj_opt">
		<text>9x18, six packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_9x18_pmm_opt">
		<text>9x18, PBM, five packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_9x19_fmj_opt">
		<text>9x18, six packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_9x19_pbp_opt">
		<text>9x18, +P+, five packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_12x70_buck_opt">
		<text>12x70 buckshot rounds, fifteen packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_12x76_zhekan_opt">
		<text>12x76 slug rounds, fifteen packs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ammo_vog-25_opt">
		<text>VOG-25 grenades, twenty units.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_opt">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs, ten doses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage_opt">
		<text>Bandages, twenty pieces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread_opt">
		<text>Bread, twenty loafs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva_opt">
		<text>Canned food, twenty tins.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_opt">
		<text>Energy drink, fifteen cans.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_f1_opt">
		<text>F1 grenades, ten units.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_rgd5_opt">
		<text>RGD-five grenades, ten units.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa_opt">
		<text>Sausages, twenty pieces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army_opt">
		<text>Army medkit, twenty pieces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_opt">
		<text>First-aid kit, twenty pieces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_scientic_opt">
		<text>Scientific medkit, twenty pieces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka_opt">
		<text>Cossacks vodka, fifteen bottles.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_cant_sleep_find_shelter_mlr">
		<text>A safer location is required to sleep</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_device_torch_low_name">
		<text>Halogen flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_low_descr">
		<text>A conventional low-quality halogen flashlight with almost no ability to shed light on any terrain, purchased from the nearest supermarket from the perimeter of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_normal_name">
		<text>Standard flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_normal_descr">
		<text>A standard flashlight used for illuminating dark spaces, sporting a fair lighting distance and radius.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dev_torch_light_better_name">
		<text>Chinese flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dev_torch_light_better_descr">
		<text>A Chinese-made flashlight, featuring fair range and good radius. Appears to have been purchased in a local home appliance store.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dev_torch_light_better_1_name">
		<text>High-quality flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dev_torch_light_better_1_descr">
		<text>A device produced by a Ukrainian private military company, commonly used by soldiers of all ranks because of a lack of alternatives. The light features an average radius, although its range goes as far as 20 meters.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_disassemble_kit">
		<text>Tools for disassembling weapons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_disassemble_kit_descr">
		<text>A basic set used for dismantling any weapon. It includes a handful of tools that can help with some problematic elements of a weapon.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_dont_has_knife">
		<text>Knife required</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_dyn_news_y04_pole">
		<text>in the Meadow,</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_dyn_news_way_in_zone">
		<text>íà ×åðòå,</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_blizko_1">
		<text>in the village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_blizko_2">
		<text>at the canteen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_blizko_3">
		<text>in the parking lot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_blizko_4">
		<text>at the factory</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_daleko_1">
		<text>the village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_daleko_2">
		<text>the canteen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_daleko_3">
		<text>the parking lot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dyn_y04_pole_daleko_4">
		<text>the factory</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_energy_drink_nonstop">
		<text>Non Stop energy drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_nonstop_descr">
		<text>An outstanding energy drink containing caffeine, taurine, and a powerful vitamin complex that relieves fatigue and adds strength.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_gift_for_dutys">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]Gunko:\nHey, you. If you want to go to the Bar, you'll have to pay. Come to me, I'm standing by the trailer.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_itm_actor_backpack_desc_mlr">
		<text>Often used by stalkers as a fallback in case of unforeseen circumstances. Its features are simple, consisting of a strap which can be dropped along with the backpack at any moment, in order to run away quickly. Quite compact and capacious. Practically, it allows you to reset your backpack along with some content. \n%c[255,238,153,26]When used, it allows you to drop your backpack along with some of its contents.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_1_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Twilight Sparkle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_2_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Rainbow Dash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_3_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Princess Celestia</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_4_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Rarity</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_5_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Fluttershy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_6_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Pinkie Pie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_7_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Apple Jack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_8_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Handsome Jack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_9_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Suigintou</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_10_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Kanaria</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_11_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Suiseiseki</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_12_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Souseiseki</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_13_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Shinku</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_14_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Hinaichigo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_15_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Kirakishou</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_16_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Barasuishou</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_17_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Tohru Adachi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_18_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Kurisu Makise</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_19_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Fuu</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_20_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Asuka Langley Sohryu</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_21_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Maki Nishikino</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_22_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Sakuya Izayoi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_23_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Petro Poroshenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_24_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with Ariana</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_25_name">
		<text>Dakimakura with flag of Ukraine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_sleepbag_wife_desc">
		<text>Probably the print was made somewhere beyond the perimeter, and the fabric was subsequently moved to the territory of the Zone by local stalkers. It is an ordinary sleeping bag with a favorite character of a stalker, which will warm his body and soul on a cold night.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_jg_1">
		<text>About the job...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_2">
		<text>What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_3">
		<text>I heard your message. Need a guide?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_4">
		<text>Alright, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_5">
		<text>Lead the way, stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_6">
		<text>Sorry, but you don't have the money to pay me in case the plan doesn't go through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_mlr_1">
		<text>I don't even know who you are. No, thanks, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_7">
		<text>Remind me, where are we going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_8">
		<text>Here we are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_9">
		<text>Finally! Thanks, stalker, nice work. Here's your money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_10">
		<text>I've changed my mind. I'd prefer to cancel the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_11">
		<text>Really? Are you sure about that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_12">
		<text>Yes, I'm sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_13">
		<text>Actually, never mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_14">
		<text>Looking for an experienced stalker who can lead me to %s. Right now, I'm %s. Name's %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_15">
		<text>We're too late. I'm gonna be needing %s rubles back. %s out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_16">
		<text>Glad someone heard it. Here's the deal: within %s hours, I need to be %s. I can pay you %s rubles for the job, but keep in mind that you owe me %s rubles if we don't get there in time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_17">
		<text>I need to be</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_18">
		<text>Then I'll continue on my own, and I'll be taking that money. What a shame.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jg_19">
		<text>Length, including starting point and destination:&#032;</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_mlr_vodka">
		<text>Cossacks vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka_mlr_descr">
		<text>A bottle of vodka, apparently manufactured by GSC. It can serve as nervous treatment, but should not be taken in large doses. Moreover, it features a bad taste and appears to be counterfeit.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_new_path_mlr">
		<text>A route between two areas has become accessible.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_pda_mlr_descr">
		<text>A personal digital assistant containing possible information on routes between different areas. Its message history is inaccessible due to the presence of a password lock.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_plz_save_rookie">
		<text>Fatty:\nHey, stalker? Stalker! Please, help me, there's a bloodsucker trying to gobble me up in here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_plz_save_rookie_done">
		<text>Fatty:\nOh, thank you! Here, I'll open the door!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_pole_dead_stalkers_camp">
		<text>Fatty:\nGoddamn, what a horror... Who are they? Let's see if they've left any traces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pole_entrance_factory">
		<text>Fatty:\nThis place is giving me the chills... Let's go take a look inside the checkpoint booth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pole_here_zero_staff">
		<text>Fatty:\nLook, I don't think there's anything here, let's get out of here before those we end up like those poor fellows.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pole_main_build_factory">
		<text>Fatty:\nThere should be something in that section in front of us, like in the building in the middle of the complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pole_meet_controller">
		<text>Fatty:\nI have a weird fucking feeling, like someone is rummaging through my mind...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pole_out_here">
		<text>Fatty:\nLet's get out of here, quick!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_pri_special_trader_mlr_message">
		<text>Hatchet:\nStalker, you are in the territory of the Syndicate. You won't be attacked, but we expect proper behavior of you. If you're looking for work, I may have a few things for you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_stalker_baraholka_outfit">
		<text>Prospector suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stalker_baraholka_outfit_descr">
		<text>The prototype of this "product" was the Sunrise suit, widespread in the stalker environment. Its main advantages can be undoubtedly attributed to the reduced weight of both the body armor and the clothes in the set (rubber in many places just cut off) and an additional container for artifacts. Unfortunately for the conduct of military operations this sample of mediocre thought is not capable, but it will help in hunting for artifacts on the initial path of becoming a stalker.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_wpn_baraholka_groza">
		<text>OTs-14 Groza</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_baraholka_groza_descr">
		<text>It is a kind of almost ordinary shabby Groza, if not for one "but". These are not traces of natural operation, but experiments conducted by some local silly tech. As a result, the wear of the barrel increased more than two times! Simply put, unlike the original, this crap will literally fall apart on your hands while using it. But don't throw it out, right?</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_upgr_condlist_mlr">
		<text>Insufficent reputation among stalkers</text>
	</string>



	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_assault_rifle">
		<text>Gun parts (Assault rifles)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_assault_rifle_descr">
		<text>Spare parts left from disassembled weapons. \n%c[255,238,153,26]• Only for assault rifles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_machine_gun">
		<text>Gun spare parts (Machine Guns)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_machine_gun_descr">
		<text>Spare parts left from disassembled weapons \n%c[255,238,153,26]• Only for machine guns</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_pistol">
		<text>Gun parts (Handguns)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_pistol_descr">
		<text>Spare parts left from disassembled weapons. \n%c[255,238,153,26]• Only for pistols</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_shotgun">
		<text>Gun spare parts (Shotguns)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_shotgun_descr">
		<text>Spare parts left from disassembled weapons. \n%c[255,238,153,26]• Only for shotguns</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_sniper_rifle">
		<text>Gun parts (Sniper rifles)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_sniper_rifle_descr">
		<text>Spare parts left from disassembled weapons. \n%c[255,238,153,26]• Only for sniper rifles</text>
	</string>



	<string id="stalker_companion_task_mlr_1_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Oh, hey, dude! You gonna show us some of that local romance? Go ahead, we'll follow your lead. We're always ready to have some fun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_companion_task_mlr_1_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Need anything? Are we doing everything right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_companion_task_mlr_1_complete">
		<text>Look, thank you, man. We will never forget you, and if we'd ever reach the Wish Granter, then we will also make your life a sugar one. Goodbye, my friend!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_companion_task_mlr_1_actor_reply">
		<text>Mm-hmm.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="story_b_cs_0">
		<text>What can you tell me about Cold?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_1">
		<text>What can I say? He's earned quite a bit of respect as the current leader of our organization.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_2">
		<text>How did he earn that respect?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_3">
		<text>You see, there was some controversy regarding Lebedev, our former leader—who, by the way, I personally never met—and he didn't seem to take the opinions of the faction members into account during their reckless crusade towards the CNPP. That mercenary certainly helped us out, but in the end, it just wasn't worth it. Those who remained at the base were unable to fight back against a resurgence made by the renegades. The significance of our struggle in the swamps was reduced to zero... and the sacrifices here and on the way to the Chernobyl NPP turned out to be in vain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_4">
		<text>It seems like the faction's resentment towards their leader at that time was justified.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_5">
		<text>There's more to it. After our troops managed to return, we had to start a long conflict to take everything back. We wouldn't be able to manage in day-to-day life without Cold. He rallied up a number of unaffiliated stalkers and got in touch with folks throughout the Garbage and the Cordon. Free stalkers helped us out, and having a charismatic leader certainly didn't hurt. Moreover, he's given an order to all fighters, without exceptions, not to leave this place. We'll take any help, but we won't continue risking the lives of our guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_6">
		<text>Whoever Lebedev was and what he did, you don't seem to be the same faction as you used to be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_7">
		<text>That's your opinion, certainly has some value to it. Right now, we have no large-scale goals, nor any common ideology... Anyway, it's probably time we cut the storytelling and start the trading.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_b_cs_8">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="story_dog_0">
		<text>Whose pseudodog is that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_1">
		<text>That's Buddy, the Doctor's dog. Doctor asked Cold to keep him safe, as he's started getting a little old.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_2">
		<text>Well, by the looks of it, you wouldn't say that he needs it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_3">
		<text>Looks can be deceiving sometimes. Pet a kind-hearted creature. Now, can I tell you about these dogs and answer your questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_4">
		<text>Go ahead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_5">
		<text>Pseudodogs aren't really dogs at all, they actually originate from wolves. Duty found that out while researching them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_6">
		<text>That's... I need to write that down. What's the request, anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_7">
		<text>By virtue of my profession, I collect all sorts of stories. To the north, there's a place similar to our swamps, called Zaton. I hear there's an old crank living in the old barge, and apparently, he also has a pseudodog. Perhaps you can find out if it's true, if traveling that far won't be a problem for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dog_8">
		<text>Ok, I will check it out.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="story_dolg_m_0">
		<text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dolg_m_1">
		<text>I used to be stationed at the Agroprom Research Institute before I got a promotion. Before the Zone came into existence, I was a car mechanic. Duty noticed my skills as a handyman after I had been around for a while, so they decided to assign me as technician here. I prefer tinkering with heavy firearms and assault weapons... hate working on snipers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dolg_m_2">
		<text>What's with the bottles? Didn't think Duty allowed for drinking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dolg_m_3">
		<text>Duty lets me drink on duty... he-he. Man, it's hard getting by without a few bottles... The work is pretty damn tedious, and boring. I wish I could go back to the Agroprom, but our base there is gone now. I don't even know if I'd be alive if they had never relocated me. They say the base was lost during an emission in 2011... Huh, looks like we've gone way off topic. Anyway, don't be shy now. Show me your toys if you need 'em fixed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_dolg_m_4">
		<text>I'll see if I have anything.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="sultan_st_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_1">
		<text>Congratulations! With a memory like that, you'll be the next Strelok. Now listen carefully. I'm the big dog here, and you will know my name. I got here from Zaton some time ago along with my guys. We fucked the mutants out of the base and got it back up and running. Some sod set us up, pretended to be one of us and ratted me out. Had to get the fuck out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_2">
		<text>These rooks don't even know the rules, copping the made guys like that. Whatever that douchebag's name was, I'm going to rip him a new one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_3">
		<text>His name was Sashenka or something. And stay out of his ass. Your prick can't be any larger than my pinky, and his asshole's a metal maze.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_4">
		<text>Got it. Any tips on others in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_5">
		<text>Simple. Don't trust anybody but our guys with skulls on their sleeves. Pretty much everyone else is hostile, remember that. Just try to figure things out for yourself. If you feel something's off, get your ass out of there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_6">
		<text>Got it. Any safe places I can stay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_7">
		<text>No such place as safe in the Zone, boy, but don't let this advice go to waste. North of us is the truck cemetery, and our boys there control the old checkpoint and the entrance to the army warehouses. Try not to hang around the cemetery at night, and stay away from all the old vehicles. Radiation levels there are high enough to make your counter ring down to your balls, and that's not even mentioning the creatures and anomalies. There's the Garbage to the west; total chaos over there, and there's a checkpoint to the north controlled by Duty. South of us is a forest called the Darkscape. Really wild place, you've got soldiers patrolling there from time to time and loners pissing about. Pretty big maze. Also, there are a few stalkers at the farm on the way to the Darkscape, so don't fuck around. There's a huge advantage in that forest: the road leads to the Cordon. You'll easily find our guys at the vehicle station there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_8">
		<text>That's kind of scary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_9">
		<text>And what did you expect, boy? No sunshine and rainbows. This is the real life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sultan_st_10">
		<text>Alright, whatever. Thanks for the help, boss.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="take_barman_doc_from_factory_pole_0">
		<text>Hey, Barman. I visited the factory in the Meadow and found some documents. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="take_barman_doc_from_factory_pole_1">
		<text>Come on, let's see what the hell you got... well, this is something only armchair generals or collectors will appreciate, you can safely bin these pieces of paper. But for solving the mystery of the plant, well done, here's some money.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="talk_to_barman_mil_7_7_about_lottery_0">
		<text>Anything interesting going on in this bar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_barman_mil_7_7_about_lottery_1">
		<text>Other than Russian roulette, you mean? I happen to be running a lottery. You need to bring me as many rare patches as possible from stalkers around the Zone, and I'll give you a random prize. If you bring ten, there's only gonna be a fifty-fifty chance of getting anything, and even then, the reward ain't gonna be that big. But if you manage to find a whooping fifty patches: o-o-o, boy! Other than that, there's a bigger demand for patches from scientists and Monolithians, so you can get even more for that; it's a complete win-win. Oh, and Freedom patches won't count, 'cause I've already got plenty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_barman_mil_7_7_about_lottery_2">
		<text>What are you going to do with those patches?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_barman_mil_7_7_about_lottery_3">
		<text>Gonna sew myself a blanket out of them! You sure got a lot of questions, pal.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="talk_to_gar_outpost_dolg_main_soldier_0">
		<text>What kind of place is this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_gar_outpost_dolg_main_soldier_1">
		<text>Are you high or what? And as I know, well, dump after dump. It's actually a shitty place, filled with lots of radiation and all sorts of thugs. There's a large depot right to the right of the road, and it's better not to go there, as there's a bandit base. And I don't know anything else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_gar_outpost_dolg_main_soldier_2">
		<text>And what if Voronin finds out what you are doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_gar_outpost_dolg_main_soldier_3">
		<text>Don't mess with me, stalker, that could very well be life threatening for you. And where is the evidence to support your words? That's right, you don't have any. Get out of here, while we are still good.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="talk_to_inf_trader_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_inf_trader_1">
		<text>I'm a local informant, and I can offer you all kinds of services. At the moment, I've got different types of information, and maps with routes to various locations. Don't ask me where I got this stuff.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="talk_to_maps_0">
		<text>Any free info can you share about the surrounding area?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_maps_1">
		<text>Usually info is how I make a living, but since everything's quiet anyway, I can give you a bit of an insight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_maps_2">
		<text>I'm all ears.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_maps_3">
		<text>Well, you're in Rostok. It's completely safe for anyone on good terms with Duty. To the west lies the Wild Territory, former western part of the Rostok factory. Rumors advise against going there at night. The best kill zones are held by the mercs, so you'll likely be getting shot from two sides. There are mutants in the lower lands, and it's better to stay at a height provided by warehouses... Although, the mercs have them covered. That's all about the Wild Territory. To the north lie the army warehouses, held by Duty's “best friend”, Freedom. There's nothing particularly interesting going on there, but it's the last shelter around for sane people. To the east is the Truck Cemetery: stock up on anti-radiation supplies and ammo if you're going there. There are a lot of mutants and sometimes the radiation is way past what even we consider to be normal. To the south is the Garbage... complete anarchy going on over there. You've got mutants and thugs, but you've also got a neat marketplace. That's all for the roundabouts, need anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_maps_4">
		<text>You mentioned something about a shelter for sane people?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_maps_5">
		<text>Well, north of the warehouses is the Radar, an eerie place held by the Monolith. If you're heading there, best stock up on ammunition and supplies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_maps_6">
		<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="talk_to_saving_rookie_dlg_0">
		<text>Hey, man, thank you so much. The door's rather flimsy and the bloodsucker would've turned me into bones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_saving_rookie_dlg_1">
		<text>No problem. How did you end up in here, anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_saving_rookie_dlg_2">
		<text>I know this sounds cheesy, but I was looking for something to profit on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_saving_rookie_dlg_3">
		<text>Have you found anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_to_saving_rookie_dlg_4">
		<text>You bet! I've stashed some loot in the attic, you can head up there and take it as a token of gratitude. Listen, man, if you don't have anything important on your mind, please come to me. I've got an offer.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="tesak_meet_dialog_0">
		<text>So what are mercenaries doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tesak_meet_dialog_1">
		<text>We're stuck, man. We can't continue forward for obvious reasons, and we can't retreat, either. On top of that, all the paths are cut off, but that could be a positive: if we return to Dushman, he's gonna tear our balls off and shove them right down our throats anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tesak_meet_dialog_2">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tesak_meet_dialog_3">
		<text>We were carrying out some kind of assignment for our client, but screwed up bad. The military eliminated most of our guys and scoured the nearby laboratory for any information. I really don't feel like chattering about this... If you're looking for work, I've got some.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="tesak_travel_first_dlg_0">
		<text>You're a guide, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tesak_travel_first_dlg_1">
		<text>That is the case. I know a couple of paths from here thanks to a stalker... They say one of our squads wanted to get rid of him, but fortunately, he ain't mad at us for that. And, the sewer network here is quite well developed. My list goes as follows: CNPP, Pripyat, Yanov in Jupiter, the Radar, the Pripyat Underground, and Zaton, through Garry.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="to_lim_on_the_bridge_killer_ivent">
		<text>Gatekeeper:\nYou wanna get to Limansk? You'll have to pay. Fortunately, you won't have to pay much; only with the heads of a few chimeras hiding in that tunnel. Deal with them, and we might consider letting you through... he-he.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="to_lim_on_the_bridge_killer_ivent_2">
		<text>Gatekeeper:\nYou got 'em? Alright, we'll lower the bridge. Those flying abominations have been bothering us for who knows how long. You're welcome to trade supplies with us.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="totaliz_helper_mlr_text">
		<text>For a different perspective on the area, press the tilde key or \ to open the console, and enter: demo_record 1. The camera can be controlled using the W, A, S, and D keys, along with CTRL. To exit, press the ESC key.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_dasc_traveler_mlr_base_0">
		<text>I need your services.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_dasc_traveler_mlr_base_1">
		<text>Alright. Where we are going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_dasc_traveler_mlr_base_2">
		<text>To the rookie village in the Cordon. %c[255,238,153,26][1000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_dasc_traveler_mlr_base_3">
		<text>To the hidden base in the Great Swamp. %c[255,238,153,26][2500]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_dasc_traveler_mlr_base_4">
		<text>To the flea market in the Garbage. %c[255,238,153,26][2500]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_dasc_traveler_mlr_base_5">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_ds_killer_guide_main_base_0">
		<text>I want to leave the city.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_ds_killer_guide_main_base_1">
		<text>Which way are we going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_ds_killer_guide_main_base_2">
		<text>To the waste processing station in Zaton. %c[255,238,153,26][8000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_ds_killer_guide_main_base_3">
		<text>To the outpost by the bridge in the Red Forest. %c[255,238,153,26][2500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_ds_killer_guide_main_base_4">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_bar_0">
		<text>Need to be lead somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_1">
		<text>Yeah, where?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_2">
		<text>To the Cordon. %c[255,238,153,26][3000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_3">
		<text>To the Garbage. %c[255,238,153,26][700 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_4">
		<text>To the Army Warehouses. %c[255,238,153,26][1000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_5">
		<text>To Yantar. %c[255,238,153,26][3500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_6">
		<text>To Jupiter. %c[255,238,153,26][6000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_7">
		<text>To the Great Swamps. %c[255,238,153,26][6000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_bar_8">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_0">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_1">
		<text>Where we goin'?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_2">
		<text>To the Truck Cemetery. %c[255,238,153,26][1500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_3">
		<text>To the container warehouse in Jupiter. %c[255,238,153,26][8000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_4">
		<text>To the factory in the Cordon. %c[255,238,153,26][4000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_5">
		<text>To the train hangar in the Garbage. %c[255,238,153,26][1500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_dv_bandit_6">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_jup_0">
		<text>Take me somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jup_1">
		<text>Okay, where?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jup_2">
		<text>To the Bar. %c[255,238,153,26][6000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jup_3">
		<text>To Pripyat. %c[255,238,153,26][3000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jup_4">
		<text>To the outskirts. %c[255,238,153,26][4000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jup_5">
		<text>To the Red Forest. %c[255,238,153,26][2500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jup_6">
		<text>To Zaton. %c[255,238,153,26][2000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jup_7">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_jupdepo_mon_mon_0">
		<text>I'd like to travel somewhere, brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jupdepo_mon_mon_1">
		<text>Of course. Where would you like to go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jupdepo_mon_mon_2">
		<text>To the Red Forest. %c[255,238,153,26][6000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jupdepo_mon_mon_3">
		<text>To the outskirts. %c[255,238,153,26][2000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jupdepo_mon_mon_4">
		<text>To Pripyat. %c[255,238,153,26][1000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_jupdepo_mon_mon_5">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_0">
		<text>I'd like to travel somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_1">
		<text>To which location do you seek to go, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_2">
		<text>To the outskirts. %c[255,238,153,26][1000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_3">
		<text>To Jupiter. %c[255,238,153,26][1000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_l11pri_mon_haron_4">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_0">
		<text>I'd like to use your services.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_1">
		<text>Alright, where to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_2">
		<text>To the observation outpost. %c[255,238,153,26][300 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_3">
		<text>To the residence of the Swamp Doctor. %c[255,238,153,26][1000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_4">
		<text>To the pump station. %c[255,238,153,26][500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_5">
		<text>To the old church. %c[255,238,153,26][500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_6">
		<text>To the machine yard. %c[255,238,153,26][800 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_7">
		<text>To the rookie village in the Cordon. %c[255,238,153,26][1500 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_8">
		<text>To Agroprom. %c[255,238,153,26][2000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_9">
		<text>To the Bar. %c[255,238,153,26][4000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_marsh_csky_10">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_0">
		<text>Guide me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_1">
		<text>Where?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_2">
		<text>To the Chernobyl NPP. %c[255,238,153,26][12000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_3">
		<text>To Pripyat. %c[255,238,153,26][3000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_4">
		<text>To the Radar. %c[255,238,153,26][8000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_5">
		<text>To Jupiter. %c[255,238,153,26][4000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_6">
		<text>To Zaton. %c[255,238,153,26][4000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_pri_stalker_7">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_prikbo_mon_mon_0">
		<text>I'd like to travel somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_prikbo_mon_mon_1">
		<text>Certainly. Where would you like the guides to take you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_prikbo_mon_mon_2">
		<text>To Jupiter. %c[255,238,153,26][2000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_prikbo_mon_mon_3">
		<text>To Pripyat. %c[255,238,153,26][1000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_prikbo_mon_mon_4">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_red_forest_mon_0">
		<text>I'd like to travel somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_red_forest_mon_1">
		<text>Certainly. Where would you like the guides to take you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_red_forest_mon_2">
		<text>To the outskirts. %c[255,238,153,26][5000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_red_forest_mon_3">
		<text>To Jupiter. %c[255,238,153,26][6000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_red_forest_mon_4">
		<text>To Pripyat. %c[255,238,153,26][5000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_red_forest_mon_5">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_guid_zat_0">
		<text>Take me places.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_zat_1">
		<text>Where to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_zat_2">
		<text>To Pripyat. %c[255,238,153,26][4000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_zat_3">
		<text>To the outskirts. %c[255,238,153,26][5000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_zat_4">
		<text>To Jupiter. %c[255,238,153,26][2000 RU]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_guid_zat_5">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="travel_zaton_killer_guide_station_base_0">
		<text>I need your services.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_zaton_killer_guide_station_base_1">
		<text>Where to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_zaton_killer_guide_station_base_2">
		<text>To Dead City %c[255,238,153,26][Trade cooperative, 8000]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_zaton_killer_guide_station_base_3">
		<text>To Red Forest %c[255,238,153,26][Outpost after the bridge, 2500]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="travel_zaton_killer_guide_station_base_4">
		<text>Perhaps I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_start_0">
		<text>'Sup, homie? Armor and weapon repairs, all by me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_1_text">
		<text>The technician in the Truck Cemetery has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_1_about">
		<text>Bro, more than half of the stuff we got here is breaking apart, and I really need some tools to help out the guys. Wanna help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Bro, more than half of the stuff we got here is breaking apart, and I really need some tools to help out the guys. Wanna help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Oooh, yeah... That's what I'm talkin' about. Tell ya what: since you helped me out, Imma help you out with a discount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_2_text">
		<text>The technician in the Truck Cemetery has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_2_about">
		<text>This area is complete wilderness, but this place right here... It's a strategic point, man! To get our comrades as much firepower as possible, we're gonna need some better tools to work with. Help me out again, will ya?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>This area is a complete wilderness, but this place right here... It's a strategic point, man! To get our comrades as much firepower as possible, we're gonna need some better tools to work with. Help me out again, will ya?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Oh, fuck. You're the best, man. You'll definitely be getting another discount for that!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_3_text">
		<text>The technician in the Truck Cemetery has asked you to find %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_3_about">
		<text>Was just sittin' around, chillin' like villains, when I realized what we were missing. That's right, even better tools! Anyways, 'sup with you? Wanna help find some?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Was just sittin' around, chillin' like villains, when I realized what we were missing. That's right, even better tools! Anyways, 'sup with you? Wanna help find some?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trucks_cemetery_bandit_mechanic_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Wow, you actually fuckin' did it! Thanks, pal, you're the best. Biggest discount goes to you, enjoy it!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ui_mm_death_ini_alternative_option">
		<text>Increased loot on corpses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_fake_news_option">
		<text>PDA network</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_fast_travel_option">
		<text>Fast travel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_lootmoney_option">
		<text>Loot money on corpses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_mask_hud">
		<text>Dynamic mask HUD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_rank_loot_option">
		<text>Loot condition dependent on rank</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_robbery_at_sleep_option">
		<text>Robberies during sleep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_show_tip_reputation_option">
		<text>Reputation messages</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_transitions_closed_disable">
		<text>Open level passageways</text>
	</string>


	
	<string id="ui_mm_position_cam_show">
		<text>Îòîáðàæàòü ïîçèöèþ êàìåðû</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_fps_show">
		<text>Îòîáðàæàòü Ñ÷¸ò÷èê ÔÏÑ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_Memory_show">
		<text>Îòîáðàæàòü èñïîëüçóåìóþ ïàìÿòü</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ui_mm_god_show">
		<text>Ðåæèì Áîãà</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ui_mm_none">
		<text>Áåç àíèìàöèé</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ui_mm_simple">
		<text>×àñòè÷íûå</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ui_mm_full">
		<text>Âñå àíèìàöèè</text>
	</string>
	
	
	

	<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_0">
		<text>I'd like to purchase some extra equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_1">
		<text>What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>

		<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_2">
			<text>Medical supplies.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_3">
			<text>Provisions.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_4">
			<text>Ammunition.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_5">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_6">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_7">
			<text>Choose.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="ussr_level_of_buy_equpments_30">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_0">
		<text>Greetings, Sparrow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_1">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_2">
		<text>How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_3">
		<text>I'm good, if a bit worn. Never thought I'd voluntarily end up in the Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_4">
		<text>What's your story?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_5">
		<text>I've spent lots of time in the Zone, used to dwell around the Bar. Last time I was there, I made a mistake and got wasted when all this crap started around the Radar. All the ensuing chaos got interesting. Soldiers scurrying about, Monolithians completely exhausted. I came across a bunch of guys from the Monolith, except that, by some miracle, they weren't shooting at me. I helped them out a bit, decided to go to their base, but here I already got used to it, sort of.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_6">
		<text>Why did you decide to remain?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_7">
		<text>I just can't leave the Zone behind. I've had thoughts of going elsewhere, but as I remembered the Great Land... the unemployment, the lack of prospect and any self-will. Even in a place like this, I feel more accomplished. Anyway, we'll have more time to chat later, if I survive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk_8">
		<text>Good luck.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk_0">
		<text>You're Pegasus, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk_1">
		<text>Yeah. Hey, there. Did you wanna get acquainted?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk_2">
		<text>Yeah. How did you end up here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk_3">
		<text>I crossed the army blockade and ended up here, and I'd rather keep the details to myself. It's a bit personal. Besides that, the C-Consciousness is going to lead me to my dream. I've been one of the top marksmen in Wings, even though I don't particularly fancy sniper rifles myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk_4">
		<text>What is the C-Consciousness?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk_5">
		<text>You really haven't heard about them? Some might dismiss them as myth, but I know for sure that they're a group of expert scientists who somehow came into the noosphere. I managed to visit their laboratory in the north of the Zone, and let me tell you, they've got some fine technology. Holograms, advanced equipment... It's difficult to believe that it's the result of modern Ukrainian inventions combined with old Soviet technology. And, you know, I'd rather be around those who inspire confidence than some fucked-up Dutyers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk_0">
		<text>You must be Wind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk_1">
		<text>Yep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk_2">
		<text>Anything you want to share about yourself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk_3">
		<text>Nope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk_4">
		<text>Alright?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk_5">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="y04_pole">
		<text>Meadow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_space_restrictor_to_pol_1_descr">
		<text>To Meadow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_space_restrictor_to_pole_1_descr">
		<text>To Meadow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pol_space_restrictor_to_esc_1_descr">
		<text>To Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pol_space_restrictor_to_val_1_descr">
		<text>To Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pol_smart_terrain_1_1_anomaly_spot_name">
		<text>Meatgrinder anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pol_smart_terrain_1_2_anomaly_spot_name">
		<text>Volt anomaly</text>
	</string>



	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the %s artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_text">
		<text>Professor Sakharov has asked you to find a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_about">
		<text>Would you like to assist me with some research? I will pay you for your efforts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Would you like to assist me with some research? I offer a reward for a %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>On behalf of the scientific community, I thank you. Here is the reward, as promised.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_3_name">
		<text>Find two controller brain tissues</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_3_text">
		<text>Professor Sakharov has asked for your help in finding two controller brain tissues for his research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Hello again! For some time, I've been attempting to research psy-emissions, and I would like your assistance. No particular mental activity will be required from you, of course, but what about the brain of a controller... or, two, if you will?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent, please show them! Rather unpleasant, isn't it? That's just my job, however. Thank you for the help! Oh, and here's your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_4_name">
		<text>Clear the area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_4_text">
		<text>Scientists and military forces need my help in protecting the area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_4_about">
		<text>Could you help us with clearing out zombified stalkers? They've been an irritation for a long time. It was dreadful prior to the recruitment of additional security. Cries, moans, the sound of nails scratching metal... Bah, no matter. If you help us, I can share one of several artifacts that stalkers have brought here with you. Will you assist us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_4_finish">
		<text>Excellent. Now, all that remains for us is to conduct an educational program for the idiotic masses moving into the Zone and any other psy-emissive areas.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_5_name">
		<text>Find the Compass artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_5_text">
		<text>Sakharov needs an artifact known as the Compass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_5_fetch_about">
		<text>I, alongside the others working in this bunker, have all heard about a legendary type of artifact and its change of possession from one person to another. It's called the Compass, and it has never occurred to us to try and study it in person. Will you help assist us in finding one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_5_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you for your assistance. You may have one of our best suits. I'm sure that it will save your life, likely more than once.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_6_name">
		<text>Escort the scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_6_text">
		<text>It is necessary to escort a group of scientists to a certain place and ensure their safety while they conduct research, and then bring them back to the camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_6_about">
		<text>I need someone to cover our guys during routine measurements of abnormal activity. Looking back on your experience of staying in this place, I think that you are ideal for this approach. Do you agree with my statement?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_6_finish">
		<text>Thank you, stalker. Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_7_name">
		<text>Collect the bark from spoilt trees</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_7_text">
		<text>Sakharov asked me to help him with research on the local flora by going to the Red Forest for samples of bark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_7_about">
		<text>For a long time we have been arguing about the level of abnormal and radioactive interference in the structure of vegetation, in particular the so-called Red Forest trees, but all our attempts to understand this are being broken by the insurmountable obstacles that our scientific groups had to face. You can go there and take samples of the bark of the trees there for us? They say the most mutated are standing near the Symbiont anomaly, here they are and I need those.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_task_7_finish">
		<text>Thank you so much! Have this, it's what the scientific community is willing to offer.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_gauss_ammo_0">
		<text>I need batteries for a Gauss rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_gauss_ammo_1">
		<text>Got any Flash artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_gauss_ammo_2">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_gauss_ammo_3">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_gauss_ammo_4">
		<text>Here you go.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_name">
		<text>Find the Gauss rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_text">
		<text>Cardan wants to acquire a Gauss rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Yes, there is such a thing. I used to work here, before the first emission, we developed all kinds of weapons for military purposes, but after the blowout, we were evacuated and I I quit my job altogether. I couldn't even imagine that the work on improving our prototype might continue. Stalker, I need a gauss gun, I already held it in my hands when one of the stalkers brought it to me, but I want to try to improve it somehow. Bring it for me, and I'll start accumulating batteries for it. Well, will you help me out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_about">
		<text>Yes, there is such a thing. I used to work here, before the first emission, we developed all kinds of weapons for military purposes, but after the blowout, we were evacuated and I I quit my job altogether. I couldn't even imagine that the work on improving our prototype might continue. Stalker, I need a gauss gun, I already held it in my hands when one of the stalkers brought it to me, but I want to try to improve it somehow. Bring it for me, and I'll start accumulating batteries for it. Well, will you help me out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_finish">
		<text>Thanks, here, I got you a couple. Drop by anytime.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_b3_stalker_tech_start_mlr_0">
		<text>Hey, stalker. Need something?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="zat_b3_stalker_tech_start_new_after_62_0">
		<text>So?... You, err... feel free to bring me all your broken shooters, suits full of holes and whatnot... I ain't half as good when I'm sober, but I'll give it a shot...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_2_name">
		<text>Take out the stalkers in the farm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_2_text">
		<text>Sultan wants me to help fuck up the stalker at the farm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_2_about">
		<text>If you want, you can go to the farm with some tough boys and shake the stalkers there. How did they even fucking dare to appear there again. Wanna do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_2_finish">
		<text>Take your cut, Rambo.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_name">
		<text>Criminal protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_text">
		<text>The boss wanted me to shake the huckster in the Garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_about">
		<text>All right, let's do one thing. Even though those assholes at the flea market won't accept our protection, you have to show them that they're gonna need our services a lot. Well, you never know what can happen in life, right? Pay immediately and fucking take it. There they have a couple of devils on the lookout, I don't think there's gonna be any trouble for you. And listen here: I'm gonna send my guys to hunt you down if it turns out that you keep even a single piss-soaked penny for yourself, and they're goin to leave body will be found in the water ditch. Capiche?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_finish">
		<text>That's all for the common cash fund, and here's your hard earned score.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_trader_day_0">
		<text>Hand over your shit right now; artifacts, goods, everything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_trader_day_1">
		<text>Here. I'm sorry, I don't have any artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_trader_night_0">
		<text>Hand over your shit right now; artifacts, goods, everything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_task_3_trader_night_1">
		<text>Take what I have. Just don't shoot.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_1_name">
		<text>Find an Armsel Protecta</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_1_text">
		<text>Noah has asked you to bring him an Armsel Protecta.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_1_about">
		<text>My current shooter is crap. If you want to help, a better one would be of use to me... such as an Armsel Protecta. Every time I think about those creatures, lurking everywhere with their bony hands stretched, their bare teeth... well, you need something more capacious and quick-firing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>My current shooter is crap. If you want to help, a better one would be of use to me... such as an Armsel Protecta. Every time I think about those creatures, lurking everywhere with their bony hands stretched, their bare teeth... well, you need something more capacious and quick-firing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Give me that and get out.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_2_name">
		<text>Clear out the southern plateau of snorks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_2_text">
		<text>Noah asked you to save him from the annoying and apparently cunning snorks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_2_about">
		<text>We need put an end to those horrid creatures. Every night, I hear them creeping around the barge, waiting, breathing, and sniffing. To get to the southern plateau, you'll have to use a teleporter. I've marked it on your map - it's not far from the burnt farmstead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_2_finish">
		<text>Here. Now get out before you infect me with any snork bacteria.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_3_text">
		<text>Noah has asked you to find %s for his dogs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_3_about">
		<text>Now that the puppies are growing, I can't leave the Ark. I need your help in finding food for my dogs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Now that the puppies are growing, I can't leave the Ark. I need your help in finding food for my dogs. %s will do just fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b18_noah_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>What job? Oh, the fodder.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_heal_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_heal_1">
		<text>And I want to see just how deep your wallet goes. Four thousand.</text>
	</string>

		<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_heal_5">
			<text>Not today.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_heal_2">
		<text>Everything's fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_heal_3">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_heal_4">
		<text>There. Stay safe.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_1_text">
		<text>A mercenary technician has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_1_about">
		<text>Listen, what kind of mercenaries are we without well-maintained equipment? We used to have tools for everything, but some cunt stole them from the substation workshop. So I need tools, and not shitty ones, either. Can you find us some?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>Listen, what kind of mercenaries are we without well-maintained equipment? We used to have tools for everything, but some cunt stole them from the substation workshop. So I need tools, and not shitty ones, either. Can you find us some?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Damn, you deserve a discount. Thanks.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_2_text">
		<text>A mercenary technician has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_2_about">
		<text>Having reliable weapons is nice, but so far we're without any sufficient upgrades. Will you find me an even better set of tools?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>Having reliable weapons is nice, but so far we're without any sufficient upgrades. Will you find me an even better set of tools?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you. Let's see how much I can help you and the others out with this!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_3_text">
		<text>A mercenary technician has asked you to bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_3_about">
		<text>Listen, let's finish our job, shall we? I need calibration tools to make sure that no scumbag escapes us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Listen, let's finish our job, shall we? I need calibration tools to make sure that no scumbag escapes us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_mech_merc_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Oh, fuck... You are the hero of every technician! Well done, indeed... I'll be doubling your discount.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zat_stancia_trader_merc_task_1_name">
		<text>Collect %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_trader_merc_task_1_text">
		<text>A mercenary has asked you to collect %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_trader_merc_task_1_about">
		<text>You feel like arranging a real safari? You will hunt people and bring their patches. We will be raising the standards of the faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_trader_merc_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>You feel like arranging a real safari? Bring me %s and I'll pay you well. We will be raising the standards of the faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_stancia_trader_merc_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>That's what I'm talking about! Here's your money.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
