<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Alkash Programmer\n%c[default]I need access to the internet. Is there any in the Bar, or perhaps over at Sidorovich's place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Andriy Patriot\n%c[default]Во, млін, москалів понаїхало...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Deals on sausage and bread have been real shitty as of late.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]You guys heard that some transport in the Zone still works? Such a thing can be found in the Truck Cemetery, and it doesn't even need any gasoline! What a miracle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Ha-ha-ha, the military have got themselves a real shit show right now. They were on some kind of raid and their helicopter got shot at... got ordered to return to base immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Man, again Yantar is full of zombies. Careful there, people!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_7">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]«В окне автобуса проплыл ебаный военкомат... ну всё ты в армии, нахуй, о-о-о - теперь ты в армии, нахуй!»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_8">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Don't head into any basements, they're full of mutants! Go around the top!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_9">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Get to cover, now. There's a helicopter around the old church.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_10">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Saw a group of shady guys, presumably Freedom. They're heading toward the Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_11">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Saw a group of shady guys, presumably Duty. They're heading toward the army warehouses.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]We will look for you, we will find you, and we will kill you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_12">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]The military's pinned down in Agroprom, in the central complex!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_13">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Wish I had a house for four million! And how many artifacts am I going to have to collect for that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_14">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Boring... I feel like putting holes in somebody.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_15">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Join the Monolith in order to avoid your collective and inevitable fates!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_16">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Yesterday I met an old friend of mine that had been missing and he didn't even recognize me, instead immediately opening fire! Had to take him out... People, be careful around psy-emissions. Shooting former brothers of yours is not a simple task. at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_17">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]There was heavy fog in Yantar yesterday, made zombies impossible to spot from a distance.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Well, there's fog there almost every day, damn it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_18">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Garik, get me out of Jupiter. I'm on the road right now, will be over at Yanov in a second.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_19">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I hear Sakharov's got some new detectors!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_20">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]A group of five people are moving toward the Barrier; in all likelihood, Monolith. Take measures.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_21">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]«Группа крови на рукаве, мой мой порядковый номер на рукаве - пожелай мне удачи в бою, пожелай мне... не остаться в этой траве.»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_22">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Haha, loser. Why'd you leave your farm? And we've already cashed in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_23">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Two-Three-Seven, we're heading back. Regroup.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_24">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Tired... I'm tired of everything... Creatures... Damn stalkers, damn anomalies!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_25">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]If any other stalker tries to enter the Agroprom, I'm gonna get Duty to lock him up in the arena cages.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_26">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Zhurov, we're out of free hands. We need you and a few other guys to prepare a burial for a couple of bodies. They'll be sent to the South as Cargo 200 in a couple of days.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Zhurov\n%c[default]It'll be my pleasure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_27">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Fuck this weather. It goes from clear, to rain, to a fucking blowout in just a couple hours!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_28">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Together we shall protect the Monolith!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_29">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]The mutants have increased in number, leaving us with no fucking breathing room. What is Duty even up to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_30">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Know, infidels, that we are strong and you are weak. Run, and we will catch you. Hide, and we will find you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_31">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]What fucker snatched all the loot from my stash? The one in the Wild Territory. I know you're reading this... Prepare your sorry ass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_32">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]«И лампа не горит... и врут календари... и если ты пошёл на кровососа в рейд, то не реви.»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_33">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]What's the point, to be dragged somewhere. Uh, there'd better be a bar on the Cordon.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Butcher\n%c[default]Visit the flea market, damn it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_34">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]We'll track the crashed helicopter in the Swamps while no one's there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_35">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Who the hell trashed my vodka stash?\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Bruise\n%c[default]We drank it, sucker!\n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Wishing you'd have choked on it, scumbag!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_36">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]The command of the peacekeeping contingent for the isolation of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone is announcing recruitment into the ranks of the military stalkers: pork, horilka, endless ammunition, and a free burial are all guaranteed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_37">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Any smartass brave enough to enter our territory will be given hell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_38">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Anyone seen flying black smoke in the Wild Territory? Fuck me... Is it some kind of new poltergeist?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_39">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I'm pinned down by a bunch of looters, help me out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_40">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Miklukha, we've dealt with the mercs. Heading back as we speak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_41">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Miklukha, Duty's over at the farmstead again. Why?\n \n%c[255,40,40,255]Miklukha\n%c[default]You'll see. Soon, there will be decisive changes in the balance of forces... and not in Duty's favor.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Voronin\n%c[default]Calling fanatics into your ranks once again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_42">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Army warehouses. Apparently, there's not a chunk left of the pilots. Someone totally fucked that helicopter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_43">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I wiped this zone and why did I just come here? Money. Yes, we have fattened with our blood and sweat the cocksuckers in the government, that earn while doing fucking shit, and we are here, obliged to crawl for pathetic crumbs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_44">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Guys, there are some real strange things going on in the Zone. Ever heard stories about experiments and operations?\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Yeah. And it's unclear who's doing them or what exactly those experiments are. What's worse, only a small part of them have leaked out to the public...\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]You lads are gonna sleep better at night not knowing the details, trust me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_45">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Bros, any info on the next blowout?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_46">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]The Swamps are restless today. You can get stuck in the mud, and there are lots of creatures around. They are coming straight from the ground, goddammit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_47">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]We're seeing a wave of mutants coming from the northern gorge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_48">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]We're seeing a wave of mutants coming from the east, presumably from the Darkscape.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_49">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]We're seeing a wave of mutants coming from the northwest. See the attached coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_50">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I just spotted a couple of helicopters heading north. Sending coordinates. We'll remain hidden - I don't know what their instructions are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_51">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]A bunch of helicopters just passed by in the Swamps. What the hell are they up to here? I've heard nothing about any planned sweeps or operations in these areas, and my sources are reliable. Something sketchy's going on... Keep your eyes peeled, boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_52">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]People! Be careful in the village by the army warehouses - a burnt fuzz has grown on the pillars!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_53">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Anyone been to the Red Forest? I was planning on heading there, seems like there's some good loot to be found.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_54">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]People, I'm looking through my binoculars - seems like a new party of soldiers has arrived! I advise staying out of sight for a couple of days. They're combing the area, but the Zone's gonna chew 'em up anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_55">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]«Не те времена пошли, не те»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_56">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Some people do not learn anything and don't want to, have they seen too many American movies or are they blinded by greed? You tell them about the anomalies, they tell you about the loot - they don't want to think about anything, 'cept for mazuma, until their guts get scattered on the branches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_57">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Trust no one but the Monolith and your fellow brothers. No one..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_58">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]How many hounds are going to keep running around Rostok? When is Duty gonna deal with them already? Man, fuck this. I'm going to find someone who actually keeps their word.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_59">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Handing out an exoskeleton for free! And now that I've got your attention - I offer to sell a Wrenched artifact, price negotiable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_60">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]«Полковнику никто... не пишет. Полковника никто... не ждёт.»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_61">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Came to the Zone and thought I'd come across new sights to see and lots of mutants to hunt... and what do I get? Guard duty all day long at a stupid checkpoint with jack shit to do!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_62">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Seems like the military aren't sending any choppers to the area around Rostok after their last one got shot down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_63">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]We've accessed the southern tunnel of the facility, heading downwards into the underground. The Red Forest is visible from the windows here. It's quiet here.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]We're losing comms with you. Put the remote broadcaster on your output, or continue to transmit via text, as you are doing now.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Yeah, let's close the channel. We don't want this to leak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_64">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Got attacked by a pseudodog, barely made it out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_65">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Got attacked by a pseudodog, barely made it out.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Nice work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_66">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Anyone heard about some new guy over at the mercenary base in Pripyat? Seems like he's got some unique equipment you can order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_67">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]You heard about one of the sentries shooting himself? I'm having second feelings about joining the patrol.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_68">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I overheard some military discussions. Seems like they're planning an op on Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_69">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Death to non-believers!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_70">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I feel like sleeping</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_71">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Stalkers, Sakharov is paying decent money for loot!... And is looking for someone to send to lab X16. I'm not going there, too risky. Full of psy-emissions... and zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_72">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]A pack of dogs is coming at us sending coordinates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_73">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]You shitheads want a taste of a heat-seeking missile? Who taught you to fire an RPG?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_74">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Damn, who emptied my stash?\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Hahaha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_75">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Time for a commercial! You wanna be a real lad in the Zone? Get some dirt on your boot, earning plenty of loot? Live on the cushion? Join the bandits! We've got the one right perspective on the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_76">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Need to run away from the Zone, pronto</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_77">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Some dude in the Garbage got hold of a pretty rare gizmo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_78">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Sold some mutant parts to Sidorovich, and it seems like I got ripped off, that old fart... People, best you trade with Barman instead.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Even Strelok's memory loss wasn't nearly as bad as yours!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_79">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I'm leaving the Zone shortly, the adrenaline suddenly struck me, I realized everything</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_80">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Ha, how many dumbasses have rushed through the north in recent times.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_81">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Hemul, head over to the Bar. Got some work for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_82">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Rumor has it that there's a controller dwelling inside X16, and maybe not even one. A few experienced stalkers ventured there yesterday and haven't returned since.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_83">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]who are those bozos near the farm in merc gear? I ain't even thinking of goin near there!.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_84">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Damn rifle jamming on me again, and this is happening right after I took it to the technician from Duty in Rostok! What else could I have expected from an alcoholic? If your gear needs repairing, he's the type to stay away from.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_85">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Agh, there's a broken tank somewhere in the Red Forest, somewhere in a thicket. They say there's still a PKM left with a few rounds, but I can't look around for it by myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_86">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Did my pockets grow or something? Seems like it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_87">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]I heard the Kremlin sends their own people into the Zone. It'll be interested to watch them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_88">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Arnie\n%c[default]Fighting at midnight tonight. Don't miss it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_89">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ashot\n%c[default]Attention: I am now at Yanov station. Don't go looking for me in the warehouses, fellas. I offer you wonderful products at the lowest prices.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_90">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Barman\n%c[default]If anyone stumbles upon any documents containing information about the area around the Radar and the Scorcher, let me know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_91">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Barman\n%c[default]I'm going to explain this one more time for the boneheaded. There are no programmers in the back room of the bar that are responsible for any communications through your PDAs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_92">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Barman\n%c[default]Are you looking for a drink, a good firearm, a lot of money, and a conversation with reliable partners? Come to the 100 Rads bar!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_93">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Swamp Doctor\n%c[default]Egh, Strelok... how I need you right now. I don't even know who else to turn to with my problems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_94">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bolt\n%c[default]I ain't feeling good... Had some canned food, apparently from a warehouse. I looked at the expiration date, and I've screwed up bad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_95">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Beard\n%c[default]There's work for anyone willing to get their hands dirty. Come to the Skadovsk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_96">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Voronin\n%c[default]If I find out that you take bribes from stalkers passing through the Bar, I'm going to print and sign death warrants for each and every individual responsible before I put it in their coffins.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_97">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Hawaiian\n%c[default]Hola, ese! Got some work for anyone wandering around Jupiter - come visit Yanov station!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_98">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Hermann\n%c[default]A reminder to all stalkers that it is necessary to subscribe to the newsletter regarding any emissions in the Zone. The information is always accurate and up-to-date.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_99">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Groza\n%c[default]Prophet, I'm heading back to base. Got tons of artifacts!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_100">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Gromov\n%c[default]I need tools, come to me if you find anything suitable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_101">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Gromov\n%c[default]Guys, where did Zulu go? Nobody saw him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_102">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Deserter\n%c[default]Selling army goods! I have a lot of stuff, from unique weapons to ammo as well as armor. Anyone know where I am, come up. Whoever doesn't know will never learn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_103">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Digger\n%c[default]Need 5-6 stalkers for a raid on the catacombs. As soon as I find my PDA, we'll be on the move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_104">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Digger\n%c[default]Gathering people for a raid on the catacombs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_105">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Digger\n%c[default]We're in need of two more stalkers for a raid in the catacombs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_106">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Zhurov\n%c[default]Enough with the harassment at the perimeter already. We'll be covering the entirety of your village with mortar fire if this doesn't cease.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_107">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ivan Pisser\n%c[default]Heard some news: someone wants to get through to the Scorcher once again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_108">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Snitch\n%c[default]If you need information, go to the Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_109">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Snitch\n%c[default]Got a little job for an agile newbie, paying well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_110">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Kitsenko\n%c[default]Psss, where can I get a little smoke?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_111">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Kuznetsov\n%c[default]Combat battalion, knock back some good vodka, raid in 3 minutes! Get the squad ready and move out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_112">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Kuznetsov\n%c[default]This morning, five privates were missing from the drill... presumably deserters. I will be grateful for anyone who finds these degenerates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_113">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Kurgan\n%c[default]I can modify the firmware in the PDA, look for me in the bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_114">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Leon\n%c[default]That's enough, quit the spamming.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_115">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Loki\n%c[default]Hey, Duty, how are you doing without Yanov? Good thing your founder's little backstory got revealed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_116">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Baldy\n%c[default]The bandits showed up again in the Dark Valley, not good. We'll eradicate them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_117">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Makar\n%c[default]If only I could leave this mess, buy a flat in the city, and get some work in a studio.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_118">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Maslyak\n%c[default]I heard it again from the speakers at the checkpoint. Someone's laughing louder and louder, laughing more aggressively, like a maniac.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_119">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Maslyak\n%c[default]I can't do this anymore. Every day, the blood in my veins chills.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_120">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Miklukha\n%c[default]Free stalkers! Our men at the army warehouses welcome you at any time. Here, you will find true friends and comrades, good attitudes, and much more! The Zone is our home: reflect on whether you see yourself outside the Zone and help us deal with Duty once and for all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_121">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Butcher\n%c[default]I always have a job for a good hunter. Come to the flea market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_122">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Father Peter\n%c[default]Let us pray, brethren, for the peace of the soul of Yuri Semetsky! Amen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_123">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]Third squad, the raid to catch monsters for the arena has not been canceled! Come on, get out of the bar! Do you want to be like those anarchists weirdos?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_124">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]Everyone! The delivery of ammunition has to be conducted at the specified hours! Do I have to spend the night here?!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_125">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]There is work for the veterans, we pay big bucks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_126">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]There's work for free stalkers, adequate payments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_127">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]I'm offering a job to shoot mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_128">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]I purchase artifacts for science, come visit the Duty outpost at Rostok. If there's no money, I'll trade for something else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_129">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]Everyone on the parade grounds on the double. Whoever misses it will be discharged from Duty immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_130">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]We're having temporary difficulties with maintaining the private channel. If you need something, write to me personally.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_131">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Gunpowder\n%c[default]Sanya, are you seeing this too? What's this dumbfuck doing near the bushes? It's been three freaking days! Can I bust his ass already?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_132">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Gatekeeper\n%c[default]Once again for those "particularly gifted": do not go to the bridge in the DL, our snipers will calm you down instantly. Limansk is under the Syndicate's control.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_133">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Limpid\n%c[default]Guys, if you find any toolkit, bring it to me! I got basically nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_134">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Limpid\n%c[default]Anyone who's out hunting... you grab some PDAs for me, we can deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_135">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Rogovets\n%c[default]Here we go again, the vodka ran out again, that's it. How can I treat the nerves of the guys without it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_136">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Romka\n%c[default]I require a stalker, who's a specialist in code locks and with experience of raids in the North of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_137">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Peregrine\n%c[default]Die, scum.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_138">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sakharov\n%c[default]It is beneficial, on a good exchange course, to exchange parts of rare mutants. Those interested, come to Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_139">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sakharov\n%c[default]Comrade general, could you send me another five of your men? At the agreed price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_140">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sakharov\n%c[default]Dear friends stalkers! Our research requires a large number of artifacts at the moment, as many as you can bring. More than a decent payment guaranteed.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Deck yourselves out, eggheads. Brothers, who took care of you at first, who gave you the vodka, eh? Those stubborn scientists? Or uncle Sid? Bring those artifacts to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_141">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Senka\n%c[default]Oh, I'd love me a cold beer right now... Anyone know where to get some?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_142">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sergey\n%c[default]To whoever has tools for rough, fine, and calibration work: bring them to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_143">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sidorovich\n%c[default]There's always work, both for the rookies, and for the veterans, paying normal, heh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_144">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Rookies, come to me for work - you can gain experience, earn some money and purchase ammunition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_145">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Nowadays it's dangerous to live and be a trader, I need people to protect me and my savings!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_146">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Skinflint\n%c[default]If you want some brand-new, foreign weapon, come to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_147">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Skinflint\n%c[default]We've got some good pot. Come and get some, let's chillax for a bit!\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]Idiots...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_148">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Skinflint\n%c[default]If you feel like going on a raid, you can stock up at my place. Also got some dirty work, anyone who does it will be paid a rare artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_149">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Skinflint\n%c[default]I buy various PDAs containing any valuable information, bring everything to me, more money has never hurt anyone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_150">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Skinflint\n%c[default]I got hold of some toilet paper. Those who are tired of burdocks, come quickly, stocks are limited</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_151">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Sultan\n%c[default]Brothers, when you find Sleeper you can put him down for good... but grab the PDA and bring it to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_152">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Owl\n%c[default]Buying different PDAs with any valuable information. Bring everything to me, and I'll give as good as one gets</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_153">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Solid\n%c[default]xdfhsedjentdgxhxf\n%c[255,160,160,160]Miklukha\n%c[default]Drunk again, that prick...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_154">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Biggie\n%c[default]Anyone heard that? There's something playing in the Meadow near the factory. At midnight, so creepy, and yet, so horrifyingly familiar. But I can't remember where exactly I've heard it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_155">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fanatic\n%c[default]To anyone who has not yet been in the village - don't miss the unique opportunity of learning the necessary survival skills from me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_156">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fanatic\n%c[default]People, has anyone seen Wolf?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_157">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fanatic\n%c[default]Need help in sweeping mutant's lairs, contact me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_158">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Hakim\n%c[default]Sanya, I'm heading back to base with Snake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_159">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Hog\n%c[default]I need some more tools for my work. Any mercenaries who aren't out doing any contracts, please help me out. You won't regret the payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_160">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Hog\n%c[default]Best anyone stay away from the Wild Territory. You won't find anything good there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_161">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Hog\n%c[default]Soon, I'll be replenishing my rock collection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_162">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Trunk\n%c[default]We need stalkers with raiding experience deep into the Zone. Payment is appropriate. If anyone's interested, contact me and we'll discuss the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_163">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Chechnya\n%c[default]Hunting is cool, I gotta say.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_164">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Six\n%c[default]Miklukha, Duty's over at the farmstead again. Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_165">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Nimble\n%c[default]Stalkers! I accept all kinds of PDAs with any valuable information, carry everything to me, the money won't hurt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_166">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Yar\n%c[default]Hey, Ashot, how's Yanov? Must be cozy, you lousy spoon-fed fighter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_167">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Yarik Athlete\n%c[default]There's a sucker in the Dark Valley wandering around with a cool shooter. If someone offs him, I'll buy it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_spam_168">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]REMOVE ROCK remove rock you are worst cult. you are the cult idiot you are the cult smell. return to powerplant. to our powerplant cousins you may come our Zone. you may live in the garbage....ahahahaha ,monolith we will never forgeve you. cetnik rascal FUck but fuck asshole cult stink monolith sqhipere shqipare..monolith genocide best day of my life. take a bath of dead monolith..ahahahahahMONOLITH WE WILL GET YOU!! do not forget first emission .monolith we kill the C-consciousness , monolith return to your precious rock....hahahahaha idiot cult and monolith smell so bad..wow i can smell it. REMOVE CULT FROM THE PREMISES. you will get caught. loner+bandit+duty+freedom=kill monolith...you will blowout/ strelok alive in zone, strelok making quest of zone . fast hunt strelok zone. we are rich and have artifacts now hahahaha ha because of strelok... you are ppoor stink monolith... you live in a powerplant hahahaha, you live in a sarcophagus strelok alive numbr one #1 in zone ....fuck the monolith ,..FUCKk ashol cult no good i spit in the mouth eye of ur patch and faction. strelok aliv and real strong wizard kill all the monolith farm aminal with 9x39 magic now we the loner rule .ape of the pripyat presidant c-con fukc the great cherno and lay egg this egg hatch and monolith wa;s born. stupid baby form the eggn give bak our clay we will crush u lik a skull of flesh. loner greattst faction</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Ahah shit I've seen everything now. A Dutyer playing the skin flute on another</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Motherfucking degenerates, who ate my sausage? I'll find that rat and take it down</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Lads there's lots of stalkers carrying artifacts coming from the North.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Brothers at Jupiter, got word that you have a rat from the USS. I bet my ass it's the one with a good weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Evening chat, kissel and sweets! Haha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Fucking fat-assed son of a bitch, did you lose the armory keys again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_7">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Fuck, it was more fun around the trenches than here in the base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_8">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]I think we've got a rat in here. Every raid so far has a complete fuckup, stalkers just start shooting before we even know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_9">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]We just ran into a flying black smoke cloud, what the hell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_10">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Oh, fucking trash. Here I am, now come and get me here, gopnik.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_11">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]So, don't disturb the boss in the next couple of hours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_12">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]We jumped a couple of losers and went to the base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_13">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]one of my dudes been shot, can anyone come find us and take us to the base? Guys at the perimeter, can you help us??!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_14">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]feelin pretty shit. Who cares, Ima have myself a beer, HEHE.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_15">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Damn, I don't get it. Where's my shooter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_16">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Ehh... I haven't seen my mother in a long while since I joined this business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_bandit_17">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Bandits\n%c[default]Fucking state. You don't get shit from them, you turn the other direction and they ruin your life for nothing.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_1">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Attention, all squads: upon your arrival at the base, immediately report to the command post for instructions on the use of our new equipment models.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_2">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Attention to all squads in square E-15 or nearby! Immediately confirm the presence of highly dangerous mutants in this region! This information has been received from an unverified source.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_3">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Attention to all squads that are in the square of H-23 or nearby! Immediately confirm the presence of highly dangerous mutants in this region! This information has been received from an unverified source.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_4">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Calling all free squads! Bandit activity has once again risen in the Garbage. Clean up the sector.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_5">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Any stalkers assisting us in clearing out the path to the Bar will be rewarded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_6">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Sergeant Saykin speaking, fifth squad. I'm addressing the people who committed vandalism yesterday at Rostok, on Duty grounds. If one more bottle flies through the window in Petrenko's office, any perpetrators will be shot..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_7">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Duty needs experienced and brave fighters to replenish their ranks and destroy mutants. To all those who joined our ranks, the Bar will conduct a special pricing policy. Former gangsters - do not apply!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_8">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Duty is announcing an enlistment. Any volunteer should show up at the base of operations in Rostok with a weapon, gear, and enough food for three days. IDs are not required. Good physical conditioning is welcome.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_9">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]We will warn you once again, anarchists. If you do not cease to send abrasive insults to the PDA of general Voronin, we will be paying your base a visit. You don't think we aren't aware of who's been doing this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_10">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Enter the private channel and download the security update. If some lazy ass doesn't patch and info ends up leaking, he's a dead man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_11">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Patch through all raid and mutant-related intel to the private channel. We really wouldn't want a leak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_12">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]The warehouse has received some brand-new SVDs, who wants one better hurry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_13">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]We're seeing some kind of black flying smoke in the Wild Territory, waiting for instructions. Recon team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_14">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]We need experienced stalkers to raid mutants. Payment is appropriate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_15">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]We need experienced stalkers to raid mutant hideouts. Adequate payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_16">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]We need experienced stalkers for a raid on snorks. Payment is appropriate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_17">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Petrenko speaking. Zhivoderov, Arnie's asked you not to come to him if you capture anyone, he doesn't have free cells at the moment. Keep them at your place for a day, Arnie will pay you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_18">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Petrenko, show the fuck up! What's wrong with the private channel?! Down again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_19">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Petrenko, come in! Checking connection. My radio's broke, I'm texting in the general channel. Sent a trooper with repair tools to the place where we'd been nailing boars yesterday.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_20">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Petrenko, this is captain Sorokin from the Garbage speaking. Where's our ammunition?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_21">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Stalkers, join Duty! We shall cure our Earth from the deadly disease called the Zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_22">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Stalkers, join Duty. Protect the planet from the Zone's infection!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_23">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Stalkers, remember: anarchy represents chaos, destruction, and death. Join Duty! Maintain order and purity in the Zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_24">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Stalkers, join us in our collective duty to protect and rid the world of the mutant invasion and anomalous infection!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_25">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Okay, guys, I've received information that a group of mercs is ligering in the outskirts of Rostok. Eyes peeled.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_26">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]We are having problems with the equipment in the last couple of days. The connection to the database and with the squads is acting up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_27">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Captain Semonov speaking. Reporting about a strange type of mutant. An hour ago in B-15, my squad and I observed a bizarre bloodsucker. It attacked a controller and decimated it with several blows before our very eyes. The beast didn't spot us. Awaiting orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_28">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Petrenko speaking. Kolya, confirm the info about the 10th squad not returning from yesterday's raid. I think I've found what's left of them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_dolg_29">
		<text>%c[255,255,0,0]Duty\n%c[default]Don't gunk up the channel. Nobody cares about your lucky kills.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Attention, an unknown gas leak in square B-41 has just been detected. Take appropriate measures.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]If you feel heavy as the world begins to lose its colors and an icteric veil appears in your eyes, try to leave that area as soon as possible. You are most likely falling under the direct influence of the alternating field of psy-emissions!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Requesting helicopter to the central mobile lab, square y6_4.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]There is a burst of variable psy-emissions in sector y2_4. Be extremely careful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Militarized research groups remind military stalkers that a SEVA-class suit will not provide you with adequate protection against any anomalous effects. Use an SSP-class suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Militarized research groups remind all unregistered individuals in the territory of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone that you can approach one of our mobile bunkers and surrender. You will not be shot, you will provided with all necessary medical assistance, and you will be consigned to the USS at the earliest opportunity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_7">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Any recruits among the military forces at Yantar should contact me, Professor Sakharov, immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_8">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Professor Ozersky, please contact us immediately. This concerns your latest research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_9">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Northern mobile lab, how long are we supposed to wait for those important anomalous samples from you? Enough with this absurdity!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_10">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Dear soldiers and unreported individuals! Militarized research groups and the Scientific Research Institute of the Chernobyl Anomalous Zone would like to remind you that vodka does not contribute to the elimination of radionuclides. Use anti-radiation drugs instead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_ecolog_11">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Ecologists\n%c[default]Professor Hermann speaking. For the last two days, we have been waiting for the results of our psy-emission research from Professor Sakharov... however, he has been refusing to contact us. What is the meaning of this?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_1">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Attention! Just recently, our fighters were attacked by DUTY SOLDIERS, disguised as mercenaries. Be careful, guys. This is smelling like provocation street.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_2">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]All volunteers who have joined Freedom will be issued the latest Zone survival kit free of charge, along with the latest weaponry from the West! If that ain't enough, you get a head start of 2500 rubles!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_3">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]To all our guys: get into the private channel and update the security at once. Don't go whining about the fact that Duty found out about your next attack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_4">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Join Freedom! We'll stop anyone from seizing the Zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_5">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Long live Freedom! With the help of the Zone, we'll make the world a better place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_6">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Any data on the movement of mercenary squads should be left in the private channel at once. This is important.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_7">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]If you're out doing a job, keep any important info in the private channel. There are people out there reading our stuff, you know!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_8">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Download the new firmware so that you don't get as many crashes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_9">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Leshiy, where the hell have you headed off to? Boss is waiting for you in the office.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_10">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Loki, it's Miklukha. Contact me privately. Got an important matter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_11">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Max, it's Skinflint. The supplies are gonna be here in a week, hold on tight over there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_12">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Miklukha, for three days now, we've been getting nothing but dead air from you. What are we gonna do about the Monolith while they haven't crucified us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_13">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Mishka, sup, there was something I wanted to tell you yesterday... but I keep forgetting. Anyway, I saw a suspicious group of people to the west of our base, near the farmstead. Don't forget to tell Miklukha about this, or you're just gonna get stoned and let it slip your mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_14">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Looking for friendly company, sincere conversations, and a helping hand in future campaigns? Join us and become free!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_15">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]They've brought in a shipment of new G-36s to the warehouses. Better get 'em quick, there's practically a waiting list for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_16">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]We going out for lunch, or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_17">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]We're in need of experienced stalkers for an artifact hunt. We'll owe you one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_18">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Free stalkers, Freedom is speaking! If you want to live under respectable conditions in the Zone without any obligations from the military, like Duty, then come to us! We're always happy to see new faces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_19">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Free stalkers, Freedom speaking here! What do you have to gain by consciously limiting yourself to a life under the command under a bunch of bureaucratic pigs, living in their barracks and blindly following their orders? Become a part of us and join our expeditions to the most treasured places in the Zone, tasting the life of a free man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_20">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Greetings, stalker - it's me, your freedom! Come visit me at my address anytime: army warehouses, straight down the road and toward the right at the fork. ;)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_21">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Rostok today, the Verkhovna Rada tomorrow, and the whole world in two days!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_22">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Seems like they took out a massive group of zombies at Yantar today, in the workshops. There might still be a few left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_23">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Skinflint, where'd you put all the fancy shooters? Why am I not seeing them in the warehouses?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_24">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Stalker, don't you love the Zone? Have you forgotten that it gave you money and a purpose in life? Do you really want to work as an office clerk for a penny after all this is over? Join Freedom! Don't let them take away the last thing you value from you, and don't let them take away your life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_25">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Alright, don't spit in the goddamn glasses, I'll fucking break someone's nose the next time I hear something like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_26">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Hey-hey-hey, rasta! The most juicy and cool joints only with us! Join the real freedom and put in the order!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_27">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]I saw a black chimera last night, fucking scary beast. How can that even be explained?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_28">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[defaultWe duped a couple of bandits yesterday. I'm surprised they even remember to wear their pants each day, they're so goddamn dumb!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_29">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]There's a literal army of undead in Yantar going up in number everyday... What the hell we can do?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_30">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]I'm feeling creative today! Ah, yes, I'll express myself by hanging up Dutyers on branches!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_31">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]Dudes! Guess what, the ganja, the one growing near da springboard, it hits like a truck! Hahahaaa!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_freedom_32">
		<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Freedom\n%c[default]This is Skinflint. I've just received a small batch of American erotic magazines...\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Who the hell needs those, idiot? Everyone outside of the Zone has been using hard drives for years now, us included.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Base, this is Delta squad, we've got the entrance to the Dark Valley lab, what are the orders?\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Goddammit! Switch to the private channel!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Base, this is recon team Nightbird,we're having encryption problems and are dropping a message here. Landed in Limansk and the building site seems impenetrable, large concentrations of enemy forces, 8 RPGs, 5 snipers and 4 with unknown weapons, we cannot send our coordinates and the enemies are listening on the general channel, what are your orders?\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Copy, Nightbird. Return to the Red Forest immediately and regroup with Vulture. Make further decisions from there on out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Attention! When trying to cross the perimeter, the soldiers guarding it have the right to open fire on you without warning. Do not take chances and do not break the law.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]To all military stalkers operating in the area of Darkscape and Cordon, switch to the encrypted channel! That's an order!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]All military stalkers should establish comms on the double! Everybody assemble in the channel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Radio frequencies are muffled in square a4_4. Please report from other locations nearby the anomalous zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_7">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Citizens, the Zone is deadly dangerous! We do not protect the Zone from you, but you from the Zone! Do not endanger your lives, do not try to enter the secured area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_8">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Requesting a helicopter in the square a1_6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_9">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Requesting mortar strike on the coordinates e2_12.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Oi, easy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_10">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Contracted soldiers and military stalkers - if anyone in one of the raids finds the wreckage of a fallen helicopter, please recover the flight recorder and send it to Major Kuznetsov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_11">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Kuznetsov, there will be an examination by two observers of the USS tomorrow. Prepare a fitting reception.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_12">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Kuznetsov, get in touch immediately. Waiting for you in office #3.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_13">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Kestrel, it's Peony. Can you answer? There's no radio signal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_14">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Guys, don't screw around in the ravine. Some rabid creatures have settled where we burned a few boxes a couple of days ago..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_15">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Attention sappers, it is necessary to lay a few more mines in the square e3_16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_16">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]The Security Service of Ukraine calls for the cooperation of all good and conscientious citizens, report to us all cases of stalking known to you, only with your help will we be able to defeat this ugly phenomenon!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_army_17">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Armed Forces of Ukraine\n%c[default]Need to strengthen the Northern pass, according to the order #231. When will the armor be sent?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Soldiers, do not meddle in areas with variable psi-emissions, you'll get your goddamn brain fried.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]A squad was lost in the area of the cemetery of sunken ships, we have no connection with them. If anyone has seen those guys, hurry up to reason with them before they get into trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]I've seen some kind of squad in our uniform near Prypiat, behaving in a hostile manner and not allowing anyone get close. The oddity is that these are not ordinary deserters. They're headed downtown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Attention, Wings at the Generators. The installation has been destabilized. Head to the bunker as instructed and begin fixing the problem immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]We've spotted an enormous black chimera on the outskirts of the station. Fighters in sector ast_1 - be on the alert.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Barrier-1 is concerned at square aes2_m1. It seems that they've spotted some humanoids, hardly zombies, moving at a steady pace.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_7">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]A signal has come from the sarcophagus. Shall I verify?\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Not possible. Too much background radiation and tons of creatures are located there. I've already told you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_8">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Wings, come in. Are you already in place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_9">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]There is no Wish Granter, but there is a group of people ahead of their time with power that knows no equal. Don't ruin the dream... With your support, we will build a new world. A new reality.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_10">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]All recruits should meet with Mentor immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_11">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]A zombie horde is expected on the outskirts of Pripyat. Take action.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_12">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]We have lost a detachment in Agroprom. Find them, dead or alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_13">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]How many inquisitors are there, you say? Will a couple dozen not suffice? Well, crap. Mentor, best put your recruits to some training.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_14">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]How's the Radar? Is everything the same?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_15">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Our commander is worried again, there's nothing to eat at the station. Where do we find provisions? My fighters will soon be passing on to human flesh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_16">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Stalker, see what scientific activity has done to this world. It has challenged its foundations, and we need YOU to help make this world a better place. Based on the reality given to you, YOU must understand that with the help of the brotherhood, everything becomes possible. Paradise on earth? On the snap of your fingers. Assist us in keeping this miracle alive. Any future companions should arrive at any of our areas of deployment with arms and armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_17">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Where did Inquisitor's group go? We've got nothing to cover sector p_5 with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_18">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Fellow scientists, give up your ungrateful job. All the fruits of your work shall sooner or later settle in the oligarchic minorities, and you will be forgotten in oblivion. The brotherhood is in need of qualified specialists. Let us not offer you any rewards but the ability for you to choose your own futures for yourselves and your loved ones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_19">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]A sentry has died by his own hand in the control room. Remove the corpse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_20">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]This is the group at the station, we're running out of gear. We need help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_21">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Inquisitors speaking. We'll be clearing out the approaches to Pripyat. Be careful, we work using computer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_22">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]Commander of the Barrier speaking, we have five unfettered deserters. If you met them in the vicinity of Pripyat, shoot them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_23">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]This is Rabbit. Shortly, we will be securing some new equipment. The men have promised that they are bringing something from the military in the Agroprom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_monolith_24">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Monolith\n%c[default]This is the storeman from the Yubileiny service center. I'm quite worried. Are supplies expected in the near future? We don't even have enough 5.45.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Location unknown, burer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Location unknown, cause of death unknown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Location unknown, snork.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Location unknown, chemical poisoning.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Army warehouses, bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Great Swamp, septicaemia.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_7">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Great Swamp, sucked into a quagmire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_8">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Generators, anomalous canyon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_9">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Wild Territory, Whirligig anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_10">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Wild Territory, poltergeist.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_11">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, Iron Forest anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_12">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, Oakpine anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_13">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, Circus anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_14">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, Claw anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_15">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, burer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_16">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, controller.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_17">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_18">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, flesh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_19">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, chimera.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_20">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Zaton, chemical works.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_21">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Truck cemetery, bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_22">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Truck cemetery, crushed.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]When will this shit get fixed?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_23">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Truck cemetery, blind dog.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_24">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Truck cemetery, Springboard anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_25">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Cordon, Electro.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Have you heard? It's time for a hike. I believe: this is a good sign!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_26">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Dead City, gunshot wound.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_27">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Outskirts of Pripyat, anomalous vine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_28">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Outskirts of Pripyat, bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_29">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Outskirts of Pripyat, bullet wound.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_30">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Agroprom Underground, poltergeist.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Did you hear? Well, gulp down some fine vodka, it's time to earn money. Who's with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_31">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Pripyat, gravitational anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_32">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Pripyat, falling from heights.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_33">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Radar, cause of death unknown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_34">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Radar, pseudogiant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_35">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Red Forest, Luna Park anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_36">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Red Forest, whirligig.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_37">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Red Forest, meadow of corpses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_38">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Sarcophagus, springboard.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Did you hear? Well, gulp down some fine vodka, it's time to earn money. Who's with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_39">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Garbage, Venus flytrap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_40">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Dark Valley, pseudodog.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_41">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Central Pripyat, cause of death unknown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_42">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. CNPP, whirligig.\n \n%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]Have you heard? It's time for a hike. I believe: this is a good sign!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_43">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Jupiter, Concrete Bath anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_44">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Jupiter, Ash Heap anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_45">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Jupiter, burer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_46">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Jupiter, bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_47">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Jupiter, chimera.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_fake_news_death_48">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Fatal Error\n%c[default]Dead stalker, Yuri Semetsky. Yantar, cause of death unknown.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_1">
		<text>It's during moments like this in the morning that I remember my childhood. My village. You get up so early and watch the shadow and light play in your room... It's unreal. Magical.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_2">
		<text>Almost like evening...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_3">
		<text>Bricks were shat all night at the camp. Terrible night!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_4">
		<text>Fucking burers had a yell fest yesterday. Oh, wait... Those were izloms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_5">
		<text>Can anyone hear me? A group of our guys went missing tonight. Should have been back by the morning from the Agroprom. Still nothing. We'll go looking for them in an hour. Join us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_6">
		<text>Guys, you should see what a dawn is on Yantar. This surely is something... scary, and beautiful... Snork corpses drifting in the sparkling surface of the lake in the morning sun, so cool... Romantic...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_7">
		<text>Guys, wake up! It's morning already!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_8">
		<text>Guys, it's dawning... It's so beautiful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_9">
		<text>Rise and shine, folks. I'm pretty sure we can get moving already, there's not much we could run into. Not like at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_10">
		<text>Finally, the sky is no longer black. I can get out of the underground with the damn wildlife gone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_11">
		<text>It's morning. Moving forward; it's more or less safe now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_12">
		<text>A beautiful dawn! As if in Sevastopol and not here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_13">
		<text>Day is breaking...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_14">
		<text>«Скоро рассвет, выхода нет, ключ повери и по-ле-те-ли!»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_15">
		<text>Time to be standing up again, geez.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_16">
		<text>A terror, not a morning.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_17">
		<text>Is it morning already? I'm just hanging around in the underground.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_18">
		<text>Damn, who invented morning... We've been drinking all night... Skinflint, fucking bastard, brought some terrible vodka again from somewhere... Freedom, we carry on sleeping... The raid on Duty's base will have to wait...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_19">
		<text>Even in this place, beauty exists!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_20">
		<text>Hey, guys! Finally, dawn has come. I'm tired of shaking in fear in the dark. Better to shiver in the light of day...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_morn_21">
		<text>Egh... I used to have completely different things to do in the morning.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_1">
		<text>Damn, it's darker than up the ass of a nigger. The devil's dragged me into the depths of the Zone, and now I don't even know how far I am from camp! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_2">
		<text>Well, horseshit. I'm on guard duty this night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_3">
		<text>Attention, everyone! Scientists report suspicious mutant activity in Yantar this night. Everyone stay in your camps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_4">
		<text>Screw you and your hunting! At night. Hunting snorks... Fucking psychopaths.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_5">
		<text>Sunset... Ah, even in the Zone, sunsets are beautiful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_6">
		<text>Yeah, go ahead, hunting down bloodsuckers in the middle of the night like a bunch of dumbasses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_7">
		<text>The moon is gonna be up before long. Damn, I don't have any time to get to the camp. Is anyone around? I think I feel something following me already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_8">
		<text>Is there anyone nearby? It's so damn dark... scary... I can barely see the road...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_9">
		<text>To the people who are staying in the Agroprom complex: don't get too close to those hatches. People say snorks crawl from there at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_10">
		<text>No, I'm not going anywhere. It's too late...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_11">
		<text>Well, pussies, time to start shaking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_12">
		<text>Damn, the zombies won't retreat. Dushman, what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_13">
		<text>Well? Who wants to go shooting some pseudodogs with me? I'm scared of sleeping in a tent at night, I keep hearing sudden sloshing in the dark. It's better to wander somewhere...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_14">
		<text>Tonight, mutant activity in Yantar is up to eleven, and, well... so is everywhere else, so everybody, stay in your camps!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_15">
		<text>I heard that burers come to the surface at night... It's better to catch some sleep in the camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_16">
		<text>So, sunset has arrived... Best you come back without making any noise. These roads are no longer safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_17">
		<text>Okay, return to your camps slowly. The Zone is absolutely not safe at night!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_18">
		<text>Shit. Guys, do what you want, but I'm not going to look for loot today. Night is coming...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_news_main_time_night_19">
		<text>Damn, the sun's already going down... Don't have time to get to camp. I can already feel something unsettling in the vicinity.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
